[
    {
        "question": "8/8 stratus base 200 ft/AGL is observed at sunrise at an aerodrome in the north of France ; the QNH is 1028 hPa and there is\na variable wind of 3 kt. What change in these clouds is likely at 1200 UTC in summer and winter ?\n",
        "answer": "Winter : OVC , base 500 ft/AGL , summer : SCT , base 3000 ft/AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "Winter : SCT , base 3000 ft/AGL , summer : OVC , base 500 ft/AGL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Winter : BKN , base 2500 ft/AGL , summer : BKN , base 3500 ft/AGL.\n",
        "choicethree": "Winter : clear sky , summer : BKN CB , base 1500 ft/AGL.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A blocking anticyclone in the northern hemisphere is ;\n",
        "answer": "a warm anticyclone/quasi stationary/situated between 50\u00b0N and 70\u00b0N\n",
        "choiceone": "a cold anticyclone/steering depressions/situated over Scandinavia\n",
        "choicetwo": "quasi stationary/situated between 50\u00b0N and 70\u00b0N/a cold anticyclone\n",
        "choicethree": "situated between 50\u00b0N and 70\u00b0N/a cold anticyclone/steering depressions\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A Cb with thunderstorm has reached the mature stage. Which statement is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "In temperatures lower than \u201323\u00baC icing is still possible.\n",
        "choiceone": "The freezing level in the whole cloud lies lower than outside the cloud.\n",
        "choicetwo": "If hail occurs , it only occurs in downdrafts.\n",
        "choicethree": "Severe turbulence occurs in the cloud , but hardly ever below the cloud.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A cold air pool ;\n",
        "answer": "is usually most evident in the circulation and temperature fields of the middle troposphere and may show\n little or no sign on a surface chart.\n",
        "choiceone": "develops usually in winter when very unstable maritime polar or maritime arctic air currents stream\n southwards along the eastern side of an extensive ridge of high pressure , in association with occluded\n systems.\n",
        "choicetwo": "occurs frequently in winter to the south of the Alps when this region is under the influence of cold north-\n westerly airstream.\n",
        "choicethree": "normally disappears at night and occurs almost exclusively in summer.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A cold air pool can be best identified by means of ;\n",
        "answer": "the isohypses on an upper air chart.\n",
        "choiceone": "the CAT areas on a significant weather chart.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the isobars on a surface chart.\n",
        "choicethree": "a GAMET report.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A conditionally unstable air mass is forced to ascend a mountain slope. What type of clouds can be expected ?\n",
        "answer": "Clouds with considerable vertical development and associated turbulence.\n",
        "choiceone": "Stratiform clouds with considerable turbulence.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Layer-like clouds with little vertical development.\n",
        "choicethree": "Stratiform clouds with a temperature inversion.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4331A rev. 20.01.2003 )\n Annex 050-4331A\n A convergence line is indicated by ;\n",
        "answer": "number 1.\n",
        "choiceone": "number 3.\n",
        "choicetwo": "number 4.\n",
        "choicethree": "number 2.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A cumulonimbus cloud at mid-latitudes in summer contains ;\n",
        "answer": "ice crystals , water droplets and supercooled water droplets.\n",
        "choiceone": "only ice crystals.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ice crystals and water droplets but never supercooled water droplets.\n",
        "choicethree": "only water droplets.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A cumulus congestus is ;\n",
        "answer": "a cumulus that is of great vertical extent.\n",
        "choiceone": "a cumulus with little vertical development.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a cumulus that only occurs in association with the ITCZ.\n",
        "choicethree": "a remnant of a CB.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A dry , sand- and dust-laden North Easterly wind that blows in winter over large parts of North West Africa is known as a ;\n",
        "answer": "Harmattan.\n",
        "choiceone": "Scirocco.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Pampero.\n",
        "choicethree": "Khamsin.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A flight is to depart from an airport with runways 09 and 27. Surface wind is 270/05 , an inversion is reported at 300 feet\nwith turbulence and wind shear. The wind just above the inversion is 090/30. What is the safest departure procedure ?\n",
        "answer": "Depart on runway 09 with a tailwind.\n",
        "choiceone": "Take-off is not possible under these conditions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Depart runway 27 with as steep an ascent as possible.\n",
        "choicethree": "Depart runway 27 with maximum throttle during the passage through the inversion.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A flight with a jet aeroplane from Munich to London is planned with a departure time of 22:50 local time. Which type of\nsatellite imagery available with observation time close to ETD is best to locate the clouds and the exact position of a cold front\nforecast for this night over Western Europe ?\n",
        "answer": "Infrared ( IR ) , polar orbiting.\n",
        "choiceone": "Visual ( VIS ) , polar orbiting.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Visual ( VIS ) , geo-stationary.\n",
        "choicethree": "Water vapour ( WV ) , geo-stationary or polar orbiting.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A Foehn wind occurs on the ;\n",
        "answer": "leeward side of a mountain range and is caused by significant moisture loss by precipitation from cloud.\n",
        "choiceone": "windward side of a mountain range and is caused by surface heating.\n",
        "choicetwo": "leeward side of a mountain range and is caused by the condensation level being lower on the leeward side\n than on the windward side.\n",
        "choicethree": "windward side of a mountain range and is caused by surface cooling and reverse air flow.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A frontal depression passes through the airport. What form of precipitation do you expect ?\n",
        "answer": "Continuous rain or snow during 6 hours until the warm front arrives. The precipitation stops for several hours\n within the warm sector. On the arrival of the cold front , showers within a couple of hours.\n",
        "choiceone": "Showers during some 2 hours until the warm front arrives. Drizzle in the warm sector within 12 hours. Rain\n or snow on the passage of the cold front.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Continuous rain or snow while the frontal wave passes for a period of some 24 hours.\n",
        "choicethree": "Rain or snow during about 12 hours until the warm front arrives. Within the warm sector the rain increases.\n Improvement on the passage of the cold front.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A given mass of air is saturated with water vapour ( no condensed water ). If temperature increases ;\n",
        "answer": "the amount of water vapour remains constant.\n",
        "choiceone": "relative humidity increases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the amount of water vapour decreases.\n",
        "choicethree": "relative humidity remains constant.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A gust front is ;\n",
        "answer": "formed by the cold air outflow from a thunderstorm.\n",
        "choiceone": "characterized by heavy lightning.\n",
        "choicetwo": "another name for a cold front.\n",
        "choicethree": "normally encountered directly below a thunderstorm.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A high pressure area ( slack pressure gradient ) covers part of the Mediterranean Sea and coastal region during the summer.\nWhat surface wind direction is likely at an airport at the coast on a sunny afternoon ?\n",
        "answer": "Sea to land.\n",
        "choiceone": "Land to sea.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Variable.\n",
        "choicethree": "Parallel to the coastline.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A katabatic wind blows ;\n",
        "answer": "down the slope during the night.\n",
        "choiceone": "up the slope during the day.\n",
        "choicetwo": "down the slope during the day.\n",
        "choicethree": "up the slope during the night.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A layer can be ;\n",
        "answer": "stable for unsaturated air and unstable for saturated air.\n",
        "choiceone": "stable for saturated air and unstable for unsaturated air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "unstable for unsaturated air and neutral for saturated air.\n",
        "choicethree": "unstable for unsaturated air and conditionally unstable.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A layer in which the temperature decreases with 1\u00b0C per 100 m increasing altitude is ;\n",
        "answer": "neutral for dry air.\n",
        "choiceone": "absolutely unstable.\n",
        "choicetwo": "conditionally unstable.\n",
        "choicethree": "absolutely stable.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A layer in which the temperature increases with height is ;\n",
        "answer": "absolutely stable.\n",
        "choiceone": "neutral.\n",
        "choicetwo": "absolutely unstable.\n",
        "choicethree": "conditionally unstable.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A layer in which the temperature remains constant with height is ;\n",
        "answer": "absolutely stable.\n",
        "choiceone": "neutral.\n",
        "choicetwo": "unstable.\n",
        "choicethree": "conditionally unstable.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A layer is absolutely unstable if the temperature decrease with height is ;\n",
        "answer": "more than 1\u00b0C per 100 m.\n",
        "choiceone": "0.65\u00b0C per 100 m.\n",
        "choicetwo": "between 1\u00b0C per 100 m and 0.65\u00b0C per 100 m.\n",
        "choicethree": "less than 0.65\u00b0C per 100 m.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A layer is conditionally unstable if the air ;\n",
        "answer": "is unstable for saturated air and stable for dry air.\n",
        "choiceone": "becomes stable by lifting it.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is unstable for saturated air as well as for dry air.\n",
        "choicethree": "is stable for saturated air and unstable for dry air.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A layer of stratus is most likely to be dispersed by ;\n",
        "answer": "insolation resulting in the lifting of the condensation level.\n",
        "choiceone": "adiabatic cooling due to subsidence.\n",
        "choicetwo": "absorption of solar radiation in the stratus layer.\n",
        "choicethree": "the release of latent heat due to precipitation.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A METAR message is valid ;\n",
        "answer": "at the time of observation.\n",
        "choiceone": "for the hour following the observation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "for 9 hours.\n",
        "choicethree": "for 2 hours.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A microburst phenomenon can arise in the ;\n",
        "answer": "downdraught of a cumulonimbus at the mature stage.\n",
        "choiceone": "updraught of a cumulonimbus at the mature stage.\n",
        "choicetwo": "downdraught of a cumulonimbus at the formation stage.\n",
        "choicethree": "updraught of a cumulonimbus at the growth stage.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A microburst with its damaging winds at the surface ;\n",
        "answer": "has a diameter up to 4 km.\n",
        "choiceone": "is always associated with thunderstorms.\n",
        "choicetwo": "has a life time of more than 30 minutes.\n",
        "choicethree": "occurs only in tropical areas.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A moist but unsaturated parcel of air becomes saturated by ;\n",
        "answer": "lifting the parcel to a higher level.\n",
        "choiceone": "lowering the parcel to a lower level.\n",
        "choicetwo": "moving the parcel to an area with lower pressure and equal temperature.\n",
        "choicethree": "moving the parcel to an area with higher pressure and equal temperature.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A moist , stable layer of air is forced to rise against a mountain range and the stability does not change. Which of the\nfollowing phenomena may develop ?\n",
        "answer": "Stratified clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "Inversions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Showers and thunderstorms.\n",
        "choicethree": "Areas of severe turbulence.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A mountain breeze ( katabatic wind ) blows ;\n",
        "answer": "down the slope during the night.\n",
        "choiceone": "up the slope during the day.\n",
        "choicetwo": "up the slope during the night.\n",
        "choicethree": "down the slope during the day.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A night in January has been cold and clear. In the forenoon of the next day an airfield is in IMC due to fog which extends to\na height of 700 ft. A heavily laden aircraft departs and , when breaking through the top of the fog , experiences temporary bumpiness\nand a sudden decrease in climb rate. Mark the answer that states the most probable reason for the altered aircraft performance.\n",
        "answer": "The aircraft suffers reduced lift and thrust due to a temperature inversion at the top of the fog.\n",
        "choiceone": "The water which has been gathered during flight through the fog modifies the aerodynamic properties of the\n aircraft , thus reducing lift.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The aircraft is under influence of a mountain breeze ( descending air from the surrounding hills due to the\n incident sunshine ).\n",
        "choicethree": "The additional weight gained by water which has been gathered on wings and fuselage during flight through\n the fog reduces the lift.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A non-occluded frontal wave passes the airport. What form of precipitation do you expect ?\n",
        "answer": "Continuous rain or snow during several hours until the warm front arrives. The precipitation stops for several\n hours or becomes intermittent light within the warm sector. On the arrival of the cold front , showers will\n occur.\n",
        "choiceone": "Showers during some 2 hours until the warm front arrives. Drizzle in the warm sector within 12 hours. Rain\n or snow on the passage of the cold front.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Continuous rain or snow while the frontal wave passes for a period of some 24 hours.\n",
        "choicethree": "Rain or snow for about 12 hours until the warm front arrives. Within the warm sector rainfall increases. On\n the arrival of the cold front precipitation ceases.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A parcel of moist but not saturated air rises due to adiabatic effects. Which of the following changes ?\n",
        "answer": "Relative humidity\n",
        "choiceone": "Absolute humidity\n",
        "choicetwo": "Mixing ratio\n",
        "choicethree": "Specific humidity\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A parcel of rising air stays unsaturated. Which of the following statements is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "Relative humidity increases , temperature decreases.\n",
        "choiceone": "Relative humidity and mixing ratio remain unchanged.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Mixing ratio increases , temperature decreases.\n",
        "choicethree": "Relative humidity decreases , mixing ratio remains unchanged.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A parcel of unsaturated air is forced to rise through an isothermal layer. So long as it remains unsaturated , the temperature of\nthe parcel ;\n",
        "answer": "decreases 1\u00b0C per 100 m.\n",
        "choiceone": "decreases 0.65\u00b0C per 100 m.\n",
        "choicetwo": "remains constant.\n",
        "choicethree": "becomes equal to the temperature of the isothermal layer.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A parcel of unsaturated air is lifted to just below the condensation level and then returned to its original level. What is the\nfinal temperature of the parcel of air ?\n",
        "answer": "The same as the starting temperature.\n",
        "choiceone": "It depends upon the QFE.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Lower than the starting temperature.\n",
        "choicethree": "Higher than the starting temperature.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A pilot is warned of severe icing at certain flight levels by information supplied in ;\n",
        "answer": "SWC and SIGMET.\n",
        "choiceone": "METAR and SIGMET.\n",
        "choicetwo": "TAF and METAR.\n",
        "choicethree": "TAF and SIGMET.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A plain in Western Europe with an average elevation of 500 m ( 1600 ft ) above sea level is covered with a uniform AC layer\nof cloud during the summer months. At what height above the ground is the base of this cloud to be expected ?\n",
        "answer": "7000 - 15000 ft above the terrain.\n",
        "choiceone": "15000 - 25000 ft above the terrain.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1500 - 7000 ft above the terrain.\n",
        "choicethree": "100 - 1500 ft above the terrain.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A plain in Western Europe with an average height of 500 m ( 1600 ft ) above sea level is covered with a uniform CC layer of\ncloud during the summer months. At what height above the ground is the base of this cloud to be expected ?\n",
        "answer": "15000 - 35000 ft above the terrain.\n",
        "choiceone": "1500 - 7000 ft above the terrain.\n",
        "choicetwo": "100 - 1500 ft above the terrain.\n",
        "choicethree": "7000 - 15000 ft above the terrain.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A plain in Western Europe with an average height of 500 m ( 1600 ft ) above sea level is covered with a uniform SC layer of\ncloud during the summer months. At what height above the ground is the base of this cloud to be expected ?\n",
        "answer": "1500 - 7000 ft above ground.\n",
        "choiceone": "15000 - 25000 ft above ground.\n",
        "choicetwo": "7000 - 15000 ft above ground.\n",
        "choicethree": "100 - 1500 ft above ground.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A sample of moist but unsaturated air may become saturated by ;\n",
        "answer": "expanding it adiabatically.\n",
        "choiceone": "lowering the pressure , keeping temperature constant.\n",
        "choicetwo": "compressing it adiabatically.\n",
        "choicethree": "raising the temperature.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A significant inversion at low height is a characteristic of ;\n",
        "answer": "nocturnal radiation.\n",
        "choiceone": "the passage of cold front.\n",
        "choicetwo": "advection fog.\n",
        "choicethree": "cumulus clouds.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A small supercooled cloud droplet that collides with an airfoil will most likely ;\n",
        "answer": "freeze immediately and create rime ice.\n",
        "choiceone": "travel back over the wing , creating rime ice.\n",
        "choicetwo": "travel back over the wing , creating clear ice.\n",
        "choicethree": "freeze immediately and create clear ice.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A SPECI is ;\n",
        "answer": "an aviation special weather report.\n",
        "choiceone": "a warning for special weather phenomena.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an aviation routine weather report.\n",
        "choicethree": "a forecast for special weather phenomena.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A special air-report ;\n",
        "answer": "may trigger a SIGMET message.\n",
        "choiceone": "may be the reason for closing an airport due to meteological conditions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is used to produce better aerodrome forecasts ( TAF ).\n",
        "choicethree": "may be the reason for closing a part of an airway due to meteological conditions.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A stationary front is a front in which ;\n",
        "answer": "there is no horizontal motion perpendicular to the front.\n",
        "choiceone": "there is no difference in temperature between the two air masses.\n",
        "choicetwo": "there is no wind on both sides of the front.\n",
        "choicethree": "there are never frontal clouds.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A stationary observer in the northern hemisphere is situated in front of a depression. The centre of the depression passes from\nwest to east and south of the observer. For this observer the wind ;\n",
        "answer": "backs.\n",
        "choiceone": "initially veers , then backs.\n",
        "choicetwo": "veers.\n",
        "choicethree": "initially backs , then veers.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A strong , dry and warm downslope wind , produced by prior enforced ascent of air over hills or mountains is known as a ;\n",
        "answer": "Foehn.\n",
        "choiceone": "Bora.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Mistral.\n",
        "choicethree": "Scirocco.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A super-cooled droplet is ;\n",
        "answer": "a droplet still in liquid state at a temperature below 0\u00b0C.\n",
        "choiceone": "a small particle of water at a temperature below -50\u00b0C.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a water droplet that has been frozen during its descent.\n",
        "choicethree": "a water droplet that is mainly frozen.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A surface based inversion is a characteristic of ;\n",
        "answer": "nocturnal radiation during clear nights.\n",
        "choiceone": "the passage of cold front.\n",
        "choicetwo": "hill fog.\n",
        "choicethree": "cumulus clouds.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A temperature inversion indicates a state of the atmosphere which is ;\n",
        "answer": "absolutely stable.\n",
        "choiceone": "absolutely unstable.\n",
        "choicetwo": "conditionally unstable.\n",
        "choicethree": "indifferent.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A temperature of +15\u00b0C is recorded at an altitude of 500 metres above sea level. If the vertical temperature gradient is that of\na standard atmosphere , what will the temperature be at the summit of a mountain , 2500 metres above sea level ?\n",
        "answer": "+2\u00b0C 2500 \u2013 500 = 2000 feet\n",
        "choiceone": "0\u00b0C\n",
        "choicetwo": "\u20132\u00b0C Her 1000 metrede s\u0131cakl\u0131k ISA\u2019ya g\u00f6re 6.5\u00b0C d\u00fc\u015fece\u011finden ;\n",
        "choicethree": "+4\u00b0C 2 x 6.5\u00b0C = 13\u00b0C\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A trough near the surface is an area of ;\n",
        "answer": "convergence and widespread ascent.\n",
        "choiceone": "divergence and widespread ascent.\n",
        "choicetwo": "convergence and subsidence.\n",
        "choicethree": "divergence and subsidence.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A trough of low pressure on a surface synoptic chart is an area of ;\n",
        "answer": "convergence and widespread ascent.\n",
        "choiceone": "convergence and subsidence.\n",
        "choicetwo": "divergence and widespread ascent.\n",
        "choicethree": "divergence and subsidence.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A vertical spacing of 1000 ft is the standard required separation between two FL. Under conditions of cold air advection\n( ISA \u2013 15\u00b0C ) , what would the true vertical separation be ?\n",
        "answer": "Less than 1000 ft.\n",
        "choiceone": "More than 1000 ft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It remains 1000 ft.\n",
        "choicethree": "Without QNH information , it can not be determined.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A vertical temperature profile indicates the possibility of severe icing when the temperature profile ;\n",
        "answer": "intersects the 0\u00b0C isotherm twice.\n",
        "choiceone": "indicates temperatures above 3\u00b0C.\n",
        "choicetwo": "coincides with a dry adiabatic lapse rate.\n",
        "choicethree": "indicates temperatures below -40\u00b0C.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A wide body takes off on a clear night in Dhahran , Saudi Arabia. Shortly after take off the aircraft\u2019s rate of climb drops to\nzero. This can be due to ;\n",
        "answer": "a very strong temperature inversion.\n",
        "choiceone": "sand/dust in the engines.\n",
        "choicetwo": "low relative humidity.\n",
        "choicethree": "very pronounced downdrafts.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A wind of 20 knots corresponds to an approximate speed of ;\n",
        "answer": "10 m/sec.\n 20 knot = 20 NM/h = 20 x 1.852 = 37.04 km/h\n",
        "choiceone": "40 m/sec.\n",
        "choicetwo": "50 km/h.\n 37.04 km/h = 37040 m/h = 37040 : 60 = 617.33 m/min\n",
        "choicethree": "10 km/h.\n 617.33 m/min = 617.33 : 60 = 10.28 \u2248 10 m/sec\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A wind sounding in the region of a polar front jet stream gives the following wind profile ( Northern hemisphere) ;\n 900 hPa 220/20 kt\n 800 hPa 220/25 kt\n 700 hPa 230/35 kt\n 500 hPa 260/60 kt\n 400 hPa 280/85 kt\n 300 hPa 300/100 kt\n 250 hPa 310/120 kt\n 200 hPa 310/80 kt\n Which system is the jet stream associated with ?\n",
        "answer": "With a warm front.\n",
        "choiceone": "With a ITCZ.\n",
        "choicetwo": "With a cold front.\n",
        "choicethree": "With an easterly wave.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A wind speed of 350 kt within a jet stream core should be world-wide regarded as ;\n",
        "answer": "possible but a very rare phenomenon.\n",
        "choiceone": "not unusual in polar regions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a common occurrence.\n",
        "choicethree": "not possible.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A winter day in northern Europe with a thick layer of stratocumulus clouds and temperature close to zero degrees C at\nground level , you can expect ;\n",
        "answer": "a high probability for icing in clouds. Severe icing may occur in the upper part due to accumulation of large\n droplets.\n",
        "choiceone": "decreasing visibility due to snowfall below cloud base, but only light icing in clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "turbulence due to a strong inversion, but no icing because clouds consist of ice crystals.\n",
        "choicethree": "reduced visibility and light icing in clouds.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A zone of strong convection currents is encountered during a flight. In spite of moderate gust you decide to continue the\nflight. What are your precautionary measures ?\n",
        "answer": "Decrease the speed / try to climb above the zone of convective currents if aircraft performance parameters\n allow.\n",
        "choiceone": "Increase the speed / try to descend below the zone of convective currents.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Decrease the speed / try to descend below the zone of convective currents.\n",
        "choicethree": "Increase the speed / try to climb above the zone of convective currents if aircraft performance parameters\n allow.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "About ten identical clouds are in the sky , well isolated from one another , dense , with well defined contours , developing\nvertically in a cauliflower shape. The side of these clouds lit by the sun is bright white. Their base , relatively dark , is essentially\nhorizontal and at FL 30 , and their tops at FL 150. These clouds are ;\n",
        "answer": "towering Cumulus.\n",
        "choiceone": "broken Cumulus.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Altocumulus castellanus.\n",
        "choicethree": "Stratocumulus.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Above and below a low level inversion the wind is likely to ;\n",
        "answer": "change significantly in speed and direction.\n",
        "choiceone": "change in speed but not in direction.\n",
        "choicetwo": "experience little or no change in speed and direction.\n",
        "choicethree": "change in direction but not in speed.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Absolute instability in the atmosphere will occur when the environmental lapse rate is ;\n",
        "answer": "greater than both saturated adiabatic lapse rate and dry adiabatic lapse rate.\n",
        "choiceone": "less than both saturated adiabatic lapse rate and dry adiabatic lapse rate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "less than saturated adiabatic lapse rate.\n",
        "choicethree": "greater than saturated adiabatic lapse rate but less than dry adiabatic lapse rate.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Absolute instability is said to exist whenever the environmental lapse rate ;\n",
        "answer": "exceeds the dry adiabatic lapse rate.\n",
        "choiceone": "is less than the dry adiabatic lapse rate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is between the dry and saturated adiabatic lapse rate.\n",
        "choicethree": "is less than the saturated adiabatic lapse rate.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4338A rev. 20.01.2003 )\n Annex 050-4338A\n According to ICAO , which symbol indicates a tropical revolving storm ?\n",
        "answer": "Symbol 4\n",
        "choiceone": "Symbol 2\n",
        "choicetwo": "Symbol 1\n",
        "choicethree": "Symbol 3\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4339A rev. 20.01.2003 )\n Annex 050-4339A\n According to ICAO , which symbol indicates danger to an aircraft flying according to instrument flight rules ( IFR ) ?\n",
        "answer": "Symbol 2\n",
        "choiceone": "Symbol 3\n",
        "choicetwo": "Symbol 1\n",
        "choicethree": "Symbol 4\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4340A rev. 20.01.1003 )\n Annex 050-4340A\n According to ICAO , which symbol indicates danger to an aircraft flying according to instrument flight rules ( IFR ) ?\n",
        "answer": "Symbol 3\n",
        "choiceone": "Symbol 4\n",
        "choicetwo": "Symbol 2\n",
        "choicethree": "Symbol 1\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 1 )\n Image 1\n According to ICAO , which symbol indicates severe icing ?\n",
        "answer": "Symbol d\n",
        "choiceone": "Symbol b\n",
        "choicetwo": "Symbol c\n",
        "choicethree": "Symbol a\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4337A rev. 20.01.2003 )\n Annex 050-4337A\n According to ICAO , which symbol indicates severe icing ?\n",
        "answer": "Symbol 1\n",
        "choiceone": "Symbol 3\n",
        "choicetwo": "Symbol 2\n",
        "choicethree": "Symbol 4\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 1 )\n Image 1\n According to ICAO , which symbol indicates a severe line squall ?\n",
        "answer": "Symbol a\n",
        "choiceone": "Symbol c\n",
        "choicetwo": "Symbol b\n",
        "choicethree": "Symbol d\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 1 )\n Image 1\n According to ICAO , which symbol indicates a tropical revolving storm ?\n",
        "answer": "Symbol c\n",
        "choiceone": "Symbol b\n",
        "choicetwo": "Symbol d\n",
        "choicethree": "Symbol a\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 9 )\n Image 9\n According to ICAO , which symbol indicates danger to an aircraft flying according to instrument flight rules ( IFR ) ?\n",
        "answer": "Symbol 2\n",
        "choiceone": "Symbol 1\n",
        "choicetwo": "Symbol 4\n",
        "choicethree": "Symbol 3\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 1 )\n Image 1\n According to ICAO , which symbol indicates widespread haze ?\n",
        "answer": "Symbol b\n",
        "choiceone": "Symbol c\n",
        "choicetwo": "Symbol a\n",
        "choicethree": "Symbol d\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "According to ISA the temperature in the lower part of the stratosphere ;\n",
        "answer": "is constant with altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "decreases with altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "first increases with altitude but decreases at higher altitudes.\n",
        "choicethree": "increases with altitude.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-11873A )\n Annex 050-11873A\n According to the extract of the surface isobar map , the surface wind direction over the sea is approximately ;\n",
        "answer": "140\u00b0.\n",
        "choiceone": "110\u00b0.\n",
        "choicetwo": "220\u00b0.\n",
        "choicethree": "310\u00b0.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Advection fog can be formed when ;\n",
        "answer": "warm moist air flows over a colder surface.\n",
        "choiceone": "cold moist air flows over warmer water.\n",
        "choicetwo": "warm moist air flows over a warmer surface.\n",
        "choicethree": "cold moist air flows over a warmer surface.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Advection fog is most likely to form when ;\n",
        "answer": "a mild moist airstream flows over snow covered ground and the wind speed is less than 10 kt.\n",
        "choiceone": "warm maritime air flows over a relatively warmer surface and the wind speed is greater than 15 kt.\n",
        "choicetwo": "cold maritime air flows over a warmer surface and the wind speed is greater than 15 kt.\n",
        "choicethree": "cold air is forced over higher ground and further adiabatic cooling occurs.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Advection is ;\n",
        "answer": "horizontal motion of air.\n",
        "choiceone": "the same as subsidence.\n",
        "choicetwo": "vertical motion of air.\n",
        "choicethree": "the same as convection.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Advection of very cold air over a warm sea current can cause ;\n",
        "answer": "steaming fog.\n",
        "choiceone": "no fog at all.\n",
        "choicetwo": "frontal fog.\n",
        "choicethree": "advection fog.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "After a clear night cumuliform clouds are formed in the morning. Why can the base of these clouds become higher during the\nday ?\n",
        "answer": "Because the surface temperature increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "The wind speed is increasing , because the cold air mass changes into a warm air mass.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Because the difference between the temperature and the dewpoint temperature at the initial condensation\n level becomes smaller.\n",
        "choicethree": "Because the stability increases.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "After a prolonged VMC descent in very cold air , you penetrate a humid air mass. What type of icing will you encounter ?\n",
        "answer": "Hoar frost\n",
        "choiceone": "Smooth icing\n",
        "choicetwo": "Rime ice\n",
        "choicethree": "Clear ice\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "After a sunny day , followed by a long clear night , you take-off from an airfield at mid-latitudes an hour before sunrise. The\nfield is not situated close to the coast. Though the pressure gradient is rather large , the easterly surface wind is weak and makes ;\n",
        "answer": "a sudden strong increase in wind speed and strong veering of the wind a short time after take-off.\n",
        "choiceone": "little increase in wind speed and little veering of the wind up to a height of 5000 ft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "large but gradual increase in wind speed and large but gradual veering of the wind up to a height of 5000 ft.\n",
        "choicethree": "a squally wind up to great heights.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "After a sunny day , followed by a long clear night , you take-off from an airfield at mid-latitudes in the northern hemisphere\nan hour before sunrise. The field is not situated close to the coast. Though the pressure gradient is rather large , the easterly surface\nwind is weak. What do you expect ?\n",
        "answer": "A sudden strong increase in wind speed and strong veering of the wind a short time after take-off.\n",
        "choiceone": "A squally wind up to great heights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A little increase in wind speed and little veering of the wind up to a height of 5000 ft.\n",
        "choicethree": "A large but gradual increase in wind speed and large but gradual veering of the wind up to a height of\n 5000 ft.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "After landing at an aerodrome ( aerodrome elevation 1715 ft ) , the altimeter indicates an altitude of 1310 ft. The altimeter is\nset to the pressure value of 1013 hPa. What is the QNH at this aerodrome ?\n",
        "answer": "1028 hPa. 1715 ft \u2013 1310 ft = 405 ft , 1 hPa\u2019\u0131 27 ft olarak al\u0131rsak ;\n",
        "choiceone": "1013 hPa.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1015 hPa. 407 : 27 = 15 hPa. U\u00e7ak ini\u015fte d\u00fc\u015f\u00fck bir irtifa okudu\u011fu\n",
        "choicethree": "998 hPa. i\u00e7in QNH daha y\u00fcksek bir de\u011ferde olmal\u0131d\u0131r. Buna g\u00f6re ;\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "After landing at an aerodrome ( QNH 993 hPa ) it is noticed that the altimeter is still set to 1013.2 hPa and that it reads 1200\nfeet. What is the elevation of the aerodrome above mean sea level ?\n",
        "answer": "660 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "2280 feet. 1013 hPa \u2013 993 hPa = 20 hPa , 1 hPa\u2019\u0131 27 ft olarak al\u0131rsak ;\n",
        "choicetwo": "1200 feet. 20 : 27 = 540 ft. U\u00e7ak daha y\u00fcksek bir altimetrik de\u011fer set ederek\n",
        "choicethree": "1740 feet. ini\u015f yapt\u0131\u011f\u0131na g\u00f6re meydan irtifas\u0131n\u0131 daha y\u00fcksek olarak okumu\u015ftur.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "After passing at right angles through a very active cold front in the direction of the cold air , what will you encounter at\nFL 50 , in the northern hemisphere immediately after a marked change in temperature ?\n",
        "answer": "A veering in the wind direction.\n",
        "choiceone": "A backing in the wind direction.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A decrease in tailwind.\n",
        "choicethree": "An increase in tailwind.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ahead of a warm front ( northern hemisphere ) the wind direction changes from the surface up to the tropopause. The effect\nof this change is that the wind ;\n",
        "answer": "veers in the friction layer and veers above the friction layer.\n",
        "choiceone": "backs in the friction layer and backs above the friction layer.\n",
        "choicetwo": "veers in the friction layer and backs above the friction layer.\n",
        "choicethree": "backs in the friction layer and veers above the friction layer.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Air masses which are being cooled from below are often characterized by ;\n",
        "answer": "fog , poor visibility and layered clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "uniform temperature good visibility.\n",
        "choicetwo": "continuous rain and freezing temperatures.\n",
        "choicethree": "strong winds , cumulus clouds , good visibility.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Aircraft struck by lightning may sometimes get considerable damage and at least temporarily the manoeuvring of the aircraft\nwill be made more difficult. Which one of the following statements is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "Aircraft made by composite material may get severe damage , the crew may be blinded and temporarily lose\n the hearing.\n",
        "choiceone": "An aircraft has in the atmosphere the same qualities as a \u201cFaradays cage\u201d , which means that struck of\n lightning seldom occurs. But if it happens , the result will be an occasional engine failure. The crew may get\n a shock.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Aircraft made by composite material can't conduct a lightning and will therefore very seldom be struck.\n",
        "choicethree": "An aircraft made by metal has a certain capacity to attract a lightning , but the lightning will follow the\n surface and therefore no damage will be caused.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "All pilots encountering Clear Air Turbulence are requested to report it. You experience CAT which causes passengers and\ncrew to feel definite strain against their seat belt or shoulders straps. Unsecured objects are dislodged. Food service and walking are\ndifficult. This intensity of CAT should be reported as ;\n",
        "answer": "moderate.\n",
        "choiceone": "severe.\n",
        "choicetwo": "light.\n",
        "choicethree": "extreme.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Along the West coast of India the prevailing winds are the ;\n",
        "answer": "SW monsoon in July and a NE monsoon in January.\n",
        "choiceone": "SW monsoon in July and a SE monsoon in January.\n",
        "choicetwo": "SE monsoon in July and a SW monsoon in January.\n",
        "choicethree": "NE monsoon in July and a SW monsoon in January.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Altostratus clouds are classified as ;\n",
        "answer": "medium level clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "low level clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "convective clouds.\n",
        "choicethree": "high level clouds.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aerodrome warning message gives information , among other things , about ;\n",
        "answer": "TS , SN including the expected or observed snow accumulation , hoar frost.\n",
        "choiceone": "PL , SS , RA.\n",
        "choicetwo": "GR , FG , FZRA including the observed friction coefficient.\n",
        "choicethree": "DS , SN clearing , FZRA including the observed braking action.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane flies at flight level 40. Elevation of the aerodrome 990 ft , QNH 976 hPa. The tower clears the pilot to fly at\n3000 ft QNH. Which of the following statements is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "Only a small change of altitude is necessary.\n",
        "choiceone": "The aeroplane has to descend about 2000 ft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The aeroplane has to climb about 1000 ft.\n",
        "choicethree": "The aeroplane has to descend about 1000 ft.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An air mass acquires its basic properties ;\n",
        "answer": "by stagnation of the air for a long period of time over areas having particular characteristics.\n",
        "choiceone": "by the influence of jet streams.\n",
        "choicetwo": "by widespread thunderstorms.\n",
        "choicethree": "in the westerlies of the mid-latitudes.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An air mass is ;\n",
        "answer": "an extensive body of air within which the temperature and humidity in horizontal planes are practically\n uniform.\n",
        "choiceone": "a large body of air within which the temperature and humidityis uniform in horizontal and vertical planes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a large body of air with temperature and humidity constant in the vertical.\n",
        "choicethree": "a body of air with a volume of not more than thousand cubic kilometres.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An air mass is called stable when ;\n",
        "answer": "the vertical motion of rising air tends to become weaker and disappears.\n",
        "choiceone": "the environmental lapse rate is high , with little vertical motion of air currents.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the temperature in a given air mass decreases rapidly with height.\n",
        "choicethree": "the pressure in a given area is constant.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An air mass is stable when ;\n",
        "answer": "the vertical motion of a rising parcel of air tends to become weaker and disappears.\n",
        "choiceone": "pressure is constant.\n",
        "choicetwo": "temperature in a given area drops off very rapidly with height.\n",
        "choicethree": "the lapse rate is 1\u00b0C per 100 m.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An air mass is stable when ;\n",
        "answer": "lifted air returns to its original level.\n",
        "choiceone": "temperature in a given area drops off very rapidly with height.\n",
        "choicetwo": "pressure is constant.\n",
        "choicethree": "the lapse rate is 1\u00b0C per 100 m.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An air mass is unstable when ;\n",
        "answer": "an ascending parcel of air continues to rise to a considerable height.\n",
        "choiceone": "temperature and humidity are not constant\n",
        "choicetwo": "pressure shows a marked variation over a given horizontal area\n",
        "choicethree": "temperature increases with height\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An air mass which originates over the North Atlantic between 50 and 70 degrees north and is moving in over Scandinavia is\ncalled ;\n",
        "answer": "maritime polar air.\n",
        "choiceone": "continental arctic air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "maritime arctic air.\n",
        "choicethree": "continental polar air.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An air temperature of \u201315\u00b0C at the 700 hPa level over central Europe in summer is ;\n",
        "answer": "low. 1000 feet\u2019de 2\u00b0C d\u00fc\u015fer , buna g\u00f6re FL100\u2019da olmas\u0131 gereken s\u0131cakl\u0131k ;\n",
        "choiceone": "within \u00b1 5\u00baC of ISA.\n",
        "choicetwo": "20\u00baC below standard. 700 hPa seviyesi FL100\u2019a kar\u015f\u0131l\u0131k gelmektedir. ISA\u2019ya g\u00f6re s\u0131cakl\u0131k her\n",
        "choicethree": "high. ( 2 x 10 ) \u2013 15 = \u20135\u00b0C\u2019dir. Yani \u201315\u00b0C ISA\u2019g\u00f6re 10\u00b0C daha so\u011fuktur.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An air temperature of \u201330\u00b0C at the 300 hPa level over central Europe in summer is ;\n",
        "answer": "high.\n",
        "choiceone": "within \u00b1 5\u00baC of ISA. 300 hPa seviyesi FL300\u2019a kar\u015f\u0131l\u0131k gelmektedir. ISA\u2019ya g\u00f6re s\u0131cakl\u0131k her\n",
        "choicetwo": "very low. 1000 feet\u2019de 2\u00b0C d\u00fc\u015fer , buna g\u00f6re FL300\u2019de olmas\u0131 gereken s\u0131cakl\u0131k ;\n",
        "choicethree": "low. ( 2 x 30 ) \u2013 15 = \u201345\u00b0C\u2019dir. Yani \u201330\u00b0C ISA\u2019g\u00f6re 15\u00b0C daha s\u0131cakt\u0131r.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An air temperature of \u201355\u00b0C at the 200 hPa level over central Europe in summer is ;\n",
        "answer": "within \u00b1 5\u00baC of ISA.\n",
        "choiceone": "low.\n",
        "choicetwo": "high. 200 hPa seviyesi FL390\u2019a kar\u015f\u0131l\u0131k gelmektedir. ISA\u2019ya g\u00f6re bu seviyede\n",
        "choicethree": "very high. kabul edilen s\u0131cakl\u0131k \u201356\u00b0C\u2019dir. Soruda verilen \u201355\u00b0C\u2019lik s\u0131cakl\u0131k da\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An airborne weather radar installation makes it possible to detect the location of ;\n",
        "answer": "zones of precipitation , particularly liquid-state precipitation , and also their intensity.\n",
        "choiceone": "cumulonimbus , but provided that cloud of this type is accompanied by falls of hail.\n",
        "choicetwo": "stratocumulus and its vertical development.\n",
        "choicethree": "all clouds.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft descents in layered clouds , the freezing level is situated at FL 60. At what levels is the probability for airframe\nicing the highest ?\n",
        "answer": "Between FL 120 and FL 60.\n",
        "choiceone": "Between FL 60 and FL 20.\n",
        "choicetwo": "At FL 140.\n",
        "choicethree": "Between FL 120 and FL 180.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft encounters atmospheric conditions in which abrupt changes of attitude and altitude of the aircraft occur. Changes\nin accelerometer readings go up to 1.2 g measured at the aircraft\u2019s centre of gravity. Lose objects inside the aircraft are tossed about.\nWhich report , if any , is required ?\n",
        "answer": "Special air-report\n",
        "choiceone": "Flight safety report\n",
        "choicetwo": "Routine air-report\n",
        "choicethree": "No air-report is necessary\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft flies at flight level 40. Elevation of the aerodrome : 990 ft , QNH 976 hPa. The tower clears the pilot to fly at\n3000 ft QNH. Which of the following statements is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "Only a small change of altitude is necessary.\n",
        "choiceone": "The aircraft has to descend about 2000 ft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The aircraft has to climb about 1000 ft.\n",
        "choicethree": "The aircraft has to descend about 1000 ft.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft flies into freezing rain in an area with a temperature below 0\u00b0C. The type of icing it will most likely encounter is ;\n",
        "answer": "clear ice.\n",
        "choiceone": "rime ice.\n",
        "choicetwo": "hoar frost.\n",
        "choicethree": "granular frost.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft flying at FL 45 ( OAT 6\u00b0C ) obtains a reading of 1860 ft on its radio altimeter when flying over ground 3090 ft\nabove mean sea level. What is the value of the QNH , to the nearest hPa , at that point ?\n",
        "answer": "1030\n",
        "choiceone": "1013 3090 + 1860 = 4950 ft u\u00e7a\u011f\u0131n MSL\u2019e g\u00f6re ger\u00e7ek irtifas\u0131d\u0131r.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1042 FL45 = 4500 ft , 4950 \u2013 4500 = 450 ft ger\u00e7ek irtifa ile bas\u0131n\u00e7 irtifas\u0131 aras\u0131ndaki farkt\u0131r.\n",
        "choicethree": "996 FL45\u2019deki +6\u00b0C\u2019lik s\u0131cakl\u0131k ISA\u2019ya g\u00f6re uygun de\u011ferde oldu\u011fundan s\u0131cakl\u0131k sapmas\u0131 yoktur.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft flying at FL 100 from Marseille ( QNH 1012 hPa ) to Palma de Mallorca ( QNH 1006 hPa ) experiences no\nchange to true altitude. The reason for this is that ;\n",
        "answer": "the air at Palma de Mallorca is warmer than that at Marseille.\n",
        "choiceone": "the altimeters are erroneous , and need to be tested.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the air at Palma de Mallorca is colder than that at Marseille.\n",
        "choicethree": "one of the two QNH values may be incorrect.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft flying in the southern hemisphere at 2000 feet , has to turn to the right in order to allow for drift. In which\ndirection , relative to the aircraft , is the centre of low pressure ?\n",
        "answer": "In front.\n",
        "choiceone": "Behind.\n",
        "choicetwo": "To the left.\n",
        "choicethree": "To the right.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is approaching a cold front from the warm air mass side at FL 270 and experiencing moderate to severe\nturbulence. A jet stream is forecast to be at FL 310. The shortest way to get out of this turbulence is by ;\n",
        "answer": "descending.\n",
        "choiceone": "maintain FL 270.\n",
        "choicetwo": "turn right.\n",
        "choicethree": "climbing.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is approaching under visual flight rules an airfield ( northern hemisphere ) whose runway is parallel to the coast.\nWhen downwind over the sea , the airfield is on the left. What wind effect should be anticipated on final approach and landing during\na sunny afternoon ?\n",
        "answer": "Crosswind from the left.\n",
        "choiceone": "Crosswind from the right.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Tailwind.\n",
        "choicethree": "Headwind.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is approaching under visual flight rules an airfield whose runway is parallel to the coast. When downwind over\nthe sea , the airfield is on the right. What wind effect should be anticipated on final approach and landing during a sunny afternoon ?\n",
        "answer": "Crosswind from the right.\n",
        "choiceone": "Headwind.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Crosswind from the left.\n",
        "choicethree": "Tailwind.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is descending to land under IFR. If the local QNH is 1009 hPa , what will happen to the altitude reading when the\naltimeter is reset at the transition level ?\n",
        "answer": "It will decrease.\n",
        "choiceone": "It will increase.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It will not be affected.\n",
        "choicethree": "It will remain the same.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is flying at FL 80. The local QNH is 1000 hPa. After the second altimeter has been adjusted to the local QNH ,\nthe reading will be approximately ;\n",
        "answer": "7650 ft. 13 x 27 = 351 ft , Altimetreye daha d\u00fc\u015f\u00fck bir bas\u0131n\u00e7 y\u00fczeyinin\n",
        "choiceone": "8600 ft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "8350 ft. 1013 \u2013 1000 = 13 hPa , 1 hPa 27 ft kabul edersek ;\n",
        "choicethree": "8000 ft. de\u011feri ba\u011flanaca\u011f\u0131ndan okunacak de\u011fer daha k\u00fc\u00e7\u00fck olacakt\u0131r ;\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is flying at FL 180 in the northern hemisphere with a crosswind from the left. Which of the following is correct\nconcerning its true altitude ?\n",
        "answer": "It decreases.\n",
        "choiceone": "It remains constant.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It increases.\n",
        "choicethree": "Without knowing temperatures at FL 180 this question can not be answered.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4246A )\n Annex 050-4246A\n An aircraft is flying from Point A to Point B at the flight level corresponding to the pressure surface of the constant pressure\nchart. Which of the following statements is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "Wind speed over B is higher than over Paris.\n",
        "choiceone": "Wind speed over A is higher than over B.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The true altitude will be higher over B than over A.\n",
        "choicethree": "The true altitude will be higher over B than over Paris.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4247A )\n Annex 050-4247A\n An aircraft is flying from Point A to Point B at the flight level corresponding to the pressure surface of the constant pressure\nchart. Which of the following statements is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "Wind speed over B is higher than over A.\n",
        "choiceone": "The true altitude will be higher over B than over London.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Wind speed over A is higher than over B.\n",
        "choicethree": "The true altitude will be higher over B than over A.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4248A )\n Annex 050-4248A\n An aircraft is flying from Point A to Point B at the flight level corresponding to the pressure surface of the constant pressure\nchart. Which of the following statements is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "Wind speed over A is higher than over B.\n",
        "choiceone": "Wind speed over B is higher than over A.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The true altitude will be higher over A than over Madrid.\n",
        "choicethree": "The true altitude will be higher over A than over B.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4249A )\n Annex 050-4249A\n An aircraft is flying from Point A to Point B at the flight level corresponding to the pressure surface of the constant pressure\nchart. Which of the following statements is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "Wind speed over A is higher than over B.\n",
        "choiceone": "The true altitude will be higher over A than over B.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Wind speed over B is higher than over A.\n",
        "choicethree": "The true altitude will be higher over B than over Melbourne.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4246A )\n Annex 050-4246A\n An aircraft is flying from Point A to Point B on the upper level contour chart. The altimeter setting is 1013.2 hPa. Which of\nthese statements is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "The true altitude will be higher at A than at B.\n",
        "choiceone": "Wind speed at Paris is higher than at B.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The true altitude will be higher at B than at A.\n",
        "choicethree": "Wind speed at A is higher than at B.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4247A )\n Annex 050-4247A\n An aircraft is flying from Point A to Point B on the upper level contour chart. The altimeter setting is 1013.2 hPa. Which of\nthese statements is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "The true altitude will be higher at A than at B.\n",
        "choiceone": "The true altitude will be higher at B than at A.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Wind speed at A and at B is the same.\n",
        "choicethree": "Wind speed at A is higher than at B.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4248A )\n Annex 050-4248A\n An aircraft is flying from Point A to Point B on the upper level contour chart. The altimeter setting is 1013.2 hPa. Which of\nthese statements is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "The true altitude will be higher at B than at A.\n",
        "choiceone": "Wind speed at Madrid is higher than at A.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The true altitude will be higher at A than at B.\n",
        "choicethree": "Wind speed at B is higher than at A.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4249A )\n Annex 050-4249A\n An aircraft is flying from Point A to Point B on the upper level contour chart. The altimeter setting is 1013.2 hPa. Which of\nthese statements is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "The true altitude will be higher at B than at A.\n",
        "choiceone": "Wind speed at A and at B is the same.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The true altitude will be higher at A than at B.\n",
        "choicethree": "Wind speed at B is higher than at A.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is flying from South to North , above the polar front jet stream , at FL 400 in the southern hemisphere. What\nchange , if any , in temperature will be experienced ?\n",
        "answer": "It decreases.\n",
        "choiceone": "It increases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It decreases and then increases.\n",
        "choicethree": "It stays the same.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is flying in the southern hemisphere at 2000 feet , has to turn to the right in order to allow for drift. In which\ndirection , relative to the aircraft , is the centre of low pressure ?\n",
        "answer": "In front.\n",
        "choiceone": "To the left.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Behind.\n",
        "choicethree": "To the right.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is flying in the southern hemisphere at low altitude ( less than 2000 feet ) and going directly away from a centre\nof low pressure. What direction , relative to the aircraft , does the wind come from ?\n",
        "answer": "From the left and slightly on the nose.\n",
        "choiceone": "From the right and slightly on the nose.\n",
        "choicetwo": "From the right and slightly on the tail.\n",
        "choicethree": "From the left and slightly on the tail.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is flying over the Alps on a very cold winter\u2019s day. The regional QNH is 1013 hPa. During the flight , you circle\naround a mountain at an altitude of its summit. What reading will the aneroid altimeter give , compared to the elevation of the\nsummit ?\n",
        "answer": "A higher altitude than the elevation of the summit.\n",
        "choiceone": "The same altitude as the elevation of the summit.\n",
        "choicetwo": "There is insufficient information to come to a conclusion.\n",
        "choicethree": "A lower altitude than the elevation of the summit.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is flying over the Alps on a warm summer\u2019s day. The weather is fine , and there is a high pressure system in the\narea. During the flight , a mountain is passed at an altitude of its summit. What reading will the aneroid altimeter give , compared to\nthe summit\u2019s elevation ?\n",
        "answer": "A lower altitude than the elevation of the summit.\n",
        "choiceone": "A higher altitude than the elevation of the summit.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The same altitude as the elevation of the summit.\n",
        "choicethree": "There is insufficient information to come to a conclusion.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is flying over the sea at FL 90 , the true altitude is 9100 feet , local QNH is unknown. What assumption , if any ,\ncan be made about the air mass in which the aircraft is flying ?\n",
        "answer": "There is insufficient information to make any assumption.\n",
        "choiceone": "It is colder than ISA.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Its average temperature is the same as ISA.\n",
        "choicethree": "It is warmer than ISA.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is flying over the sea at FL 100 , with a true altitude of 10.000 feet , local QNH is 1003 hPa. What assumption , if\nany , can be made about the air mass in which the aircraft is flying ?\n",
        "answer": "It is warmer than ISA.\n",
        "choiceone": "It is colder than ISA.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Its average temperature is about ISA.\n",
        "choicethree": "There is insufficient information to come to any conclusion.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is flying over the sea at FL 120 , with a true altitude of 12.000 feet , local QNH is 1013 hPa. What assumption , if\nany , can be made about the air mass in which the aircraft is flying ?\n",
        "answer": "Its average temperature is the same as ISA.\n",
        "choiceone": "It is warmer than ISA.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It is colder than ISA.\n",
        "choicethree": "There is insufficient information to come to any conclusion.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is flying through the Alps on a very cold winter\u2019s day. The regional QNH is 1013 hPa. During the flight , you\ncircle around a mountain at an altitude of its summit. What reading will the aneroid altimeter give , compared to the elevation of the\nsummit ?\n",
        "answer": "A higher altitude than the elevation of the summit.\n",
        "choiceone": "The same altitude as the elevation of the summit.\n",
        "choicetwo": "There is insufficient information to come to a conclusion.\n",
        "choicethree": "A lower altitude than the elevation of the summit.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is flying through the Alps on a warm summer\u2019s day. The weather is fine , and there is a high pressure system in\nthe area. During the flight , a mountain is passed at an altitude of its summit. What reading will the aneroid altimeter give , compared\nto the summit\u2019s elevation ?\n",
        "answer": "A lower altitude than the elevation of the summit.\n",
        "choiceone": "The same altitude as the elevation of the summit.\n",
        "choicetwo": "There is insufficient information to come to a conclusion.\n",
        "choicethree": "A higher altitude than the elevation of the summit.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is flying through the polar front jet stream from south to north , beneath the core. How would the OAT change ,\nin the northern hemisphere , during this portion of the flight ?\n",
        "answer": "It decreases.\n",
        "choiceone": "It increases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It remains constant.\n",
        "choicethree": "It first increases , then decreases.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft lands at an airport ( airport elevation 540 ft , QNH 993 hPa ) with the altimeter set to 1013 hPa. What will it\nindicate ?\n",
        "answer": "1080 ft. Altimetreye daha y\u00fcksek bir bas\u0131n\u00e7 de\u011feri set edildi\u011finden ini\u015fte altimetrede\n",
        "choiceone": "0 ft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "700 ft. 1013 \u2013 993 = 20 hPa , 1 hPa 27 feet kabul edersek ;\n",
        "choicethree": "380 ft. 20 x 27 = 540 feet ,\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft lands at an airport ( airport elevation 1240 ft , QNH 1008 hPa ). The altimeter is set to 1013 hPa. The altimeter\nwill indicate ;\n",
        "answer": "1375 ft.\n",
        "choiceone": "1105 ft. 1013 \u2013 1008 = 5 hPa , 1 hPa 27 feet kabul edersek ;\n",
        "choicetwo": "1280 ft. 5 x 27 = 135 feet ,\n",
        "choicethree": "1200 ft. Altimetreye daha y\u00fcksek bir bas\u0131n\u00e7 de\u011feri set edildi\u011finden ini\u015fte altimetrede\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft maintains a constant indicated altitude of 4500 ft from A ( 360 ft/AMSL - QNH 986 hPa ) to B ( 690 ft/AMSL -\nQNH 1011 hPa ). Assuming that the altimeter subscale setting remains unchanged at 986 hPa , the height of the aircraft above the\nsurface at B will be ;\n",
        "answer": "4485 ft. bulunan bir bas\u0131n\u00e7 y\u00fczeyindedir ve ger\u00e7ek irtifas\u0131 4500 feet\u2019den daha y\u00fcksekte bir de\u011ferde\n",
        "choiceone": "5175 ft. 1011 \u2013 986 = 25 hPa , 1 hPa 27 ft olarak al\u0131rsak \u2192 25 x 27 = 675 ft ,\n",
        "choicetwo": "3135 ft. U\u00e7ak QNH\u2019\u0131 1011 hPa olan B noktas\u0131nda 986 hPa ile u\u00e7maktad\u0131r , yani daha y\u00fcksekte\n",
        "choicethree": "4815 ft. olacakt\u0131r. 4500 + 675 = 5175 , soruda u\u00e7a\u011f\u0131n B noktas\u0131nda yerden y\u00fcksekli\u011fi soruldu\u011funa\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft maintains a constant indicated altitude of 5500 ft from A ( 1050 ft/AMSL - QNH 968 hPa ) to B ( 650 ft/AMSL -\nQNH 1016 hPa ). Assuming that the altimeter subscale setting remains unchanged at 968 hPa , the height of the aircraft above the\nsurface at B will be ;\n",
        "answer": "6146 ft. U\u00e7ak QNH\u2019\u0131 1016 hPa olan B noktas\u0131nda 968 hPa ile u\u00e7maktad\u0131r , yani daha y\u00fcksekte\n",
        "choiceone": "6796 ft. 1016 \u2013 968 = 48 hPa , 1 hPa 27 ft olarak al\u0131rsak \u2192 48 x 27 = 1296 ft ,\n",
        "choicetwo": "4854 ft. bulunan bir bas\u0131n\u00e7 y\u00fczeyindedir ve ger\u00e7ek irtifas\u0131 5500 feet\u2019den daha y\u00fcksekte bir de\u011ferde\n",
        "choicethree": "7446 ft. olacakt\u0131r. 5500 + 1296 = 6796 , soruda u\u00e7a\u011f\u0131n B noktas\u0131nda yerden y\u00fcksekli\u011fi\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft maintains a constant indicated altitude of 6500 ft from A ( 600 ft/AMSL - QNH 1012 hPa ) to B ( 930 ft/AMSL -\nQNH 977 hPa ). Assuming that the altimeter subscale setting remains unchanged at 1012 hPa , the height of the aircraft above the\nsurface at B will be ;\n",
        "answer": "4625 ft. U\u00e7ak QNH\u2019\u0131 977 hPa olan B noktas\u0131nda 1012 hPa ile u\u00e7maktad\u0131r , yani daha al\u00e7akta\n",
        "choiceone": "6515 ft. 1012 \u2013 977 = 35 hPa , 1 hPa 27 ft olarak al\u0131rsak \u2192 35 x 27 = 945 ft ,\n",
        "choicetwo": "5225 ft. bulunan bir bas\u0131n\u00e7 y\u00fczeyindedir ve ger\u00e7ek irtifas\u0131 6500 feet\u2019den daha d\u00fc\u015f\u00fck bir de\u011ferde\n",
        "choicethree": "5555 ft. olacakt\u0131r. 6500 \u2013 945 = 5555 , soruda u\u00e7a\u011f\u0131n B noktas\u0131nda yerden y\u00fcksekli\u011fi soruldu\u011funa\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft maintains a constant indicated altitude of 7500 ft from A ( 270 ft/AMSL - QNH 1021 hPa ) to B ( 1650 ft/AMSL\n- QNH 983 hPa ). Assuming that the altimeter subscale setting remains unchanged at 1021 hPa , the height of the aircraft above the\nsurface at B will be ;\n",
        "answer": "4824 ft. olacakt\u0131r. 7500 \u2013 1026 = 6474 , soruda u\u00e7a\u011f\u0131n B noktas\u0131nda yerden y\u00fcksekli\u011fi\n",
        "choiceone": "6474 ft. 1021 \u2013 983 = 38 hPa , 1 hPa 27 ft olarak al\u0131rsak \u2192 38 x 27 = 1026 ft ,\n",
        "choicetwo": "6204 ft. U\u00e7ak QNH\u2019\u0131 983 hPa olan B noktas\u0131nda 1021 hPa ile u\u00e7maktad\u0131r , yani daha al\u00e7akta\n",
        "choicethree": "6876 ft. bulunan bir bas\u0131n\u00e7 y\u00fczeyindedir ve ger\u00e7ek irtifas\u0131 7500 feet\u2019den daha d\u00fc\u015f\u00fck bir de\u011ferde\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft over Western Europe is crossing a jet stream 2500 ft below its core at right angles. While crossing , the outside\ntemperature is increasing. The prevailing wind is ;\n",
        "answer": "from the right.\n",
        "choiceone": "from the left.\n",
        "choicetwo": "headwind.\n",
        "choicethree": "tailwind.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An altimeter adjusted to 1013 hPa indicates an altitude of 3600 ft. Should this altimeter be adjusted to the local QNH value\nof 991 hPa , the altitude indicated would be ;\n",
        "answer": "3006 ft. 3600 \u2013 594 = 3006 ft.\n",
        "choiceone": "4194 ft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "4278 ft. 1013 \u2013 991 = 22 hPa , 1 hPa 27 ft olarak al\u0131rsak \u2192 22 x 27 = 594 ft ,\n",
        "choicethree": "2922 ft. 991 hPa set edildi\u011finde altimetrede g\u00f6r\u00fcnen irtifada d\u00fc\u015f\u00fc\u015f olaca\u011f\u0131ndan ;\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An easterly wave is a ;\n",
        "answer": "wave in a trade wind belt , moving from east to west , with severe convective activity in rear of its trough.\n",
        "choiceone": "disturbance in the higher levels associated with the equatorial easterly jet , moving from east to west , with\n severe convective activity in rear of its trough.\n",
        "choicetwo": "small scale wave disturbance in the tropics, moving from east to west , with severe convective activity ahead\n of its trough.\n",
        "choicethree": "wave-like disturbance in the monsoon regime of India , moving from east to west , with severe convective\n activity ahead of its trough.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An inversion is ;\n",
        "answer": "an absolutely stable layer.\n",
        "choiceone": "a layer that can be either stable or unstable.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an unstable layer.\n",
        "choicethree": "a conditionally unstable layer.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An inversion is ;\n",
        "answer": "an increase of temperature with height.\n",
        "choiceone": "a decrease of pressure with height.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an increase of pressure with height.\n",
        "choicethree": "a decrease of temperature with height.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An inversion is a layer of air which is ;\n",
        "answer": "absolutely stable.\n",
        "choiceone": "conditionally unstable.\n",
        "choicetwo": "conditionally stable.\n",
        "choicethree": "absolutely unstable.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An inversion is a layer of air in which the temperature ;\n",
        "answer": "increases with height.\n",
        "choiceone": "decreases with height less than 1\u00b0C/100m.\n",
        "choicetwo": "decreases with height more than 1\u00b0C/100m.\n",
        "choicethree": "remains constant with height.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An isohypse ( contour ) ;\n",
        "answer": "indicates the true altitude of a pressure level.\n",
        "choiceone": "indicates the altitude of the zero degree isotherm.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is the longest slope line of a frontal surface.\n",
        "choicethree": "is the limit between two air masses of different temperature.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An isohypse of the 500 hPa pressure surface is labelled with the number 552. This means that for all points on the isohypse\nthe ;\n",
        "answer": "topography is 552 decameters above MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "topography is 552 meters above MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "pressure is 552 hPa.\n",
        "choicethree": "pressure altimeter will overread by 552 FT.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An isothermal layer is a layer of air in which the temperature ;\n",
        "answer": "remains constant with height.\n",
        "choiceone": "decreases with height at a constant rate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increases with height.\n",
        "choicethree": "increases with height at a constant rate.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An observer on the northern hemisphere is under influence of the wind system of a depression , which is moving from West\nto East. The centre of the depression passes to the South of the observer. For this observer the wind direction is ;\n",
        "answer": "continuously backing.\n",
        "choiceone": "continuously veering.\n",
        "choicetwo": "initially backing , then veering.\n",
        "choicethree": "initially veering , then backing.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An occlusion has the characteristics of a warm front when ;\n",
        "answer": "the cold air behind is warmer than the cold air ahead.\n",
        "choiceone": "the cold air ahead is lifted.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the cold air behind is colder than the cold air ahead.\n",
        "choicethree": "the cold air behind is lifted by the warm air.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An occlusion is called a warm occlusion when the cold air ;\n",
        "answer": "at the rear of the occlusion is less cold than the cold air ahead , with the warm air at a higher altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "ahead of the surface position of the occlusion is only at a higher altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "at the rear of the occlusion is colder than the cold air ahead , with the warm air at a higher altitude.\n",
        "choicethree": "at the rear of the occlusion is colder than the cold air ahead.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An outside air temperature of \u201335\u00b0C is measured while cruising at FL 200. What is the temperature deviation from the ISA at\nthis level ?\n",
        "answer": "10\u00b0C colder than ISA. OAT \u201335\u00b0C oldu\u011fundan ISA\u2019ya g\u00f6re 10\u00b0C daha so\u011fuktur.\n",
        "choiceone": "10\u00b0C warmer than ISA.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5\u00b0C warmer than ISA. FL200\u2019da ISA\u2019ya g\u00f6re olmas\u0131 gereken s\u0131cakl\u0131k ;\n",
        "choicethree": "5\u00b0C colder than ISA. ( 2 x 20 ) \u2212 15 = 40 \u2013 15 = \u201325\u00b0C\u2019dir.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An unstable air mass is forced to ascend a mountain slope. What type of clouds can be expected ?\n",
        "answer": "Clouds with considerable vertical development and associated turbulence.\n",
        "choiceone": "Layer-like clouds with little vertical development.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Stratiform clouds with a temperature inversion.\n",
        "choicethree": "Stratiform clouds with considerable turbulence.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An unstable air mass will normally be characterised by ;\n",
        "answer": "cumuliform cloud and good visibility except in precipitation.\n",
        "choiceone": "stratiform cloud.\n",
        "choicetwo": "poor visibility due to haze at the lower levels.\n",
        "choicethree": "continuous light rain from medium level layer cloud.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Areas of sinking air are generally cloudless because as air sinks it ;\n",
        "answer": "is heated by compression.\n",
        "choiceone": "is heated by expansion.\n",
        "choicetwo": "reaches warmer layers.\n",
        "choicethree": "loses water vapour.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Around Paris on January 3rd at 1800 UTC , the surface temperature , under shelter , is +3\u00b0C. The sky is covered by 8 oktas\nof stratus. QNH is 1033 hPa. If the sky is covered all night , the minimum temperature of the night of January 3rd to January 4th\nshould be ;\n",
        "answer": "slightly below +3\u00b0C.\n",
        "choiceone": "significantly above +3\u00b0C.\n",
        "choicetwo": "significantly below 0\u00b0C.\n",
        "choicethree": "slightly above +3\u00b0C.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "As a result of diurnal variation radiation fog is lifted and a cloud cover is formed. Which statement is true ?\n",
        "answer": "Low stratus will develop caused by increasing wind speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "Stratocumulus will develop caused by insolation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Low stratus will develop caused by radiation in combination with low geostrophic wind speed.\n",
        "choicethree": "Layers of altocumulus will develop caused by increasing wind speed.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Assume that an aircraft is flying in the northern hemisphere at the 500 hPa pressure surface on a heading of 270 degrees.\nWhich of the following statements is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "If in this pressure surface the wind comes from the direction 360 degrees , then true altitude is increasing.\n",
        "choiceone": "If in this pressure surface the wind comes from the direction 270 degrees , then true altitude is increasing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "If in this pressure surface the wind comes from the direction 180 degrees , then true altitude is increasing.\n",
        "choicethree": "If in this pressure surface the wind comes from the direction 090 degrees , then true altitude is increasing.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10720A )\n Annex 050-10720A\n Assuming a generalised zonal system of world climatic and wind circulation , zone \u201ct\u201d is an area of ;\n",
        "answer": "subtropical high pressure systems.\n",
        "choiceone": "NE trade winds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "travelling low pressure systems.\n",
        "choicethree": "SE trade winds.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10720A )\n Annex 050-10720A\n Assuming a generalised zonal system of world climatic and wind circulation , zone \u201cu\u201d is in area of ;\n",
        "answer": "NE trade winds.\n",
        "choiceone": "SW trade winds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "subtropical high pressure.\n",
        "choicethree": "travelling depressions.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10720A )\n Annex 050-10720A\n Assuming a generalised zonal system of world climatic and wind circulation , zone \u201cx\u201d is an area of ;\n",
        "answer": "subtropical high pressure systems.\n",
        "choiceone": "the intertropical convergence zone ( ITCZ ).\n",
        "choicetwo": "travelling low pressure systems.\n",
        "choicethree": "NE trade winds.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10720A )\n Annex 050-10720A\n Assuming a generalised zonal system of world climatic and wind circulation , zone \u201cy\u201d is an area of ;\n",
        "answer": "travelling low pressure systems.\n",
        "choiceone": "subtropical high pressure systems.\n",
        "choicetwo": "SE trade winds.\n",
        "choicethree": "NE trade winds.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10720A )\n Annex 050-10720A\n Assuming a generalised zonal system of world wind circulation , the NE trade winds are applicable to zone ;\n",
        "answer": "u.\n",
        "choiceone": "w.\n",
        "choicetwo": "t.\n",
        "choicethree": "v.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10720A )\n Annex 050-10720A\n Assuming a generalised zonal system of world wind circulation , the SE trade winds are applicable to zone ;\n",
        "answer": "w.\n",
        "choiceone": "v.\n",
        "choicetwo": "u.\n",
        "choicethree": "t.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10720A )\n Annex 050-10720A\n Assuming a generalised zonal system of world wind circulation , the travelling low pressure systems are applicable to zone ;\n",
        "answer": "s and y.\n",
        "choiceone": "t and x.\n",
        "choicetwo": "t only.\n",
        "choicethree": "u and w.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4368A rev. 10.11.2002 )\n Annex 050-4368A\n Assuming a normal vertical temperature gradient , at what altitude will the freezing level above Tunis be found ?\n",
        "answer": "FL 100\n",
        "choiceone": "FL 180\n",
        "choicetwo": "FL 260\n",
        "choicethree": "FL 20\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Assuming that an initial \u201ctrigger\u201d force is present , the conditions most likely to result in the formation of thunderstorms are ;\n",
        "answer": "high relative humidity and instability throughout a deep layer.\n",
        "choiceone": "high surface temperature , low dew point and high dry adiabatic lapse rate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "rapid orographic cooling of cloud containing ice crystals.\n",
        "choicethree": "intense surface heating , anticyclonic pressure system and relatively high freezing level.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4298A rev. 20.01.2003 )\n Annex 050-4298A\n Assuming the usual direction of movement , to which position will the polar frontal wave have moved ?\n",
        "answer": "Position 3\n",
        "choiceone": "Position 4\n",
        "choicetwo": "Position 2\n",
        "choicethree": "Position 1\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-2064A )\n Annex 050-2064A\n Assuming the usual direction of movement , where will this polar frontal wave have moved to ( after a certain time ) ?\n",
        "answer": "Position 3\n",
        "choiceone": "Position 4\n",
        "choicetwo": "Position 1\n",
        "choicethree": "Position 2\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10875A )\n Annex 050-10875A\n At 40\u00b0N 20\u00b0W , the forecast wind at FL 390 is ;\n",
        "answer": "090\u00b0/45 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "060\u00b0/45 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "270\u00b0/45 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "070\u00b0/30 kt\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 4 )\n Image 4\n At 40\u00b0N 20\u00b0W , the forecast wind is ;\n",
        "answer": "270\u00b0/95 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "280\u00b0/70 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "320\u00b0/40 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "240\u00b0/90 kt\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "At a certain position , the temperature on the 300 hPa chart is \u201348\u00b0C , according to the Significant Weather Chart , the\ntropopause is at FL 330. What is the most likely temperature at FL 350 ?\n",
        "answer": "\u201354\u00b0C. 300 hPa seviyesi FL300\u2019d\u0131r. FL330\u2019da Tropopause ba\u015flad\u0131\u011f\u0131ndan bu seviyeden\n",
        "choiceone": "\u201358\u00b0C.\n",
        "choicetwo": "\u201350\u00b0C. itibaren s\u0131cakl\u0131k bir s\u00fcre sabitlenecektir. Bu nedenle 330 \u2013 300 = 3000 ft i\u00e7in ISA\n",
        "choicethree": "\u201356.5\u00b0C. de\u011fi\u015fimi hesaplayaca\u011f\u0131z. S\u0131cakl\u0131k her 1000 feet\u2019te 2\u00b0C azal\u0131rsa 3000 ft boyunca\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "At a cold front ;\n",
        "answer": "warm air is lifted as cooler air pushes under it.\n",
        "choiceone": "temperature rises owing to increased pressure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "fog will form from the interaction of cold and warm air.\n",
        "choicethree": "warm air is compressed as cold air rises over it.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "At a station at the surface the significant weather with a warm front will come ;\n",
        "answer": "mostly before the front passes.\n",
        "choiceone": "after the front has passed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "after the warm sector has passed.\n",
        "choicethree": "only at the same time as the front passes.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "At about what geographical latitude as average is assumed for the zone of prevailing westerlies ?\n",
        "answer": "50\u00b0N.\n",
        "choiceone": "80\u00b0N.\n",
        "choicetwo": "10\u00b0N.\n",
        "choicethree": "30\u00b0N.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "At approximately what flight level is the subtropical jet stream found ?\n",
        "answer": "FL 400\n",
        "choiceone": "FL 200\n",
        "choicetwo": "FL 300\n",
        "choicethree": "FL 500\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "At FL 180 , the air temperature is \u201335\u00b0C.The air density at this level is ;\n",
        "answer": "greater than the density of the ISA at FL 180.\n",
        "choiceone": "unable to be determined without knowing the QNH.\n",
        "choicetwo": "less than the density of the ISA at FL 180.\n",
        "choicethree": "equal to the density of the ISA at FL 180.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10936A )\n Annex 050-2513A\n At FL 300 between Geneva and Tunis , what mean wind would be most likely ?\n",
        "answer": "245/50\n",
        "choiceone": "225/25\n",
        "choicetwo": "265/25\n",
        "choicethree": "265/40\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-11931A )\n Annex 050-11931A\n At Lyon ( LFLY , N4545 E00500 ) , at 1200 UTC , the sky is overcast with Stratocumulus and Altostratus and it is raining.\nUsing the SWC in appendix , valid at 1200 UTC , we can estimate a weather improvement for Lyon at around ;\n",
        "answer": "2100 UTC.\n",
        "choiceone": "1215 UTC.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1330 UTC.\n",
        "choicethree": "0300 UTC the following day.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "At the same latitude the geostrophic wind is greater than the gradient wind around a low pressure system with equal pressure\ngradient because the ;\n",
        "answer": "centrifugal force opposes the pressure gradient.\n",
        "choiceone": "centrifugal force is added to the pressure gradient.\n",
        "choicetwo": "coriolis force is added to the pressure gradient.\n",
        "choicethree": "coriolis force opposes to the centrifugal force.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "At the same latitude the geostrophic wind is less than the gradient wind around an anticyclone with equal pressure gradient\nbecause the ;\n",
        "answer": "centrifugal force is added to the pressure gradient.\n",
        "choiceone": "centrifugal force opposes the pressure gradient.\n",
        "choicetwo": "coriolis effect opposes to the centrifugal force.\n",
        "choicethree": "effect of coriolis is added to friction.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "At the surface the lifetime of a typical microburst and the diameter of the area affected by damaging winds are in the order\nof ;\n",
        "answer": "1-5 minutes and 4 km.\n",
        "choiceone": "5-15 minutes and 8 km.\n",
        "choicetwo": "30-40 minutes and 4 km.\n",
        "choicethree": "5-10 minutes and 12 km.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "At the top of orographic waves , in mountainous regions , the cloud most likely to be encountered is ;\n",
        "answer": "altocumulus lenticularis.\n",
        "choiceone": "cumulus mediocris.\n",
        "choicetwo": "cirrus.\n",
        "choicethree": "cirrostratus.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-2513A )\n Annex 050-2513A\n At what approximate flight level is the tropopause over Frankfurt ?\n",
        "answer": "FL 330\n",
        "choiceone": "FL 240\n",
        "choicetwo": "FL 300\n",
        "choicethree": "FL 350\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what degree of icing can ICAO\u2019s \u201cNo change of course and altitude necessary\u201d recommendation be followed ?\n",
        "answer": "Light\n",
        "choiceone": "Moderate\n",
        "choicetwo": "Severe\n",
        "choicethree": "Extreme\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what degree of icing should ICAO\u2019s \u201cChange of course and/or altitude desirable\u201d recommendation be followed ?\n",
        "answer": "Moderate\n",
        "choiceone": "Extreme\n",
        "choicetwo": "Severe\n",
        "choicethree": "Light\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what degree of icing should ICAO\u2019s \u201cChange of course and/or altitude immediately\u201d instruction be followed ?\n",
        "answer": "Severe\n",
        "choiceone": "Moderate\n",
        "choicetwo": "Light\n",
        "choicethree": "Extreme\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-2511A )\n Annex 050-2511A\n At what flight level is the jet stream core that is situated over northern Scandinavia ?\n",
        "answer": "FL 280\n",
        "choiceone": "FL 300\n",
        "choicetwo": "FL 360\n",
        "choicethree": "FL 330\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what temperatures would you expect the heaviest ice accretion to occur in a CB ?\n",
        "answer": "Between -2\u00baC and -15 \u00baC\n",
        "choiceone": "Between -20\u00baC and -30 \u00baC\n",
        "choicetwo": "Close to the freezing level.\n",
        "choicethree": "Between -30\u00baC and -40 \u00baC\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what time of day , or night , is radiation fog most likely to occur ?\n",
        "answer": "Shortly after sunrise.\n",
        "choiceone": "At sunset.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Shortly after midnight.\n",
        "choicethree": "Late evening.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what time of the year , are the paths of north Atlantic lows moving from west to east generally at their most southerly\nposition ?\n",
        "answer": "Winter.\n",
        "choiceone": "Spring.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Autumn.\n",
        "choicethree": "Summer.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what time of the year , are tornadoes most likely to occur in North America ?\n",
        "answer": "Spring , summer.\n",
        "choiceone": "Winter.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Autumn , winter.\n",
        "choicethree": "Summer , autumn.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what time of the year , are typhoons most likely to occur over the southern islands of Japan ?\n",
        "answer": "July to November.\n",
        "choiceone": "January to May.\n",
        "choicetwo": "September to January.\n",
        "choicethree": "May to July.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-2432A )\n Annex 050-2432A\n At which airport , is the following weather development taking place ?\n TAF 060600Z 060716 25006KT 8000 BKN240 BECMG 0710 OVC200 BECMG 1013 23010KT 8000 OVC100 BECMG\n 1316 23014KT 6000 RA SCT030 OVC050 =\n",
        "answer": "EDDL\n",
        "choiceone": "LEMD\n",
        "choicetwo": "LFPO\n",
        "choicethree": "LOWW\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4362A )\n Annex 050-4362A\n At which airport is the following weather development taking place ?\n TAF 231200Z 231322 24014G32KT 4000 +TSRA SCT005 BKN015 BKN020CB BECMG 1416 29012KT 9999\n BKN030TCU SCT100 TEMPO 1619 8000 SHRA BKN025TCU BECMG 1922 27012KT 9999 SCT030 OVC220 =\n",
        "answer": "EINN\n",
        "choiceone": "EKCH\n",
        "choicetwo": "LSZH\n",
        "choicethree": "ESSA\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "At which altitude , at temperate latitudes , may hail be expected in connection with a CB ?\n",
        "answer": "From the ground up to a maximum of FL 450.\n",
        "choiceone": "From the base of the clouds up to about FL 200.\n",
        "choicetwo": "From the ground up to about FL 200.\n",
        "choicethree": "From the ground up to about FL 100.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "At which height and at what time of the year can an aircraft be affected by the equatorial jet stream ?\n",
        "answer": "FL 500 from June to August.\n",
        "choiceone": "FL 400 during the winter in the northern hemisphere.\n",
        "choicetwo": "FL 400 during the winter in the southern hemisphere.\n",
        "choicethree": "FL 500 from November to February.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-2512A )\n Annex 050-2512A\n At which position is the development of thunderstorms , and what is the maximum height of the CB clouds at 00 UTC ?\n",
        "answer": "Position B , FL 270.\n",
        "choiceone": "Position A , FL 200.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Position D , FL 290.\n",
        "choicethree": "Position C , FL 200.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "At which pressure and temperature conditions may you safely assume that the minimum usable flight level at least lies at the\nsame height , as the minimum safe altitude ?\n",
        "answer": "At a temperature greater than or equal to that of the ISA and where the QNH is greater than or equal to\n 1013.25 hPa.\n",
        "choiceone": "In a very cold area with a QNH of 1015 hPa.\n",
        "choicetwo": "In a cold low pressure region.\n",
        "choicethree": "At a temperature less than or equal to that of the ISA and where the QNH is less than 1013.25 hPa.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "At which time , if any , are polar front jet streams over the South Pacific usually strongest ?\n",
        "answer": "July\n",
        "choiceone": "There is no annual variation\n",
        "choicetwo": "October\n",
        "choicethree": "January\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "ATIS information contains ;\n",
        "answer": "meteorological and operational information.\n",
        "choiceone": "operational information and if necessary meteorological information.\n",
        "choicetwo": "only operational information.\n",
        "choicethree": "only meteorological information.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Atmospheric soundings give the following temperature profile ;\n 3000 ft +15\u00b0C\n 6000 ft +8\u00b0C\n 10000 ft +1\u00b0C\n 14000 ft -6\u00b0C\n 18000 ft -14\u00b0C\n 24000 ft -26\u00b0C\n At which of the following flight levels is the risk for aircraft icing , in cloud , greatest ?\n",
        "answer": "FL 150\n",
        "choiceone": "FL 80\n",
        "choicetwo": "FL 220\n",
        "choicethree": "FL 180\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Before landing , an altimeter set to QFE indicates ;\n",
        "answer": "in standard atmosphere , the height of the aircraft above the official airport elevation.\n",
        "choiceone": "the flight level.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the height of the aircraft\u2019s wheels above the runway.\n",
        "choicethree": "the aircraft\u2019s altitude above the mean sea level.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Below a low level inversion visibility is often ;\n",
        "answer": "moderate or poor because there is no vertical exchange.\n",
        "choiceone": "very good at night.\n",
        "choicetwo": "very good in the early morning.\n",
        "choicethree": "moderate or poor due to heavy snow showers.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Below is the forecast for the destination of a flight whose ETA is 2030 UTC ;\n TAF YUDO 120600Z 121206 17010KT 3000 SCT005 BECMG 1820 VRB03KT BCFG SKC BECMG 2022 0300 FG\n VV002 =\n What can be said about the destination airport at 2030 UTC if CAT II ILS minima 350 m RVR , 100 ft Decision Height are\nbeing considered ?\n",
        "answer": "Has to be considered as closed.\n",
        "choiceone": "Still open until 2200 UTC because the weather change is not completed before 2200 UTC.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Open the whole night because 300 m of visibility corresponds o at least 900 m RVR.\n",
        "choicethree": "Still open because the decrease of the visibility below the CAT II minima will be a little bit later than 2030\n UTC.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Between mean sea level and a height of 20 km , the lowest temperature in the ICAO Standard Atmosphere ( ISA ) is ;\n",
        "answer": "\u201356.5\u00b0C\n",
        "choiceone": "\u2013273\u00b0C\n",
        "choicetwo": "\u201344.7\u00b0C\n",
        "choicethree": "\u2013100\u00b0C\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Between which latitudes are you most likely to find the region of travelling low pressure systems during summer ?\n",
        "answer": "45\u00b0 - 70\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "15\u00b0 - 25\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "10\u00b0 - 15\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "25\u00b0 - 45\u00b0\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Between which latitudes are you most likely to find the subtropical high-pressure belt ?\n",
        "answer": "25\u00b0 - 35\u00b0.\n",
        "choiceone": "55\u00b0 - 75\u00b0.\n",
        "choicetwo": "35\u00b0 - 55\u00b0.\n",
        "choicethree": "10\u00b0 - 15\u00b0.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10872A )\n Annex 050-10872A\n By the time the front \u201cZ\u201d has passed point \u201cQ\u201d the surface wind will have ;\n",
        "answer": "veered and increased.\n",
        "choiceone": "veered and decreased.\n",
        "choicetwo": "backed and decreased.\n",
        "choicethree": "backed and increased.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "By volume , what percentage of the air in the lower troposphere consists of water vapour ?\n",
        "answer": "0-5 %\n",
        "choiceone": "10-15 %\n",
        "choicetwo": "5-10 %\n",
        "choicethree": "20-30 %\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "By volume , which of the following elements makes up the largest part of the atmosphere ?\n",
        "answer": "Nitrogen.\n",
        "choiceone": "Oxygen.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Noble gases.\n",
        "choicethree": "Hydrogen.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Central Europe is situated in the zone of ;\n",
        "answer": "mid-latitude climate.\n",
        "choiceone": "subarctic climate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "dry climate.\n",
        "choicethree": "snow climate.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Clear ice forms as a result of ;\n",
        "answer": "supercooled water droplets spreading during the freezing process.\n",
        "choiceone": "supercooled droplets freezing on impact.\n",
        "choicetwo": "water vapour freezing to the aircraft.\n",
        "choicethree": "ice pellets splattering on the aircraft.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Clear ice forms on an aircraft by the freezing of ;\n",
        "answer": "large supercooled water drops.\n",
        "choiceone": "small supercooled water drops.\n",
        "choicetwo": "snow.\n",
        "choicethree": "water vapour.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Clear ice is dangerous because it ;\n",
        "answer": "is heavy and is difficult to remove from the aircraft surfaces.\n",
        "choiceone": "spreads out and contains many air particles.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is not translucent and forms at the leading edges.\n",
        "choicethree": "is translucent and only forms at the leading edges.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Clear ice is formed when supercooled droplets are ;\n",
        "answer": "large and at a temperature just below freezing.\n",
        "choiceone": "of any size at temperatures below -35\u00b0C.\n",
        "choicetwo": "small and freeze rapidly.\n",
        "choicethree": "small and at a temperature just below freezing.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Clouds , classified as being low level are considered to have bases from ;\n",
        "answer": "the surface to 6500 ft.\n",
        "choiceone": "1000 to 2000 ft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "500 to 1000 ft.\n",
        "choicethree": "100 to 200 ft.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Clouds , fog or dew will always be formed when ;\n",
        "answer": "water vapour condenses.\n",
        "choiceone": "temperature and dew point are nearly equal.\n",
        "choicetwo": "water vapour is present.\n",
        "choicethree": "relative humidity reaches 98%.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Clouds in patches , sheets or grey or whitish layers made up of elements resembling large pebbles or rollers , together or not ,\nand always clear of the ground are ;\n",
        "answer": "Stratocumulus.\n",
        "choiceone": "Altostratus.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Stratus.\n",
        "choicethree": "Nimbostratus.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Clouds will mainly consist of supercooled water droplets when the temperature is ;\n",
        "answer": "between 0\u00baC and -15\u00baC.\n",
        "choiceone": "between -30\u00baC and -40\u00baC.\n",
        "choicetwo": "between -5\u00baC and -30\u00baC.\n",
        "choicethree": "below -40\u00baC.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Cold air pools ;\n",
        "answer": "are most evident in the temperature and wind fields of the upper levels.\n",
        "choiceone": "can easily be recognized on synoptic surface charts.\n",
        "choicetwo": "only occur in winter.\n",
        "choicethree": "only occur at mid-latitudes.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Compare the following TAF and VOLMET reports for Nice ;\n TAF 240600Z 240716 VRB02KT CAVOK =\n 0920Z 13012KT 8000 SCT040CB BKN100 20/18 Q1015 TEMPO TS =\n What can be concluded from the differences between the two reports ?\n",
        "answer": "That the weather at Nice is clearly more volatile than the TAF could have predicted earlier in the morning.\n",
        "choiceone": "That the weather in Nice after 0920 is also likely to be as predicted in the TAF.\n",
        "choicetwo": "That the VOLMET speaker has got his locations mixed up , because there is no way the latest VOLMET\n report could be so different from the TAF.\n",
        "choicethree": "That the weather conditions at 0920 were actually predicted in the TAF.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider a parcel of air being forced upwards in the atmosphere. The lapse rate of the surrounding air is less than the\nsaturated adiabatic lapse rate. After the initial force is no longer effective , the parcel of air ;\n",
        "answer": "will tend to descend to its original altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "will become conditionally unstable.\n",
        "choicetwo": "will tend to remain at the new altitude.\n",
        "choicethree": "will tend to ascend further\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider a parcel of air which is moved upwards in the surrounding air by an external force. Which one of the following\nsituations describes instability ?\n",
        "answer": "The parcel tends to gain altitude after being released.\n",
        "choiceone": "The parcel tends to return to its original altitude when it is released.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The parcel tends to descend when it is released. It will move to , and maintain an altitude below its original\n altitude.\n",
        "choicethree": "The parcel tends to maintain its new altitude after being released.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10724A )\n Annex 050-10724A\n Considering Melbourne ( C ) in July , the weather is predominantly influenced by the zone of ;\n",
        "answer": "subtropical high pressure , with the occasional passage of fronts originating in the adjacent zone of westerly\n waves.\n",
        "choiceone": "Antarctic high pressure due to the absence of any protective land mass between south Australia and\n Antarctica.\n",
        "choicetwo": "disturbed temperate low pressure , bringing an almost continuous succession of fronts resulting in strong\n winds , low cloud and rain.\n",
        "choicethree": "equatorial low pressure due to the proximity of the intertropical convergence zone over central Australia.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10795A )\n Annex 050-10795A\n Considering that portion of the route indicated from 30\u00b0E to 50\u00b0E , the upper winds in January above FL 300 are most likely\nto be ;\n",
        "answer": "a subtropical westerly jet stream , maximum speed exceeding 90 kt.\n",
        "choiceone": "light easterlies.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a westerly polar front jet stream , maximum speed exceeding 90 kt.\n",
        "choicethree": "variable in direction and less than 30 kt.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Considering the North Atlantic area north of 60\u00b0N during winter , the mean height of the tropopause is approximately ;\n",
        "answer": "29 000 ft.\n",
        "choiceone": "56 000 ft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "37 000 ft.\n",
        "choicethree": "20 000 ft.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Considering the North Atlantic at latitude 50\u00b0N during winter , the mean height of the tropopause is approximately ;\n",
        "answer": "31 000 ft.\n",
        "choiceone": "43 000 ft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "54 000 ft.\n",
        "choicethree": "23 000 ft.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Considering the North Atlantic between 30\u00b0N and 65\u00b0N , the mean position of the polar front during winter extends from ;\n",
        "answer": "Florida to SW England.\n",
        "choiceone": "Newfoundland to Iceland.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Iceland to Norway.\n",
        "choicethree": "NE Canada to Portugal.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Considering the North Atlantic region between 30\u00b0N and 65\u00b0N and the adjacent land areas during mid-summer , the\npredominant pressure systems are ;\n",
        "answer": "Azores high and weak low over NE Canada.\n",
        "choiceone": "Azores low and Icelandic high.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Scandinavian high and Azores high.\n",
        "choicethree": "weak low over NE Canada and Scandinavian high.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Considering the North Atlantic region between 30\u00b0N and 65\u00b0N , the mean position of the polar front during summer extends\nfrom ;\n",
        "answer": "Newfoundland to N Scotland.\n",
        "choiceone": "NE Canada to Iceland.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Florida to SW England.\n",
        "choicethree": "Greenland to Spain.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Considering the North Atlantic region between 30\u00b0N and 65\u00b0N together with the adjacent land areas during winter , the\nnormal disposition of the main anticyclones at the surface is ;\n",
        "answer": "Azores , Siberia.\n",
        "choiceone": "Siberia , Iceland , Canaries.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Greenland , Iberian peninsula.\n",
        "choicethree": "NE Canada , Iceland.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 8 )\n Image 8\n Considering the North Atlantic route from the Azores to Bermuda , the mean height of the tropical tropopause during\nsummer is approximately ;\n",
        "answer": "51 000 ft.\n",
        "choiceone": "39 000 ft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "33 000 ft.\n",
        "choicethree": "60 000 ft.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Considering the region between 20\u00b0N and 70\u00b0N , the normal position of the main anticyclones at the surface during winter\nis ;\n",
        "answer": "Azores , Siberia , Canada.\n",
        "choiceone": "NE Canada , Iceland , Bermuda.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Siberia , Iceland , Canaries.\n",
        "choicethree": "Greenland , Iberian peninsula , Tibet.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10891A )\n Annex 050-10891A\n Considering the route between Valencia and Charleston at FL 340 , the forecast mean temperature is ;\n",
        "answer": "-50\u00b0C\n",
        "choiceone": "-40\u00b0C\n",
        "choicetwo": "-45\u00b0C\n",
        "choicethree": "-55\u00b0C\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 7 )\n Image 7\n Considering the route indicated from Recife to Dakar the mean height of the tropopause during January is approximately ;\n",
        "answer": "56 000 ft.\n",
        "choiceone": "43 000 ft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "36 000 ft.\n",
        "choicethree": "29 000 ft.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 6 )\n Image 6\n Considering the sector from 10\u00b0N to Nairobi of the route indicated , during January the upper winds at the 300 hPa level are\nmost likely to be ;\n",
        "answer": "light easterlies.\n",
        "choiceone": "westerlies at 40 kt.\n",
        "choicetwo": "easterly jet streams in excess of 70 kt.\n",
        "choicethree": "westerlies in excess of 60 kt.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 6 )\n Image 6\n Considering the sector Rome to 25\u00b0N on the route indicated , what mean upper winds may be expected at FL 300 during\nwinter ?\n",
        "answer": "Weterly jet streams in excess of 70 kt.\n",
        "choiceone": "Variable easterlies.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Easterlies at 40 kt.\n",
        "choicethree": "Light westerlies.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4314A rev. 20.01.2003 )\n Annex 050-4314A\n Continuous freezing rain is observed at an airfield. Which of the four diagrams is most likely to reflect temperatures above\nthe airfield concerned ?\n",
        "answer": "Diagram 4\n",
        "choiceone": "Diagram 3\n",
        "choicetwo": "Diagram 2\n",
        "choicethree": "Diagram 1\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Continuous updraughts occur in a thunderstorm during the ;\n",
        "answer": "initial stage.\n",
        "choiceone": "mature stage.\n",
        "choicetwo": "dissipating stage.\n",
        "choicethree": "period in which precipitation is falling.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Convective activity over land in mid-latitudes is greatest in ;\n",
        "answer": "summer in the afternoon.\n",
        "choiceone": "winter during the night and early morning.\n",
        "choicetwo": "summer during the night and early morning.\n",
        "choicethree": "winter in the afternoon.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Convective clouds are formed ;\n",
        "answer": "in unstable atmosphere.\n",
        "choiceone": "in summer during the day only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "in mid-latitudes only.\n",
        "choicethree": "in stable atmosphere.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Convective weather phenomena include ;\n",
        "answer": "thunderstorms , hail , tornadoes , wind gusts , heavy showers , lightning strikes.\n",
        "choiceone": "thunderstorms , tornadoes , hail , haze , wind gusts , advection fog.\n",
        "choicetwo": "hail , lightning strikes , wind lulls , squalls , stratocumulus , low level wind maximum.\n",
        "choicethree": "heavy showers , lightning strikes , hail , mist , squalls , light rain over a large area.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Cumulus clouds are an indication for ;\n",
        "answer": "up and downdrafts.\n",
        "choiceone": "the approach of a warm front.\n",
        "choicetwo": "stability.\n",
        "choicethree": "the approach of a cold front.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Depressions associated with developing frontal waves can be assumed to move in the direction of the 3000 feet wind ;\n",
        "answer": "in the warm sector.\n",
        "choiceone": "ahead of the warm front.\n",
        "choicetwo": "behind the cold front.\n",
        "choicethree": "at the apex of the wave.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Dew point is defined as ;\n",
        "answer": "the temperature to which moist air must be cooled to become saturated at a given pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "the lowest temperature to which air must be cooled in order to reduce the relative humidity.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the temperature below which the change of state in a given volume of air will result in the absorption of\n latent heat.\n",
        "choicethree": "the lowest temperature at which evaporation will occur for a given pressure.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Divergence in the upper air that is greater than the convergence in the friction layer results , near the surface , in ;\n",
        "answer": "falling pressure and likely formation of clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "falling pressure and likely dissipation of clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "rising pressure and likely formation of clouds.\n",
        "choicethree": "rising pressure and likely dissipation of clouds.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Does the following report make sense ?\n METAR LSZH 182320Z VRB02KT 5000 MIFG 02/02 Q1015 NOSIG =\n",
        "answer": "The report is possible , because shallow fog is defined as a thin layer of fog below eye level.\n",
        "choiceone": "The report is not possible , because , with a temperature of 2\u00b0C and a dew point of 2\u00b0C there must be uniform\n fog.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The report is nonsense , because it is impossible to observe a visibility of 5 km if shallow fog is reported.\n",
        "choicethree": "The report would never be seen , because shallow fog is not reported when the visibility is more than 2 km.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a cross-country flight at FL 50 , you observe the following sequence of clouds ;\n Nimbostratus , Altostratus , Cirrostratus , Cirrus.\n Which of the following are you most likely to encounter ?\n",
        "answer": "Decreasing temperatures.\n",
        "choiceone": "A strong downdraught.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Increasing temperatures.\n",
        "choicethree": "Strong , gusty winds.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a descent from 2000 ft above the surface to the surface ( no frontal passage , northern hemisphere ) , the wind\nnormally ;\n",
        "answer": "backs and decreases.\n",
        "choiceone": "backs and increases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "veers and decreases.\n",
        "choicethree": "veers and increases.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a flight at FL100 from Marseille ( QNH 1012 hPa ) to Palma de Mallorca ( QNH 1015 hPa ) , an aircraft remains at a\nconstant true altitude. The reason for this is that ;\n",
        "answer": "the air at Marseille is warmer than that at Palma de Mallorca.\n",
        "choiceone": "one of the two QNH values may be incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the altimeters are erroneous , and need to be tested.\n",
        "choicethree": "the air at Marseille is colder than that at Palma de Mallorca.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a flight over the sea at FL 100 from Marseille ( QNH 1012 hPa ) to Palma de Mallorca ( QNH 1012 hPa ) , the true\naltitude is constantly increasing. What action , if any , should be taken ?\n",
        "answer": "None , the reason for the change is that the air around Palma is warmer than the air around Marseille.\n",
        "choiceone": "Have your altimeter checked , because its readings are obviously wrong.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Compensate by heading further to the left.\n",
        "choicethree": "Recheck the QNH because one of the QNH values must be wrong.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a flight over the sea at FL 100 from Marseille ( QNH 1016 hPa ) to Palma de Mallorca ( QNH 1016 hPa ) , the true\naltitude is constantly decreasing. What is the probable reason for this ?\n",
        "answer": "The air at Marseille is warmer than that at Palma de Mallorca.\n",
        "choiceone": "The air at Palma de Mallorca is warmer than that at Marseille.\n",
        "choicetwo": "One of the QNH values must be wrong.\n",
        "choicethree": "The altimeter is faulty.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a flight over the sea at FL 135 , the true altitude is 13.500 feet , local QNH is 1019 hPa. What information , if any ,\ncan be gained about the air mass in which the aircraft is flying ?\n",
        "answer": "It is colder than ISA.\n",
        "choiceone": "Its average temperature is the same as ISA.\n",
        "choicetwo": "There is insufficient information to make any assumption.\n",
        "choicethree": "It is warmer than ISA.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During an adiabatic process heat is ;\n",
        "answer": "neither added nor lost.\n",
        "choiceone": "added but the result is an overall loss.\n",
        "choicetwo": "added.\n",
        "choicethree": "lost.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During an ILS approach on RWY 33 , a northwesterly wind is blowing parallel to the runway. Its speed is decreasing rapidly\nwith height while its change in direction is negligible. What has the pilot to be aware of with respect to wind shear and glide path ( no\nautopilot engaged ) ?\n",
        "answer": "Without the pilot\u2019s intervention , the aircraft is likely to fly above the designated glide path with increasing\n deviation from it.\n",
        "choiceone": "Without the pilot\u2019s intervention , the aircraft is likely to fly below the designated glide path with decreasing\n deviation from it.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A deviation from the glide path will not have to be considered since there is no significant wind shear to be\n expected.\n",
        "choicethree": "Without the pilot\u2019s intervention , the aircraft is likely to fly below the designated glide path with increasing\n deviation from it.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During an ILS approach on RWY 33 , a northwesterly wind is blowing parallel to the runway. Its speed is increasing rapidly\nwith height while its change in direction is negligible. What has the pilot to be aware of with respect to wind shear and glide path ( no\nautopilot engaged ) ?\n",
        "answer": "Without the pilot\u2019s intervention , the aircraft is likely to fly below the designated glide path with increasing\n deviation from it.\n",
        "choiceone": "A deviation from the glide path will not have to be considered since there is no significant wind shear to be\n expected.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Without the pilot\u2019s intervention , the aircraft is likely to fly above the designated glide path with increasing\n deviation from it.\n",
        "choicethree": "Without the pilot\u2019s intervention , the aircraft is likely to fly above the designated glide path with decreasing\n deviation from it.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During flight in clouds , which of the following means is the best one to identify the position of embedded CBs ?\n",
        "answer": "Weather radar.\n",
        "choiceone": "Significant weather chart.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The pilot requests the position of the CBs from the ATC controller.\n",
        "choicethree": "Aircraft observation.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During flight the headwind increases suddenly due to wind shear. What initial effect does that have on true airspeed ?\n",
        "answer": "There will be a sudden temporary increase in true air speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "None , since wind only affects ground speed and drift.\n",
        "choicetwo": "There will only be a gradual increase in true airspeed until equilibrium is established again.\n",
        "choicethree": "There will be a sudden temporary decrease in true air speed.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During July flights from Bangkok ( 13\u00b0N - 100\u00b0E ) to Karachi ( 25\u00b0N - 67\u00b0E ) experience an average tailwind component of\n22 kt. In January the same flights also operating at FL 370 , have an average headwind of 50 kt.What is the reason for this difference ?\n",
        "answer": "The wind components correspond to the seasonal change of the regional wind system.\n",
        "choiceone": "The flights happen to be in the area of the polar front jet stream.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The flights in January encountered , by chance , very unusual , adverse wind conditions.\n",
        "choicethree": "The flights during the summer encountered , by chance , very unusual , favourable conditions.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During periods of cloudless weather over land in the northern hemisphere the ;\n",
        "answer": "surface wind speed tends to be highest during the mid afternoon.\n",
        "choiceone": "angle between isobars and surface wind direction tends to be greatest in the mid afternoon.\n",
        "choicetwo": "surface wind speed tends to be highest at night.\n",
        "choicethree": "wind tends to back from early morning until early afternoon.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During periods of prolonged clear skies associated with anticyclonic conditions , the ;\n",
        "answer": "surface wind speed tends to be highest during the early afternoon\n",
        "choiceone": "surface wind speed tends to be highest at night\n",
        "choicetwo": "wind tends to back from early morning until early afternoon\n",
        "choicethree": "angle between isobars and surface wind direction tends to be greatest in the early afternoon\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During periods of undisturbed radiation weather , overland , the ;\n",
        "answer": "surface wind speed tends to be highest during the mid afternoon.\n",
        "choiceone": "wind tends to back from early morning until early afternoon.\n",
        "choicetwo": "surface wind speed tends to be highest at night.\n",
        "choicethree": "angle between isobars and surface wind direction tends to be greatest in the mid afternoon.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During summer , a weak pressure gradient covers a coastal airfield in Eastern England resulting in mainly clear skies. The\nsurface wind at dawn was calm. If the alignment of the coastline in the vicinity of the airfield is predominantly north/south , the\nsurface wind is likely to become ;\n",
        "answer": "easterly to south-easterly and increase in velocity by afternoon.\n",
        "choiceone": "easterly and then westerly by afternoon.\n",
        "choicetwo": "westerly and increase in velocity by afternoon.\n",
        "choicethree": "westerly and then southerly by evening.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During summer an anticyclone covers the British Isles giving mainly clear skies. At 06:00 UTC a south coast airfield in\nSouthern England reports a surface wind of 350/06. The coastline at the airfield perimeter is aligned in an east/west direction. During\nthe next twelve hours the surface wind is likely to ;\n",
        "answer": "become southerly to south-westerly and increase in velocity by afternoon.\n",
        "choiceone": "increase from the north by mid-morning becoming calm towards evening.\n",
        "choicetwo": "veer to easterly before becoming calm by the afternoon.\n",
        "choicethree": "back to NW and strengthen by mid-afternoon.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10763A )\n CB\n Annex 050-10763A\n During summer , the cloud type most applicable to square 2A is ;\n",
        "answer": "CB.\n",
        "choiceone": "CS.\n",
        "choicetwo": "AC.\n",
        "choicethree": "ST.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the approach of Mumbai ( 19\u00b0N - 73\u00b0E ) on the west coast of India , you are listening to the ATIS on 15 July at 0700\nLT. Which of the following reports is most likely ?\n",
        "answer": "25014KT 4500 SHRA SCT015 BKN025CB 25/24 Q1006 NOSIG =\n",
        "choiceone": "30012KT 9999 SCT030 SCT200 20/16 Q1025 BECMG 4000 BR =\n",
        "choicetwo": "02005KT CAVOK 24/09 Q1030 NOSIG =\n",
        "choicethree": "05013KT 3500 MIFG SCT003 BKN005 19/14 Q1012 BECMG 8000 =\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the climb after take-off , the altimeter setting is adjusted at the transition altitude. If the local QNH is 966 hPa , what\nwill happen to the altimeter reading during the resetting procedure ?\n",
        "answer": "It will increase.\n",
        "choiceone": "It will remain the same.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It is not possible to give a definitive answer.\n",
        "choicethree": "It will decrease.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the climb after take-off , the altimeter setting is adjusted at the transition altitude. If the local QNH is 1023 hPa , what\nwill happen to the altimeter reading during the resetting procedure ?\n",
        "answer": "It will decrease.\n",
        "choiceone": "It will increase.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It will remain the same.\n",
        "choicethree": "It is not possible to give a definitive answer.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the formation of rime ice in flight , water droplets freeze ;\n",
        "answer": "rapidly and do not spread out.\n",
        "choiceone": "slowly and do not spread out.\n",
        "choicetwo": "slowly and spread out.\n",
        "choicethree": "rapidly and spread out.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the late afternoon an air temperature of +12\u00b0C and a dew point of +5\u00b0C were measured. What temperature change\nmust at least occur during the night in order to induce saturation ?\n",
        "answer": "It must decrease to +5\u00b0C.\n",
        "choiceone": "It must decrease by 5\u00b0C.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It must decrease to +6\u00b0C.\n",
        "choicethree": "It must decrease to +7\u00b0C.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the life cycle of a thunderstorm , which stage is characterized predominantly by downdrafts ?\n",
        "answer": "Dissipating stage.\n",
        "choiceone": "Mature stage.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Tornado stage.\n",
        "choicethree": "Initial stage.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the passage of a front in the northern hemisphere the wind veers. This statement is ;\n",
        "answer": "true.\n",
        "choiceone": "not true.\n",
        "choicetwo": "only true for the passage of a cold front.\n",
        "choicethree": "only true for the passage of a warm front.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the preparation for approach to Zurich airport ( 1416 ft/AMSL ) a pilot hears the following message on the ATIS ;\n\u201cInversion warning. Inversion of 12\u00b0C between 1900 ft and 2300 ft altitude.\u201d This message indicates that the pilot should be\nprepared ;\n",
        "answer": "for wind shear just above the inversion.\n",
        "choiceone": "for fog below the inversion.\n",
        "choicetwo": "for freezing precipitation below the inversion.\n",
        "choicethree": "that the performance of the engine will be reduced from inversion level down to ground.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the winter an aircraft is parked overnight prior to an early morning departure. The crew notice a slight glistening on\ntop of the wings. The wings look clear though. The pilot should , under these conditions , appreciate that ;\n",
        "answer": "the aircraft should be sprayed with de-icing with fluid of the correct type.\n",
        "choiceone": "nothing particular will happen during take-off.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the aircraft will take off within the normal runway length.\n",
        "choicethree": "there is no risk of ice accretion.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the winter months in mid-latitudes in the northern hemisphere , the polar front jet stream moves toward the ;\n",
        "answer": "south and speed increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "north and speed decreases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "north and speed increases.\n",
        "choicethree": "south and speed decreases.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10842A )\n Annex 050-10842A\n During the winter , the air mass type advected from a direction indicated by arrow number 1 is designated ;\n",
        "answer": "maritime arctic.\n",
        "choiceone": "continental polar.\n",
        "choicetwo": "continental arctic.\n",
        "choicethree": "maritime polar.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During which seasons are hurricanes most likely to appear in the northern hemisphere ?\n",
        "answer": "Summer and Autumn.\n",
        "choiceone": "All seasons.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Winter.\n",
        "choicethree": "Winter and Spring.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During which stage of thunderstorm development are rotor winds characterized by roll clouds most likely to occur ?\n",
        "answer": "Mature stage.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cumulus stage and mature stage.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cumulus stage.\n",
        "choicethree": "Dissipating stage.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4297A )\n Annex 050-4297A\n Examining the pictures , on which one of the tracks ( dashed lines ) is this crosssection to be expected ?\n",
        "answer": "Track B-D\n",
        "choiceone": "Track A-E\n",
        "choicetwo": "Track A-D\n",
        "choicethree": "Track B-C\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Extensive cloud and precipitation is often associated with a non frontal thermal depression because of ;\n",
        "answer": "surface convergence and upper level divergence causing widespread ascent of air in the depression.\n",
        "choiceone": "surface divergence and upper level convergence causing widespread descent of air in the depression.\n",
        "choicetwo": "surface divergence and upper level convergence causing widespread ascent of air in the depression.\n",
        "choicethree": "surface convergence and upper level divergence causing widespread descent of air in the depression.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Fair weather cumulus often is an indication of ;\n",
        "answer": "turbulence at and below the cloud level.\n",
        "choiceone": "a high risk of thunderstorms.\n",
        "choicetwo": "smooth flying conditions below the cloud level.\n",
        "choicethree": "poor visibility at surface.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Fallstreaks or virga are ;\n",
        "answer": "water or ice particles falling out of a cloud that evaporate before reaching the ground.\n",
        "choiceone": "gusts associated with a well developed Bora.\n",
        "choicetwo": "strong downdraughts in the polar jet stream, associated with jet streaks.\n",
        "choicethree": "strong katabatic winds in mountainous areas and accompanied by heavy precipitation.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Flight from Bordeaux to Amsterdam , ETA 2100 UTC. At ETA Amsterdam what surface wind is forecast ?\n TAF EHAM 281500Z 281601 14010KT 6000 -RA SCT025 BECMG 1618 12015G25KT SCT008 BKN013 TEMPO 1823\n 3000 RA BKN005 OVC010 BECMG 2301 25020KT 8000 NSW BKN020 =\n",
        "answer": "120\u00b0 / 15 kt gusts 25 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "140\u00b0 / 10 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "300\u00b0 / 15 kt maximum wind 25 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "250\u00b0 / 20 kt\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Flight from Bordeaux to Amsterdam , ETA 2100 UTC. What is the minimum visibility forecast for ETA Amsterdam ?\n TAF EHAM 281500Z 281601 14010KT 6000 -RA SCT025 BECMG 1618 12015G25KT SCT008 BKN013 TEMPO 1823\n 3000 RA BKN005 OVC010 BECMG 2301 25020KT 8000 NSW BKN020 =\n",
        "answer": "3 km.\n",
        "choiceone": "6 km.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 km.\n",
        "choicethree": "5 NM.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Flight from Bordeaux to Amsterdam , ETA 2100 UTC. What lowest cloud base is forecast for arrival at Amsterdam ?\n TAF EHAM 281500Z 281601 14010KT 6000 -RA SCT025 BECMG 1618 12015G25KT SCT008 BKN013 TEMPO 1823\n 3000 RA BKN005 OVC010 BECMG 2301 25020KT 8000 NSW BKN020 =\n",
        "answer": "500 ft.\n",
        "choiceone": "500 m.\n",
        "choicetwo": "800 ft.\n",
        "choicethree": "250 ft.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10916A )\n Annex 050-10916A\n Flight from Lisbon ( LPPT ) to Kingston ( MKJP ). At 40\u00b0N 20\u00b0W , the temperature deviation from ISA at FL 390 is ;\n",
        "answer": "0\u00b0C.\n",
        "choiceone": "+6\u00b0C.\n",
        "choicetwo": "-2\u00b0C.\n",
        "choicethree": "+2\u00b0C.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10918A )\n Annex 050-10918A\n Flight from Lisbon ( LPPT ) to Kingston ( MKJP ). Considering the route segment between 60\u00b0W and 70\u00b0W , at FL 390 the\nforecast mean temperature is ;\n",
        "answer": "-55\u00b0C.\n",
        "choiceone": "-58\u00b0C.\n",
        "choicetwo": "-61\u00b0C.\n",
        "choicethree": "-52\u00b0C.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Flight Lisbon to Bordeaux , ETA 1800 UTC. At ETA Bordeaux what is the lowest quoted visibility forecast ?\n TAF LFBD 281400Z 281524 26015KT 9999 SHRA BKN020 TEMPO 1620 26020G30KT 8000 +SHRA BKN015CB\n PROB30 TSRA =\n",
        "answer": "8 km.\n",
        "choiceone": "10 NM.\n",
        "choicetwo": "8 NM.\n",
        "choicethree": "10 or more km.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Flight Lisbon to Bordeaux , ETA 1800 UTC. What type of precipitation is forecast on the approach to Bordeaux ?\n TAF LFBD 281400Z 281524 26015KT 9999 SHRA BKN020 TEMPO 1620 26020G30KT 8000 +SHRA BKN015CB\n PROB30 TSRA =\n",
        "answer": "Heavy rain showers.\n",
        "choiceone": "Light drizzle and fog.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Continuous moderate rain.\n",
        "choicethree": "Moderate snow showers.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-2550A )\n Annex 050-2550A\n Flight Munich to London. What is the direction and maximum speed of the jet stream affecting the route between Munich\nand London ?\n",
        "answer": "220\u00b0 / 120 kt.\n",
        "choiceone": "050\u00b0 / 120 km/h.\n",
        "choicetwo": "050\u00b0 / 120 kt.\n",
        "choicethree": "230\u00b0 / 120 m/sec.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-2554A )\n Annex 050-2554A\n Flight Shannon to London. What amount and type of cloud is forecast for the eastern sector of the route between Shannon\nand London at FL 220 ?\n",
        "answer": "Individual cumulonimbus.\n",
        "choiceone": "Overcast nimbo layered cumulonimbus.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Scattered towering cumulus.\n",
        "choicethree": "Scattered castellanus.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Flight visibility from the cockpit during approach in a tropical downpour can decrease to minimal ;\n",
        "answer": "tens of metres.\n",
        "choiceone": "about 500 metres.\n",
        "choicetwo": "about 1000 metres.\n",
        "choicethree": "about 200 metres.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-2505A )\n Annex 050-2505A\n Flight Zurich to Rome , ETD 1600 UTC , ETA 1800 UTC. At what flight level would you first expect to encounter clear air\nturbulence on the climb out from Zurich ?\n",
        "answer": "FL 220\n",
        "choiceone": "FL 160\n",
        "choicetwo": "FL 320\n",
        "choicethree": "FL 140\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10892A )\n Annex 050-10892A\n For 1300 UTC select a METAR which you consider to be most appropriate to position \u201cT\u201d ;\n",
        "answer": "19010KT 6000 RA BKN016 OVC090 08/06 Q1004 =\n",
        "choiceone": "18015KT 9999 SCT020 03/01 Q1000 =\n",
        "choicetwo": "27030KT 8000 SCT020 07/03 Q1004 =\n",
        "choicethree": "24020KT 5000 RA BKN100 11/10 Q1002 =\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "For a given airfield the QFE is 980 hPa and the QNH is 1000 hPa. The approximate elevation of the airfield is ;\n",
        "answer": "160 metres.\n 1000 hPa \u2013 980 hPa = 20 hPa , 1 hPa\u2019\u0131 27 ft olarak kabul edersek ;\n",
        "choiceone": "600 metres.\n",
        "choicetwo": "120 metres.\n 20 x 27 = 540 ft ,\n",
        "choicethree": "540 metres.\n 540 ft : 3.28 = 164.63 \u2248 160 metres.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "For a similar pressure gradient , the geostrophic wind speed will be ;\n",
        "answer": "greater at 30\u00b0N than at 60\u00b0N.\n",
        "choiceone": "greater at 60\u00b0N than at 30\u00b0N.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the same at all latitudes north or south of 15\u00b0.\n",
        "choicethree": "equivalent to gradient wind \u00b1 thermal component.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "For a VFR aircraft , the conditions in which it could encounter severe airframe icing are ;\n",
        "answer": "flight into freezing rain , resulting in clear ice formation.\n",
        "choiceone": "flight between two cloud layers , without precipitation , resulting in clear ice formation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "flight into supercooled rain , resulting in rime ice formation.\n",
        "choicethree": "flight into an area outside of clouds where the temperature is below 0\u00b0C , resulting in rime ice formation.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "For a VFR flight severe airframe icing may occur when flying ;\n",
        "answer": "into freezing rain , resulting in clear ice formation.\n",
        "choiceone": "into supercooled rain , resulting in rime ice formation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "into an area outside of clouds where the temperature is below 0\u00baC , resulting in rime ice formation.\n",
        "choicethree": "between two cloud layers , without precipitation , resulting in clear ice formation.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10771A )\n Annex 050-10771A\n For an aircraft at FL 40 , approaching the front ( square 3C ) from the direction of square 3D a potential hazard exists before\nreaching the front in the form of ;\n",
        "answer": "clear ice accretion to the airframe.\n",
        "choiceone": "severe downdrafts from subsiding air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "severe turbulence associated with CB.\n",
        "choicethree": "severe turbulence and wind shear.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10771A )\n Annex 050-10771A\n For an aircraft at FL 80 , ahead of the front in square 2D , the expected flight conditions are ;\n",
        "answer": "below AS type cloud , generally smooth air with light precipitation.\n",
        "choiceone": "overcast skies , moderate to heavy turbulence with the possibility of thunderstorms.\n",
        "choicetwo": "high CI and CS type cloud , light turbulence and poor visibility.\n",
        "choicethree": "IMC in cumuliform cloud , moderate turbulence with a risk of rime icing.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10771A )\n Annex 050-10771A\n For an aircraft making an approach to an airfield located in square 3B , away from the vicinity of the fronts , the most likely\nweather conditions in winter are ;\n",
        "answer": "poor visibility in mist and drizzle.\n",
        "choiceone": "scattered SC and CU , good visibility.\n",
        "choicetwo": "prolonged periods of heavy rain and hail.\n",
        "choicethree": "generally overcast , moderate continuous rain and risk of low level wind shear.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10771A )\n Annex 050-10771A\n For an aircraft making an approach to an airfield located in square 3B , the most likely weather conditions are ;\n",
        "answer": "low cloud , mist.\n",
        "choiceone": "showers of rain and hail.\n",
        "choicetwo": "moderate continuous rain.\n",
        "choicethree": "scattered AC base 2000 ft , good visibility.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10811A )\n Annex 050-10811A\n For an aircraft making an approach to an airfield which is not situated near high ground , in the vicinity of the active front in\nsquare 3B , a potential hazard exists in the form of ;\n",
        "answer": "low level wind shear.\n",
        "choiceone": "clear air turbulence ( CAT ).\n",
        "choicetwo": "radiation fog.\n",
        "choicethree": "rotor streaming.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "For an aircraft what are the meteorological dangers associated with a Harmattan wind ?\n",
        "answer": "Dust and poor visibility.\n",
        "choiceone": "Thunderstorms.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Hail.\n",
        "choicethree": "Sand up to FL 150.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "For an airfield located in the British Isles , the passage of a warm front will usually be indicated by ;\n",
        "answer": "rise in temperature , rise in dew point temperature , wind veers and decreases.\n",
        "choiceone": "rise in temperature , rapid rise in pressure , wind backs and becomes gusty.\n",
        "choicetwo": "rapid improvement in visibility , pressure falling rapidly , wind veering and increasing.\n",
        "choicethree": "a fall in temperature , rise in dew point temperature , wind backing and decreasing.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "For both saturated and unsaturated air instability will occur when the ;\n",
        "answer": "environmental lapse rate is greater than both dry adiabatic lapse rate and saturated adiabatic lapse rate.\n",
        "choiceone": "environmental lapse rate is greater than saturated adiabatic lapse rate but less than dry adiabatic lapse rate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "dry adiabatic lapse rate is less than saturated adiabatic lapse rate but greater than environmental lapse rate.\n",
        "choicethree": "environmental lapse rate is less than both dry adiabatic lapse rate and saturated adiabatic lapse rate.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "For subsonic cruising levels , a SIGMET is NOT issued in case of ;\n",
        "answer": "isolated CB.\n",
        "choiceone": "heavy sandstorm.\n",
        "choicetwo": "severe turbulence.\n",
        "choicethree": "volcanic ash.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "For the planning of a flight with an estimated time of departure 09:30 local time from an European airport a satellite picture\nis used to locate areas of fog. What type of satellite imagery available with observation time close to ETD does provide most likely\nthe best information to locate these areas of fog ?\n",
        "answer": "Visual ( VIS ) and infrared ( IR ) , polar orbiting system.\n",
        "choiceone": "Water vapour ( WV ) , geo-stationary system.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Infrared ( IR ) , geo-stationary system.\n",
        "choicethree": "Infrared ( IR ) and water vapour ( WV ) , polar orbiting system.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "For the same horizontal distance between adjacent isobars the gradient wind speed will be least at ;\n",
        "answer": "50\u00b0N with a cyclonic circulation.\n",
        "choiceone": "50\u00b0N in an anticyclone.\n",
        "choicetwo": "30\u00b0N with a cyclonic circulation.\n",
        "choicethree": "30\u00b0N in an anticyclone.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "For the same pressure gradient at 60\u00b0N , 50\u00b0N and 40\u00b0N the speed of the geostrophic wind will be ;\n",
        "answer": "greatest at 40\u00b0N.\n",
        "choiceone": "greatest at 60\u00b0N.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the same at all latitudes.\n",
        "choicethree": "least at 50\u00b0N.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Freezing fog consists of ;\n",
        "answer": "supercooled water droplets.\n",
        "choiceone": "frozen water droplets.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ice crystals.\n",
        "choicethree": "frozen minute snow flakes.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Freezing fog exists if fog droplets ;\n",
        "answer": "are supercooled.\n",
        "choiceone": "are frozen.\n",
        "choicetwo": "freeze when temperature falls below zero.\n",
        "choicethree": "are freezing very rapidly.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Freezing precipitation occurs ;\n",
        "answer": "mainly in the form of freezing rain or freezing drizzle.\n",
        "choiceone": "only in the precipitation of a warm front.\n",
        "choicetwo": "mainly in the form of freezing hail or freezing snow.\n",
        "choicethree": "only in the precipitation of a cold front.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Friction between the air and the ground results in the northern hemisphere in ;\n",
        "answer": "backing of the wind and decrease of wind speed at the surface.\n",
        "choiceone": "veering of the wind and decrease of wind speed at the surface.\n",
        "choicetwo": "backing of the wind and increase of wind speed at the surface.\n",
        "choicethree": "veering of the wind and increase of wind speed at the surface.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10870A )\n Annex 050-10870A\n From indications shown on the chart , when front \u201cS\u201d passes position \u201cV\u201d the surface wind should ;\n",
        "answer": "veer and remain more or less at the same speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "veer and increase.\n",
        "choicetwo": "back and decrease.\n",
        "choicethree": "back and remain more or less at the same speed.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "From summer to winter the average geographic position of the polar front jet stream over the North Atlantic moves ;\n",
        "answer": "towards the south and the speed increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "towards the north and the speed decreases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "towards the north and the speed increases.\n",
        "choicethree": "towards the south and the speed decreases.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "From summer to winter the polar front jet stream over the North Atlantic moves ;\n",
        "answer": "towards the south and the speed increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "towards the south and the speed decreases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "towards the north and the speed increases.\n",
        "choicethree": "towards the north and the speed decreases.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "From the following TAF you can assume that visibility at 2055Z in Birmingham ( EGBB ) will be ;\n EGBB 261000Z 261812 28015G25KT 9999 SCT025 TEMPO 1822 29018G35KT 5000 SHRASN BKN010CB PROB30\n TEMPO 1821 1500 TSGR BKN008CB BECMG 2224 26010KT\n",
        "answer": "not less than 1.5 km but could be in excess of 10 km.\n",
        "choiceone": "more than 10 km\n",
        "choicetwo": "a minimum of 1.5 km and a maximum of 5 km.\n",
        "choicethree": "a maximum 5 km.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "From what type of cloud does drizzle fall ?\n",
        "answer": "Stratus.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cirrostratus.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cumulus\n",
        "choicethree": "Altostratus\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "From which direction do the trade winds blow , in the southern hemisphere ?\n",
        "answer": "SE\n",
        "choiceone": "N\n",
        "choicetwo": "SW\n",
        "choicethree": "NE\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "From which of the following pieces of information can the stability of the atmosphere be derived ?\n",
        "answer": "Environmental lapse rate.\n",
        "choiceone": "Dry adiabatic lapse rate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Pressure at the surface.\n",
        "choicethree": "Surface temperature.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Frontal depressions can be assumed to move in the direction of the 2000 feet wind ;\n",
        "answer": "in the warm sector.\n",
        "choiceone": "at the apex of the wave.\n",
        "choicetwo": "in front of the warm front.\n",
        "choicethree": "behind the cold front.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Frontal fog can be formed by ;\n",
        "answer": "condensation of air saturated by evaporation of precipitation.\n",
        "choiceone": "evaporation of moisture at the surface.\n",
        "choicetwo": "cooling at night.\n",
        "choicethree": "condensation of air saturated by adiabatic cooling.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Frontal fog is most likely to occur ;\n",
        "answer": "in advance of a warm front\n",
        "choiceone": "in rear of a warm front\n",
        "choicetwo": "in winter in the early morning\n",
        "choicethree": "in summer in the early morning\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Frontal fog will most likely dissipate with ;\n",
        "answer": "the passage of a warm front.\n",
        "choiceone": "a decrease in wind speed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "decreasing intensity of precipitation.\n",
        "choicethree": "backing of the wind.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Frontal thunderstorms are mainly associated with ;\n",
        "answer": "cold fronts.\n",
        "choiceone": "cols.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ridges of high pressure.\n",
        "choicethree": "warm fronts.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Generally northern hemisphere winds at 5000 ft/AGL are south-westerly while most of the surface winds are southerly. What\nis the primary reason of difference between these two wind directions ?\n",
        "answer": "Friction between the wind and the surface.\n",
        "choiceone": "The influence of warm air at the lower altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Stronger Coriolis force at the surface.\n",
        "choicethree": "A strong pressure gradient at higher altitudes.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Geostrophic wind ;\n",
        "answer": "is perpendicular to the horizontal pressure gradient force.\n",
        "choiceone": "veers with height if cold air is advected in the northern hemisphere.\n",
        "choicetwo": "always increases with increasing height.\n",
        "choicethree": "is directly proportional to the density of the air.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Geostrophic wind is the wind when isobars are ;\n",
        "answer": "straight lines and no friction is involved.\n",
        "choiceone": "curved lines and friction is involved.\n",
        "choicetwo": "curved lines and no friction is involved\n",
        "choicethree": "straight lines and friction is involved.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Altimeter setting : 1013.2 hPa\n Altimeter reading : 5000 ft\n Outside air temperature at 5000 ft : +5\u00b0C\n QFE : 958 hPa\n QNH : 983 hPa\n What is the true height of the aeroplane above the aerodrome ?\n",
        "answer": "3515 ft\n",
        "choiceone": "4325 ft 983 hPa \u2013 958 hPa = 25 hPa , 1 hPa 27 ft kabul edersek ; 25 x 27 = 675 ft meydan rak\u0131m\u0131\n",
        "choicetwo": "4190 ft olarak bulunur. 1013 hPa \u2013 983 hPa = 30 \u2192 30 x 27 = 810 ft \u2192 5000 \u2013 810 = 4190 ft ,\n",
        "choicethree": "4865 ft ISA\u2019ya g\u00f6re 5000 feet\u2019de olmas\u0131 gereken s\u0131cakl\u0131k = 15 \u2013 ( 5 x 2 ) = +5\u00b0C yani ISA\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given the following METAR ;\n EDDM 250850Z 33005KT 2000 R26R/P1500N R26L/1500N BR SCT002 OVC003 05/05 Q1025 NOSIG =\n Which of the following statements is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "Visibility is reduced by water droplets.\n",
        "choiceone": "RVR on runway 26R is increasing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "There is a distinct change in RVR observed.\n",
        "choicethree": "Runway 26R and runway 26L have the same RVR.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Going from the equator to the north pole , the altitude of the tropopause ;\n",
        "answer": "decreases and its temperature increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "increases and its temperature increases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "decreases and its temperature decreases.\n",
        "choicethree": "increases and its temperature decreases.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Good visibility in the lower levels may be expected when ;\n",
        "answer": "cool dry air is moving over a warmer surface.\n",
        "choiceone": "warm air is moving over a cold surface.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the air temperature is low.\n",
        "choicethree": "the atmospheric pressure is low.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Half the mass of the atmosphere is found in the first ;\n",
        "answer": "5 km.\n",
        "choiceone": "3 km.\n",
        "choicetwo": "8 km.\n",
        "choicethree": "11 km.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hazardous hailstones , reaching the ground , are most likely to be experienced below CB clouds situated ;\n",
        "answer": "in continental interiors in middle latitudes.\n",
        "choiceone": "over the sea in middle latitudes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "in continental interiors near the equator.\n",
        "choicethree": "over the sea near the equator.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hoar frost forms on an aircraft as a result of ;\n",
        "answer": "water vapour turning directly into ice crystals on the aircraft surface.\n",
        "choiceone": "droplets forming on the aircraft and then freezing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "freezing rain striking the aircraft.\n",
        "choicethree": "small super-cooled droplets striking the aircraft.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hoar frost is most likely to form when ;\n",
        "answer": "taking off from an airfield with a significant ground inversion ( sky clear ).\n",
        "choiceone": "flying in supercooled drizzle.\n",
        "choicetwo": "flying inside stratiform clouds.\n",
        "choicethree": "flying inside convective clouds.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "How are high level condensation trails formed that are to be found occasionally behind jet aircraft ?\n",
        "answer": "Through water vapour released during fuel combustion.\n",
        "choiceone": "Only through unburnt fuel in the exhaust gases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "In conditions of low humidity , through the particles of soot contained in the exhaust gases.\n",
        "choicethree": "Through a decrease in pressure , and the associated adiabatic drop in temperature at the wing tips while flying\n through relatively warm but humid air.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "How are the air masses distributed in a cold occlusion ?\n",
        "answer": "The coldest air mass behind and the less cold air in front of the occlusion , the warm air mass is above ground\n level.\n",
        "choiceone": "The coldest air in front of and the less cold air is behind the occlusion , the warm air mass is above ground\n level.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The coldest air behind and the warm air in front of the occlusion , the less cold air mass is above ground\n level.\n",
        "choicethree": "The coldest air in front of and the warm air behind the occlusion , the less cold air is above ground level.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "How are well separated CB clouds described on the Significant Weather Chart ?\n",
        "answer": "OCNL CB.\n",
        "choiceone": "FRQ CB.\n",
        "choicetwo": "EMBD CB.\n",
        "choicethree": "ISOL CB.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "How do air masses move at a warm front ?\n",
        "answer": "Warm air overrides a cold air mass.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cold air overrides a warm air mass.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cold air undercuts a warm air mass.\n",
        "choicethree": "Warm air undercuts a cold air mass.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "How do you recognize a cold air pool ?\n",
        "answer": "As a low pressure area aloft ( e.g. on the 500 hPa chart ).\n",
        "choiceone": "As a high pressure area aloft ( e.g. on the 500 hPa chart ).\n",
        "choicetwo": "A cold air pool may only be recognized on the surface chart as a high pressure area.\n",
        "choicethree": "A cold air pool may only be recognized on the surface chart as a low pressure area.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "How does a pilot react to heavy freezing rain at 2000 ft/AGL , when he is unable to de-ice , nor land ?\n",
        "answer": "He turns back before the aircraft loses manoeuvrability.\n",
        "choiceone": "He descends to the warm air layer below.\n",
        "choicetwo": "He continues to fly at the same altitude.\n",
        "choicethree": "He ascends to the cold air layer above.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "How does freezing rain develop ?\n",
        "answer": "Rain falls through a layer where temperatures are below 0\u00b0C.\n",
        "choiceone": "Through melting of snow grains.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Snow falls through a layer where temperatures are above 0\u00b0C.\n",
        "choicethree": "Through melting of ice crystals.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "How does moderate turbulence affect an aircraft ?\n",
        "answer": "Changes in altitude or attitude occur but the aircraft remains in positive control at all times.\n",
        "choiceone": "Large , abrupt changes in altitude or attitude occur but the aircraft may only be out of control momentarily.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Rapid and somewhat rhythmic bumpiness is experienced without appreciable changes in altitude or attitude.\n",
        "choicethree": "Continued flight in this environment will result in structural damage.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "How does relative humidity and the dewpoint in an unsaturated air mass change with varying temperature ?\n",
        "answer": "When temperature increases , the relative humidity decreases , and the dewpoint remains constant.\n",
        "choiceone": "When temperature decreases , the relative humidity and the dewpoint remain constant.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When temperature decreases , the relative humidity decreases , and the dewpoint increases.\n",
        "choicethree": "When temperature increases , the relative humidity increases , and the dewpoint decreases.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "How does temperature vary with increasing altitude in the ICAO standard atmosphere below the tropopause ?\n",
        "answer": "Decreases.\n",
        "choiceone": "Remains constant.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Increases.\n",
        "choicethree": "At first it increases and higher up it decreases.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "How does the height of the tropopause normally vary with latitude in the northern hemisphere ?\n",
        "answer": "It decreases from south to north.\n",
        "choiceone": "It remains constant throughout the year.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It remains constant from north to south.\n",
        "choicethree": "It increases from south to north.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "How , if at all , is the relative humidity of an unsaturated air mass influenced by temperature changes ?\n",
        "answer": "It decreases with increasing temperature.\n",
        "choiceone": "It increases with increasing temperature.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It is not influenced by temperature changes.\n",
        "choicethree": "It is only influenced by the amount of water vapour.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "How is a ceiling defined ?\n",
        "answer": "Height above ground or water of the lowest layer of cloud below 20000 ft covering more than half of the sky.\n",
        "choiceone": "Height above ground or water of the lowest layer of cloud independent on the amount of clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Height above ground or water of the lowest layer of cloud that contributes to the overall overcast.\n",
        "choicethree": "Height above ground or water of the highest layer of cloud or obscuring phenomena aloft that covers 4 oktas\n or more of the sky.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "How is an easterly wave identifiable on a surface weather chart ?\n",
        "answer": "As a weak trough.\n",
        "choiceone": "As a well developed depression.\n",
        "choicetwo": "As a ridge.\n",
        "choicethree": "As a secondary depression.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "How is the direction and speed of upper winds described in forecasts ?\n",
        "answer": "The direction is relative to true north and the speed is in knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "The direction is relative to magnetic north and the speed is in knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The direction is relative to magnetic north and the speed is in miles per hour.\n",
        "choicethree": "The direction is relative to true north and the speed is in miles per hour.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "How is the Mediterranean climate best described ?\n",
        "answer": "Anticyclonic and hot in summer , frontal depressions in winter.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cyclonic and chilly in summer , frontal depressions in winter.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Depressions due to the polar front affect the weather throughout the whole year.\n",
        "choicethree": "Anticyclonic and warm the whole year.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long does a typical microburst last ?\n",
        "answer": "1 to 5 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "Less than 1 minute.\n",
        "choicetwo": "About 30 minutes.\n",
        "choicethree": "1 to 2 hours.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long from the time of observation is a TREND in a METAR valid ?\n",
        "answer": "2 hours.\n",
        "choiceone": "9 hours.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 hour.\n",
        "choicethree": "30 minutes.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "How would the term \u201cvertical visibility is missing or not measurable\u201d be indicated in a METAR ?\n",
        "answer": "VV///\n",
        "choiceone": "VVmis\n",
        "choicetwo": "VV999\n",
        "choicethree": "VV000\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "How would you characterise an air temperature of \u201315\u00b0C at the 700 hPa level over western Europe ?\n",
        "answer": "Low\n",
        "choiceone": "High\n ISA\u2019ya g\u00f6re 700 hPa seviyesi FL100\u2019d\u0131r. Bu seviyede ISA\u2019ya g\u00f6re\n",
        "choicetwo": "Within +/-5\u00b0C of ISA\n olmas\u0131 gereken s\u0131cakl\u0131k = ( 10 x 2 ) \u2013 15 = \u20135\u00b0C\u2019dir. Yani \u201315\u00b0C\u2019lik\n",
        "choicethree": "20\u00b0C below standard\n s\u0131cakl\u0131k ISA\u2019ya g\u00f6re 10\u00b0C daha so\u011fuktur. Cevap ; Low\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "How would you characterise an air temperature of \u201330\u00b0C at the 300 hPa level over western Europe ?\n",
        "answer": "High olmas\u0131 gereken s\u0131cakl\u0131k = ( 30 x 2 ) \u2013 15 = \u201345\u00b0C\u2019dir. Yani \u201330\u00b0C\u2019lik\n",
        "choiceone": "Within +/-5\u00b0C of ISA\n",
        "choicetwo": "Low\n",
        "choicethree": "Very low ISA\u2019ya g\u00f6re 300 hPa seviyesi FL300\u2019d\u0131r. Bu seviyede ISA\u2019ya g\u00f6re\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "How would you characterise an air temperature of \u201355\u00b0C at the 200 hPa level over western Europe ?\n",
        "answer": "Within +/-5\u00b0C of ISA\n",
        "choiceone": "High\n",
        "choicetwo": "Very high ISA\u2019ya g\u00f6re 200 hPa seviyesi FL390\u2019d\u0131r. Bu seviyede ISA\u2019ya g\u00f6re\n",
        "choicethree": "Low olmas\u0131 gereken s\u0131cakl\u0131k = \u201356\u00b0C\u2019dir. Yani \u201355\u00b0C\u2019lik s\u0131cakl\u0131k ISA\u2019ya\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ice accretion to the airframe is likely to be most hazardous at temperatures ;\n",
        "answer": "between 0\u00b0C and \u201323\u00b0C in large CU\n",
        "choiceone": "between 0\u00b0C and -17\u00b0C in AS\n",
        "choicetwo": "between 0\u00b0C and -17\u00b0C in ST\n",
        "choicethree": "below -40\u00b0C in CB\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a flight at FL 150 is planned , which of these upper wind and temperature charts would be nearest to that flight level ?\n",
        "answer": "600 hPa 850 hPa \u2192 FL50 ISA +5\u00b0C , 700 hPa \u2192 FL100 ISA \u20135\u00b0C ,\n",
        "choiceone": "500 hPa\n",
        "choicetwo": "850 hPa 500 hPa \u2192 FL180 ISA \u201321\u00b0C , 300 hPa \u2192 FL300 ISA \u201345\u00b0C ,\n",
        "choicethree": "700 hPa 250 hPa \u2192 FL340 ISA \u201352\u00b0C , 200 hPa \u2192 FL390 ISA \u201356\u00b0C.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a saturated air mass descends down a slope its temperature increases at ;\n",
        "answer": "a lower rate than in dry air , as evaporation absorbs heat.\n",
        "choiceone": "a lower rate than in dry air , as condensation gives out heat.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the same rate as if the air mass were dry.\n",
        "choicethree": "a higher rate than in dry air , as it gives up latent evaporation heat.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If atmospheric conditions exist such that the temperature is ISA +10\u00b0C in the lower troposphere up to 18.000 ft , what is the\nactual layer thickness between FL 60 and FL 120 ?\n",
        "answer": "6240 ft.\n",
        "choiceone": "5900 ft.\n S\u0131cakl\u0131k ISA +10\u00b0C oldu\u011funa g\u00f6re s\u0131cakl\u0131k sapmas\u0131 + y\u00f6nde olacakt\u0131r.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5760 ft.\n FL120 \u2013 FL60 = 60 = 6000 ft , s\u0131cakl\u0131k sapmas\u0131 ;\n",
        "choicethree": "6000 ft.\n 4 x ( 6000 : 1000 ) x 10\u00b0C = 240 ft \u2192 6000 + 240 = 6240 ft.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If CAVOK is reported then ;\n",
        "answer": "no low drifting snow is present.\n",
        "choiceone": "no clouds are present.\n",
        "choicetwo": "low level wind shear has not been reported.\n",
        "choicethree": "any CB\u2019s have a base above 5000 ft.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If in a 100 m thick layer the temperature at the bottom of the layer is 10\u00b0C and at the top of the layer is 8\u00b0C then this layer\nis ;\n",
        "answer": "absolutely unstable.\n",
        "choiceone": "neutral.\n",
        "choicetwo": "absolutely stable.\n",
        "choicethree": "conditionally unstable.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If Paris reports a wind of 08010KT on the METAR , what wind velocity would you expect to encounter at a height of 2000\nfeet above the ground ?\n",
        "answer": "11020KT 30 derece farkl\u0131l\u0131kta , \u015fiddet olarak da 2 kat\u0131 olacakt\u0131r. Buna g\u00f6re ;\n",
        "choiceone": "08005KT\n",
        "choicetwo": "08015KT\n Kuzey Yar\u0131k\u00fcrede , 2000 feet\u2019teki r\u00fczgar yerdeki r\u00fczgara g\u00f6re saat y\u00f6n\u00fcnde\n",
        "choicethree": "05020KT\n 080 + 30 = 110\u00b0 , 10 x 2 = 20 kt \u2192 Cevap ; 11020KT\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If Paris reports a wind of 16020KT on the METAR , what wind velocity would you expect to encounter at a height of 2000\nfeet above the ground ?\n",
        "answer": "19040KT\n",
        "choiceone": "17015KT Kuzey Yar\u0131k\u00fcrede , 2000 feet\u2019teki r\u00fczgar yerdeki r\u00fczgara g\u00f6re saat y\u00f6n\u00fcnde\n",
        "choicetwo": "14020KT 30 derece farkl\u0131l\u0131kta , \u015fiddet olarak da 2 kat\u0131 olacakt\u0131r. Buna g\u00f6re ;\n",
        "choicethree": "16030KT 160 + 30 = 190\u00b0 , 20 x 2 = 40 kt \u2192 Cevap ; 19040KT\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If Paris reports a wind of 19015KT on the METAR , what wind velocity would you expect to encounter at a height of 2000\nfeet above the ground ?\n",
        "answer": "22030KT 190 + 30 = 220\u00b0 , 15 x 2 = 30 kt \u2192 Cevap ; 22030KT\n",
        "choiceone": "25025KT\n",
        "choicetwo": "16020KT Kuzey Yar\u0131k\u00fcrede , 2000 feet\u2019teki r\u00fczgar yerdeki r\u00fczgara g\u00f6re saat y\u00f6n\u00fcnde\n",
        "choicethree": "22010KT 30 derece farkl\u0131l\u0131kta , \u015fiddet olarak da 2 kat\u0131 olacakt\u0131r. Buna g\u00f6re ;\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If Paris reports a wind of 30012KT on the METAR , what wind velocity would you expect to encounter at a height of 2000\nfeet above the ground ?\n",
        "answer": "33025KT Kuzey Yar\u0131k\u00fcrede , 2000 feet\u2019teki r\u00fczgar yerdeki r\u00fczgara g\u00f6re saat y\u00f6n\u00fcnde\n",
        "choiceone": "23030KT\n",
        "choicetwo": "27020KT 30 derece farkl\u0131l\u0131kta , \u015fiddet olarak da 2 kat\u0131 olacakt\u0131r. Buna g\u00f6re ;\n",
        "choicethree": "30025KT 300 + 30 = 330\u00b0 , 12 x 2 = 24 kt \u2248 25 kt \u2192 Cevap ; 33025KT\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If radiation fog forms on a clear night with light winds , the increase in wind speed from 5 kt to 13 kt will most likely ;\n",
        "answer": "cause the fog to lift and become low stratus.\n",
        "choiceone": "disperse the fog immediately.\n",
        "choicetwo": "have no effect.\n",
        "choicethree": "change the radiation fog to advection fog.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the pressure surfaces bulge upwards in all levels then the pressure system is a ;\n",
        "answer": "warm high.\n",
        "choiceone": "warm low.\n",
        "choicetwo": "cold low.\n",
        "choicethree": "cold high.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the QFE at Locarno ( 200 metres above sea level ) is 980 hPa , what is the approximate QNH ?\n",
        "answer": "1005 hPa\n 656 : 27 = 24,29 \u2248 25 hPa , QNH = QFE + 25 hPa = 980 + 25 = 1005 hPa\n",
        "choiceone": "1015 hPa\n",
        "choicetwo": "1000 hPa\n 200 metrelik rak\u0131m\u0131n ka\u00e7 hPa\u2019a denk gelece\u011fini hesaplamal\u0131y\u0131z ;\n",
        "choicethree": "1010 hPa\n 200 metre = 200 x 3.28 = 656 ft ve 1 hPa\u2019\u0131 27 ft olarak kabul edersek ;\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the QFE at Locarno ( 200 metres above sea level ) is 1000 hPa , what is the approximate QNH ?\n",
        "answer": "1025 hPa 200 metrelik rak\u0131m\u0131n ka\u00e7 hPa\u2019a denk gelece\u011fini hesaplamal\u0131y\u0131z ;\n",
        "choiceone": "990 hPa\n",
        "choicetwo": "985 hPa\n",
        "choicethree": "1035 hPa 200 metre = 200 x 3.28 = 656 ft ve 1 hPa\u2019\u0131 27 ft olarak kabul edersek ;\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the QFE , QNH and QFF of an airport have the same value ;\n",
        "answer": "the airport must be at MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "the 1013.25 hPa level must be at MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the airport must be at MSL and the conditions must be as in the ISA.\n",
        "choicethree": "the conditions must be as in the ISA.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the QNH at Locarno ( 200 metres above sea level ) is 1015 hPa , what is the approximate QFE ?\n",
        "answer": "990 hPa\n 656 : 27 = 24,29 \u2248 25 hPa , QFE = QNH \u2212 25 hPa = 1015 \u2212 25 = 990 hPa\n",
        "choiceone": "995 hPa\n",
        "choicetwo": "1005 hPa\n 200 metrelik rak\u0131m\u0131n ka\u00e7 hPa\u2019a denk gelece\u011fini hesaplamal\u0131y\u0131z ;\n",
        "choicethree": "1000 hPa\n 200 metre = 200 x 3.28 = 656 ft ve 1 hPa\u2019\u0131 27 ft olarak kabul edersek ;\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the QNH at Locarno ( 200 metres above sea level ) is 1025 hPa , what is the approximate QFE ?\n",
        "answer": "1000 hPa 200 metre = 200 x 3.28 = 656 ft ve 1 hPa\u2019\u0131 27 ft olarak kabul edersek ;\n",
        "choiceone": "1005 hPa\n",
        "choicetwo": "1025 hPa\n",
        "choicethree": "995 hPa 200 metrelik rak\u0131m\u0131n ka\u00e7 hPa\u2019a denk gelece\u011fini hesaplamal\u0131y\u0131z ;\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the subscale of an altimeter is set to QNH , what will it indicate after landing ?\n",
        "answer": "Aerodrome elevation.\n",
        "choiceone": "Less than aerodrome elevation when pressure is lower than standard , more than aerodrome elevation when\n pressure is higher than standard.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Less than aerodrome elevation when it is colder than standard , more than aerodrome elevation when it is\n warmer than standard.\n",
        "choicethree": "Pressure altitude.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the surface temperature is 15\u00b0C , then the temperature at 10.000 ft in a current of ascending unsaturated air is ;\n",
        "answer": "\u221215\u00b0C\n",
        "choiceone": "\u22125\u00b0C\n",
        "choicetwo": "5\u00b0C Doymam\u0131\u015f ( unsaturated ) bir havada y\u00fckseklikle beraber her 1000 feet i\u00e7in\n",
        "choicethree": "0\u00b0C 3\u00b0C\u2019lik bir d\u00fc\u015f\u00fc\u015f olur. Buna g\u00f6re ;\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If you are flying at FL 100 in an air mass that is 10\u00b0C warmer than a standard atmosphere , what is the outside temperature\nlikely to be ?\n",
        "answer": "+5\u00b0C ( \u22125\u00b0C ) + ( +10\u00b0C ) = +5\u00b0C\n",
        "choiceone": "+15\u00b0C\n",
        "choicetwo": "\u221215\u00b0C ISA\u2019ya g\u00f6re FL100\u2019da olmas\u0131 gereken s\u0131cakl\u0131k = ( 10 x 2 ) \u2212 15 = \u22125\u00b0C ,\n",
        "choicethree": "\u221210\u00b0C OAT , ISA\u2019ya g\u00f6re 10\u00b0C daha s\u0131cak oldu\u011funa g\u00f6re ;\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If you are flying at FL 120 and the outside temperature is \u22122\u00b0C , at what altitude will the \u201cfreezing level\u201d be ?\n",
        "answer": "FL 110 g\u00f6re donma seviyesi daha a\u015fa\u011f\u0131da olmal\u0131d\u0131r. S\u0131cakl\u0131k ISA\u2019ya g\u00f6re her 1000\n",
        "choiceone": "FL 150\n",
        "choicetwo": "FL 90 Donma seviyesinin s\u0131cakl\u0131\u011f\u0131 0\u00b0C olmal\u0131d\u0131r. FL120\u2019da s\u0131cakl\u0131k \u22122\u00b0C oldu\u011funa\n",
        "choicethree": "FL 130 feet\u2019de 2\u00b0C de\u011fi\u015fti\u011fine g\u00f6re donma seviyesi FL 110 olacakt\u0131r.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If you are flying at FL 300 in an air mass that is 15\u00b0C warmer than a standard atmosphere , what is the outside temperature\nlikely to be ?\n",
        "answer": "\u221230\u00b0C OAT ( Outside Air Temperature ) , ISA\u2019ya g\u00f6re 15\u00b0C daha s\u0131cak oldu\u011funa g\u00f6re ;\n",
        "choiceone": "\u221260\u00b0C\n",
        "choicetwo": "\u221245\u00b0C ISA\u2019ya g\u00f6re FL100\u2019da olmas\u0131 gereken s\u0131cakl\u0131k = ( 30 x 2 ) \u2212 15 = \u221245\u00b0C ,\n",
        "choicethree": "\u221215\u00b0C ( \u221245\u00b0C ) + ( +15\u00b0C ) = \u221230\u00b0C\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4380A )\n Annex 050-4380A\n If you are flying from Zurich to London at FL 240 , what conditions can you expect at cruising altitude ?\n",
        "answer": "Moderate or severe turbulence and icing.\n",
        "choiceone": "Prolonged severe turbulence and icing throughout the flight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Flight largely in cloud , no turbulence.\n",
        "choicethree": "CAT for the first half of the flight.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4386A )\n Annex 050-4386A\n If you are flying from Zurich to Shannon at FL 340 , where will your cruising altitude be ?\n",
        "answer": "Constantly in the stratosphere.\n",
        "choiceone": "First in the troposphere and later in the stratosphere.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Constantly in the troposphere.\n",
        "choicethree": "In the stratosphere for part of time.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If you are planning a flight at FL 170 , which of these upper wind and temperature charts would be nearest your flight level ?\n",
        "answer": "500 hPa\n",
        "choiceone": "700 hPa 850 hPa \u2192 FL50 ISA +5\u00b0C , 700 hPa \u2192 FL100 ISA \u20135\u00b0C ,\n",
        "choicetwo": "300 hPa 500 hPa \u2192 FL180 ISA \u201321\u00b0C , 300 hPa \u2192 FL300 ISA \u201345\u00b0C ,\n",
        "choicethree": "850 hPa 250 hPa \u2192 FL340 ISA \u201352\u00b0C , 200 hPa \u2192 FL390 ISA \u201356\u00b0C.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If you are planning a flight at FL 290 , which of these upper wind and temperature charts would be nearest your flight level ?\n",
        "answer": "300 hPa\n",
        "choiceone": "500 hPa 850 hPa \u2192 FL50 ISA +5\u00b0C , 700 hPa \u2192 FL100 ISA \u20135\u00b0C ,\n",
        "choicetwo": "850 hPa 500 hPa \u2192 FL180 ISA \u201321\u00b0C , 300 hPa \u2192 FL300 ISA \u201345\u00b0C ,\n",
        "choicethree": "700 hPa 250 hPa \u2192 FL340 ISA \u201352\u00b0C , 200 hPa \u2192 FL390 ISA \u201356\u00b0C.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If you have to fly through a warm front when freezing level is at 10000 feet in the warm air and at 2000 feet in the cold air ,\nat which altitude is the probability of freezing rain the lowest ?\n",
        "answer": "12000 feet\n",
        "choiceone": "9000 feet\n",
        "choicetwo": "5000 feet\n",
        "choicethree": "3000 feet\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Imagine an aircraft during approach to an airfield which is located in a basin within mountainous area under the influence of\na blocking anticyclone in winter. Mark the most reasonable statement given below ;\n",
        "answer": "While approaching the airfield in the early morning , after a short period of bumpiness the engines of the\n aircraft will deliver more thrust after breaking through the inversion layer if the pilot does not intervene.\n",
        "choiceone": "While approaching the airfield shortly before surise , the pilot has the consider turbulence because at first lift\n will be decreased due to katabatic winds and , after breaking through a valley inversion layer , lift is likely to\n improve due to anabatic wind.\n",
        "choicetwo": "While approaching the airfield in the early morning hours , these conditions apply for the possibility of a\n marked valley inversion which has to be considered as a potential flight hazard due to decreased lift after\n breaking through the inversion layer.\n",
        "choicethree": "While approaching the airfield in the late evening hours , without the pilot\u2019s intervention the engines of the\n aircraft are most likely to provide less thrust after breaking through the inversion layer.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Imagine an airfield during summer with sunny days and clear nights and with a runway parallel to the shoreline of a large\ninland lake 5 nautical miles away from the field. A small aircraft heading for the airfield in the afternoon experiences wind shear\nduring approach and a cross wind component which makes landing difficult. The origin of the wind shear and cross wind is most\nlikely to be seen in ;\n",
        "answer": "a strong sea breeze blowing more or less perpendicular to the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "a strong land breeze blowing more or less perpendicular to the runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a radiation inversion due to surface cooling during the clear night.\n",
        "choicethree": "a subsidence inversion typical for summer anticyclones causing variations in wind speed and direction near\n the surface.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a land- and sea-breeze circulation the land-breeze blows ;\n",
        "answer": "during the night and is weaker than the sea-breeze.\n",
        "choiceone": "during the day and is stronger than the sea-breeze.\n",
        "choicetwo": "during the day and is weaker than the sea-breeze.\n",
        "choicethree": "during the night and is stronger than the sea-breeze.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a layer of air the decrease in temperature per 100 metres increase in height is more than 1\u00b0C. This layer can be described\nas being ;\n",
        "answer": "absolutely unstable.\n",
        "choiceone": "absolutely stable.\n",
        "choicetwo": "conditionally unstable.\n",
        "choicethree": "conditionally stable.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a low pressure system the convergence at the surface is caused by ;\n",
        "answer": "frictional forces.\n",
        "choiceone": "the curvature of the isobars.\n",
        "choicetwo": "centripetal forces.\n",
        "choicethree": "the inbalance of the horizontal gradient force and the Coriolis force.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a METAR message , BR and HZ mean respectively ;\n",
        "answer": "BR = mist HZ = haze.\n",
        "choiceone": "BR = mist HZ = widespread dust.\n",
        "choicetwo": "BR = fog HZ = haze.\n",
        "choicethree": "BR = mist HZ = smoke.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a METAR message , the wind group is 23010MPS. This means ;\n",
        "answer": "wind from 230\u00b0 true at 20 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "wind from 230\u00b0 magnetic at 20 knots. 10 MPS ( Metre Per Second ) = 10 x 60 = 600 m/min\n",
        "choicetwo": "wind from 230\u00b0 true at 10 miles per hour. = 600 x 60 = 36000 m/h =36000 : 1000 = 36 km/h\n",
        "choicethree": "wind from 230\u00b0 magnetic at 10 miles per hour. 36 : 1,852 = 19,438 \u2248 20 NM/h = 20 kt , R\u00fczgar y\u00f6n\u00fc True\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a mountain-valley wind circulation , the mountain wind blows ;\n",
        "answer": "at night down from the mountains.\n",
        "choiceone": "during the day down from the mountains.\n",
        "choicetwo": "during the day up from the valley.\n",
        "choicethree": "at night up from the valley.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a mountainous area , the most hazardous flying conditions associated with standing waves are likely to be experienced ;\n",
        "answer": "in the vicinity of the \u201croll\u201d cloud or rotor zone beneath the first wave on the leeward side.\n",
        "choiceone": "just above the lenticular cloud on the windward side.\n",
        "choicetwo": "between the troughs of the waves particularly 30 NM to 50 NM downwind and close to the tropopause.\n",
        "choicethree": "on the windward side of the mountain just above the \u201ccap\u201d cloud.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a situation with a weak pressure gradient and no thunderstorms around , what will the indication of the aneroid altimeter\nof an aircraft parked on the ground do over a period of about ten minutes ?\n",
        "answer": "Apparently nothing , because any changes would be small.\n",
        "choiceone": "Increase rapidly.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Decrease rapidly.\n",
        "choicethree": "Show strong fluctuations.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a warm front occlusion ;\n",
        "answer": "the warm air is lifted.\n",
        "choiceone": "the cold air is lifted.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the warm front becomes a front aloft.\n",
        "choicethree": "the warm front overtakes the cold front.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a warm occlusion ;\n",
        "answer": "the warm air is lifted.\n",
        "choiceone": "the warm front becomes a front aloft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the coldest air is lifted.\n",
        "choicethree": "the warm front overtakes the cold front.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a westerly situation , the mean time interval between polar frontal waves in Western Europe is ;\n",
        "answer": "one to two days.\n",
        "choiceone": "three to four days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "six to twelve hours.\n",
        "choicethree": "twelve to eighteen hours.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In addition to a lifting action , what are two other requirements necessary for thunderstorm formation ?\n",
        "answer": "Unstable conditions and high moisture content.\n",
        "choiceone": "Unstable conditions and high atmospheric pressure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Stable conditions and low atmospheric pressure.\n",
        "choicethree": "Stable conditions and high moisture content.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In addition to a stable layer of air over a substantial mountain range , the conditions most favourable to the development of\nstanding waves are ;\n",
        "answer": "wind speed excess of 20 kt at the surface and increasing with height , wind direction perpendicular to the\n general direction of the range.\n",
        "choiceone": "significant moisture loss due to precipitation , rapid lowering of the tropopause in the area of the mountain\n range.\n",
        "choicetwo": "conditional instability , wind speed constant from a direction parallel to the mountain range.\n",
        "choicethree": "steep dry adiabatic lapse rate , wind speed increasing and changing direction rapidly with increase in height.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In an air mass with no clouds the surface temperature is 15\u00b0C and the temperature at 1000 m/AGL is 13\u00b0C. This layer of air\nis ;\n",
        "answer": "stable.\n",
        "choiceone": "a layer of heavy turbulence.\n",
        "choicetwo": "unstable.\n",
        "choicethree": "conditionally unstable.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In an area of converging air in low level ;\n",
        "answer": "clouds can be formed.\n",
        "choiceone": "stratified clouds can be dissolved.\n",
        "choicetwo": "clouds can not be formed.\n",
        "choicethree": "convective clouds can be dissolved.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In an intense trough of low pressure over Iceland during wintertime the weather likely to be experienced is ;\n",
        "answer": "strong wind shear , convection and snow showers.\n",
        "choiceone": "strong wind associated with an almost clear sky.\n",
        "choicetwo": "light wind , good visibility and a high cloud ceiling.\n",
        "choicethree": "strong wind with subsidence at low levels.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In an isothermal layer the state of the atmosphere is ;\n",
        "answer": "absolutely stable.\n",
        "choiceone": "conditionally unstable.\n",
        "choicetwo": "absolutely unstable.\n",
        "choicethree": "neutral.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In an unsaturated layer in the friction layer the air is well mixed by turbulence. The layer remains unsaturated. After some\ntime the vertical temperature profile will ;\n",
        "answer": "correspond to the dry adiabatic lapse rate.\n",
        "choiceone": "at first coincide with the average dry adiabat and then coincide with the average wet adiabat.\n",
        "choicetwo": "always change toward a more stable position.\n",
        "choicethree": "coincide with the average wet adiabat in the layer.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In an unstable layer there are cumuliform clouds. The vertical extent of these clouds depends on the ;\n",
        "answer": "thickness of the unstable layer.\n",
        "choiceone": "wind direction.\n",
        "choicetwo": "air pressure at the surface.\n",
        "choicethree": "pressure at different levels.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-11849A )\n Annex 050-11849A\n In appendix are shown four sections of the 700 hPa wind chart. The diagram representing most accurately the wind direction\nand speed is ;\n",
        "answer": "030\u00b0/30 kt ( diagram A ).\n",
        "choiceone": "030\u00b0/30 kt ( diagram C ).\n",
        "choicetwo": "210\u00b0/30 kt ( diagram B ).\n",
        "choicethree": "210\u00b0/30 kt ( diagram D ).\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In case of fronts , what cloud formation is most likely to occur at low levels when a warm air mass overrides a cold air\nmass ?\n",
        "answer": "Nimbostratus.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cumulonimbus.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Altostratus.\n",
        "choicethree": "Cumulus.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Central Europe when is the greatest likelihood for thunderstorms due to warm updrafts ?\n",
        "answer": "Mid - afternoon.\n",
        "choiceone": "Around midnight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Early morning.\n",
        "choicethree": "Late morning.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In general , the visibility during rainfall compared to during drizzle is ;\n",
        "answer": "greater.\n",
        "choiceone": "the same.\n",
        "choicetwo": "in rain - below 1 km , in drizzle - more than 2 km.\n",
        "choicethree": "less.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Geneva , the local QNH is 994 hPa. The elevation of Geneva is 1411 ft. The QFE adjustment in Geneva is ;\n",
        "answer": "942 hPa. 1 hPa\u2019\u0131 27 ft olarak al\u0131rsak ;\n",
        "choiceone": "967 hPa.\n",
        "choicetwo": "948 hPa.\n",
        "choicethree": "961 hPa. 1411 : 27 = 52,259 hPa \u2248 52 hPa ,\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In January an extended high pressure area is normally observed over ;\n",
        "answer": "Siberia.\n",
        "choiceone": "Central Europe.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Southern Africa.\n",
        "choicethree": "South America.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In mature Cb\u2019s the probability of severe icing , according to meteorological rules , is greatest in the following temperature\nrange ;\n",
        "answer": "0\u00b0C to \u201323\u00b0C.\n",
        "choiceone": "\u201323\u00b0C to \u201340\u00b0C.\n",
        "choicetwo": "\u201340\u00b0C to \u201360\u00b0C.\n",
        "choicethree": "+5\u00b0C to 0\u00b0C.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In METAR messages , the pressure group represents the ;\n",
        "answer": "QNH rounded down to the nearest hPa.\n",
        "choiceone": "QNH rounded up to the nearest hPa.\n",
        "choicetwo": "QFE rounded down to the nearest hPa.\n",
        "choicethree": "QFE rounded to the nearest hPa.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In meteorology the process by which water vapour is transformed directly into ice is known as ;\n",
        "answer": "sublimation.\n",
        "choiceone": "supercooling.\n",
        "choicetwo": "supersaturation.\n",
        "choicethree": "radiation cooling.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In meteorology , which constituent is considered the most important in the atmosphere\u2019s composition ?\n",
        "answer": "Water vapour.\n",
        "choiceone": "Oxygen.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Hydrogen.\n",
        "choicethree": "Nitrogen.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In mid-latitudes , the tops of Cumulus are often limited by ;\n",
        "answer": "a temperature inversion.\n",
        "choiceone": "a layer of unstable air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a radiation inversion.\n",
        "choicethree": "the tropopause.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In mid-latitudes , what surface weather is associated with a stationary high pressure region over land in the winter ?\n",
        "answer": "A tendency for fog and low ST.\n",
        "choiceone": "NS with continuous rain.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Thunderstorms.\n",
        "choicethree": "The possibility of snow showers.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In order to calculate QFE from QNH , which of the following must be known ?\n",
        "answer": "Elevation of the airfield.\n",
        "choiceone": "Elevation and the temperature at the airfield.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Elevation of the airfield and the temperature at MSL.\n",
        "choicethree": "Temperature at the airfield.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In order to reduce QFE to QNH , which of the following item(s) must be known ?\n",
        "answer": "Elevation of the airfield.\n",
        "choiceone": "Elevation of the airfield and the temperature at MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Temperature at the airfield.\n",
        "choicethree": "Elevation of the airfield and the temperature at the airfield.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In relation to the polar front jet stream , the greatest rate of wind shear is most likely to occur ;\n",
        "answer": "close to the core on the polar side.\n",
        "choiceone": "5000 ft or more above the core.\n",
        "choicetwo": "on the tropical side of the core.\n",
        "choicethree": "well below the core.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In relation to the total weight of the atmosphere , the weight of the atmosphere between mean sea level and a height of\n5500 m is ;\n",
        "answer": "50%.\n",
        "choiceone": "99%.\n",
        "choicetwo": "25%.\n",
        "choicethree": "1%.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In still air the temperature decreases at an average of 1.2\u00b0C per 100 m increase in altitude. This temperature change is called ;\n",
        "answer": "environmental lapse rate.\n",
        "choiceone": "saturated adiabatic lapse rate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "dry adiabatic lapse rate.\n",
        "choicethree": "normal lapse rate.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In stratiform clouds ;\n",
        "answer": "weak vertical currents occur and the temperature is nearly equal to the temperature of the surrounding air at\n the same height.\n",
        "choiceone": "strong vertical currents occur and the temperature is much lower than the temperature of the surrounding air\n at the same height.\n",
        "choicetwo": "strong vertical currents occur and the temperature is much higher than the temperature of the surrounding air\n at the same height.\n",
        "choicethree": "weak vertical currents occur and the temperature is much higher than the temperature of the surrounding air\n at the same height.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In summer in the northern hemisphere the maximum wind speeds associated with sub-tropical jet streams are usually\nlocated ;\n",
        "answer": "below the tropopause at about 200 hPa.\n",
        "choiceone": "above the tropopause at about 100 hPa.\n",
        "choicetwo": "below the tropopause at about 300 hPa.\n",
        "choicethree": "above the tropopause at about 250 hPa.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In summer , when wind is calm and sky is clear , the minimum temperature over land is reached approximately ;\n",
        "answer": "half an hour after sunrise.\n",
        "choiceone": "one hour before sunrise.\n",
        "choicetwo": "at the moment the sun rises.\n",
        "choicethree": "half an hour before sunrise.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In temperate latitudes what weather conditions may be expected over land during the summer in the centre of a stationary\nhigh pressure zone ?\n",
        "answer": "Calm winds , haze.\n",
        "choiceone": "CB , TS.\n",
        "choicetwo": "TS , SH.\n",
        "choicethree": "NS.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the central part of the Atlantic Ocean between 10\u00b0N and 20\u00b0N the prevailing winds are ;\n",
        "answer": "NE trade winds.\n",
        "choiceone": "SW winds throughout the whole year.\n",
        "choicetwo": "NE monsoon in winter and SW monsoon in summer.\n",
        "choicethree": "SE trade winds.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the following TAF , what is the forecast weather at 0800 UTC ?\n TAF EHAM 152300Z 160009 33005KT 9999 SCT025 BKN100 BECMG 0002 27015KT 4500 -SN SCT008 OVC015\n TEMPO 0206 0400 +SN VV002 BECMG 0406 01008KT 9999 NSW SCT030 TEMPO 0709 03015G25KT 1200 SHSN\n SCT006 SCT015CB =\n",
        "answer": "Moderate snow showers or no significant weather.\n",
        "choiceone": "Light snow or moderate snow showers.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Heavy snow or no significant weather.\n",
        "choicethree": "Moderate snow showers or heavy snow.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the ICAO Standard Atmosphere the decrease in temperature with height below 11 km is ;\n",
        "answer": "0.65\u00b0C per 100 m.\n",
        "choiceone": "0.5\u00b0C per 100 m.\n",
        "choicetwo": "0.6\u00b0C per 100 m.\n",
        "choicethree": "1\u00b0C per 100 m.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the ICAO standard atmosphere , which of the following alternatives indicates the correct vertical temperature distribution\nin the lowest 11 km ?\n",
        "answer": "15\u00baC at mean sea level , decreasing at 0.65\u00baC per 100 metres.\n",
        "choiceone": "15.2\u00baC at mean sea level , decreasing at 0.65\u00baC per 100 metres.\n",
        "choicetwo": "13\u00baC at mean sea level , decreasing at 2\u00baC per 1000 feet.\n",
        "choicethree": "15\u00baC at mean sea level , decreasing at 0.65\u00baC per 100 feet.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the lower layers of the atmosphere due to friction the wind changes direction towards the low pressure area because ;\n",
        "answer": "wind speed decreases and therefore coriolis force decreases.\n",
        "choiceone": "turbulence is formed and pressure decreases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the pressure gradient increases.\n",
        "choicethree": "turbulence is formed and pressure increases.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the lower levels of the atmosphere when the environmental lapse rate is greater than saturated adiabatic lapse rate but less\nthan dry adiabatic lapse rate - the air mass is described as being ;\n",
        "answer": "conditionally unstable.\n",
        "choiceone": "unstable.\n",
        "choicetwo": "absolutely unstable.\n",
        "choicethree": "stable.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the lower part of the stratosphere the temperature ;\n",
        "answer": "is almost constant.\n",
        "choiceone": "decreases with altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increases at first and decreases afterward.\n",
        "choicethree": "increases with altitude.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the METAR code the abbreviation VC indicates ;\n",
        "answer": "present weather within a range of 8 km , but not at the airport.\n",
        "choiceone": "volcanic ash.\n",
        "choicetwo": "present weather at the airport.\n",
        "choicethree": "present weather within the approach area.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the METAR code the abbreviation VCBLDU means ;\n",
        "answer": "blowing dust in the vicinity.\n",
        "choiceone": "an active sandstorm.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an active duststorm.\n",
        "choicethree": "an active dust- and sandstorm.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the mid-latitudes of the northern hemisphere the wind blows ;\n",
        "answer": "clockwise around anticyclones and anti-clockwise around cyclones.\n",
        "choiceone": "direct from high to low pressure areas.\n",
        "choicetwo": "clockwise around cyclones and anti-clockwise around anticyclones.\n",
        "choicethree": "clockwise around anticyclones and cyclones.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the mid-latitudes the stratosphere extends on an average from ;\n",
        "answer": "11 to 50 km.\n",
        "choiceone": "85 to more than 200 km.\n",
        "choicetwo": "50 to 85 km.\n",
        "choicethree": "0 to 11 km.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the middle of the eye of a hurricane the wind speed is ;\n",
        "answer": "lower than 63 knots and the air is descending.\n",
        "choiceone": "higher than 63 knots and the air is descending.\n",
        "choicetwo": "lower than 63 knots and the air is ascending.\n",
        "choicethree": "higher than 63 knots and the air is ascending.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the month of August you prepare a flight ( cruising level FL 370 ) from Bombay ( 19\u00b0N - 73\u00b0E ) to Bangkok ( 13\u00b0N -\n100\u00b0E ). What wind conditions can you expect ?\n",
        "answer": "Headwinds.\n",
        "choiceone": "Strong northerly winds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Tailwinds.\n",
        "choicethree": "Light winds diagonal to the route.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the North Atlantic , you can often see a series of depressions located in a row and travelling from west to east. These\ndepressions ;\n",
        "answer": "are normally generated at the polar front.\n",
        "choiceone": "are mostly generated by convergence between the subtropical highs and the equatorial trough.\n",
        "choicetwo": "are residuals of tropical cyclones in the Florida area.\n",
        "choicethree": "are primarily generated by the vaporization process that takes place above the ocean.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the northern hemisphere a pilot flying at 1000 ft/AGL directly towards the centre of a low pressure area , will find the\nwind blowing from ;\n",
        "answer": "left and behind.\n",
        "choiceone": "directly ahead.\n",
        "choicetwo": "right and behind.\n",
        "choicethree": "about 45 degrees to the right of directly ahead.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the northern hemisphere advection of warm air aloft indicates ;\n",
        "answer": "the approach of a warm occlusion.\n",
        "choiceone": "backing winds with increasing heights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the formation of advection fog.\n",
        "choicethree": "increasing probability for showers.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the northern hemisphere at 5000 ft/AGL a south-westerly wind is blowing. The surface wind at the same location is a\nsoutherly wind. What is the primary reason of difference between these two wind directions ?\n",
        "answer": "Friction between the wind and the surface.\n",
        "choiceone": "The influenceof warm air at the lower altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Stronger Coriolis force at the surface.\n",
        "choicethree": "A strong pressure gradient at higher altitudes.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the northern hemisphere , during periods of prolonged clear skies associated with anticyclonic conditions , the ;\n",
        "answer": "surface wind speed tends to be highest during the early afternoon.\n",
        "choiceone": "wind tends to back from early morning until early afternoon.\n",
        "choicetwo": "surface wind speed tends to be highest at night.\n",
        "choicethree": "angle between isobars and surface wind direction tends to be greatest in the early afternoon.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the northern hemisphere the gradient wind of a cyclonic pressure distribution is 350/24 , over the sea the surface wind\nwould approximate ;\n",
        "answer": "340/20. Kuzey Yar\u0131k\u00fcrede deniz \u00fczerinde , 2000 feet\u2019teki r\u00fczgar deniz \u00fczerindeki\n",
        "choiceone": "030/28.\n",
        "choicetwo": "030/20. r\u00fczgara g\u00f6re saat y\u00f6n\u00fcnde 10 ila 15 derece farkl\u0131l\u0131kta olur. R\u00fczgar \u015fiddeti ise\n",
        "choicethree": "340/28. deniz y\u00fczeyinde , 2000 feet\u2019teki r\u00fczgar\u0131n yakla\u015f\u0131k 75%\u2019i kadard\u0131r. Buna g\u00f6re ;\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the northern hemisphere the wind at the surface blows ;\n",
        "answer": "counter-clockwise around , and toward the centre of , a low pressure area.\n",
        "choiceone": "from a low pressure area to a high pressure area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "clockwise around , and away from the centre of , a low pressure area.\n",
        "choicethree": "counter-clockwise around , and away from the centre of , a high pressure area.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the northern hemisphere with an anticyclonic pressure system the geostrophic wind at 2000 ft over the sea is 060/15. At\nthe same position the surface wind is most likely to be ;\n",
        "answer": "050/10. r\u00fczgara g\u00f6re saat y\u00f6n\u00fcnde 10 ila 15 derece farkl\u0131l\u0131kta olur. R\u00fczgar \u015fiddeti ise\n",
        "choiceone": "070/20.\n",
        "choicetwo": "060/20. Kuzey Yar\u0131k\u00fcrede deniz \u00fczerinde , 2000 feet\u2019teki r\u00fczgar deniz \u00fczerindeki\n",
        "choicethree": "060/10. deniz y\u00fczeyinde , 2000 feet\u2019teki r\u00fczgar\u0131n yakla\u015f\u0131k 75%\u2019i kadard\u0131r. Buna g\u00f6re ;\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the southern hemisphere what wind effect would you expect when flying from a high pressure area towards a low pressure\narea at FL 100 ?\n",
        "answer": "Wind from the right.\n",
        "choiceone": "Headwind with no drift.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Tailwind with no drift.\n",
        "choicethree": "Wind from the left.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the TAF for Athens , during the summer , for the time of your landing you note ; TEMPO TS. What is the maximum time\nthis deterioration in weather can last in anyone instance ?\n",
        "answer": "60 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "120 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "20 minutes.\n",
        "choicethree": "10 minutes.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the trade wind belt between the surface and the 500 hPa level , which of the following is true ?\n",
        "answer": "The air is relatively moist in the lower part and dry in the upper part.\n",
        "choiceone": "The air is relatively dry in the lower part and moist in the upper part.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The air is relatively moist.\n",
        "choicethree": "The air is relatively dry.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the tropopause the position of so called \u201ctropopause breaks\u201d is important for aviation because ;\n",
        "answer": "the cores of jet streams can be located near these breaks.\n",
        "choiceone": "winds will reverse direction in these breaks.\n",
        "choicetwo": "moderate to severe icing often occurs in these breaks.\n",
        "choicethree": "from this position the direction of movement of high pressure systems can be derived.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the troposphere the decrease of pressure per 100 m increase in height ;\n",
        "answer": "is smaller at higher levels than at lower levels.\n",
        "choiceone": "is in the order of 27 hPa near MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is greater at higher levels than at lower levels.\n",
        "choicethree": "remains constant at all levels.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the troposphere the decrease of pressure per 100 m increase in height is ;\n",
        "answer": "larger in the lower layers than in the higher layers.\n",
        "choiceone": "in the order of 27 hPa per 100 m in the friction layer.\n",
        "choicetwo": "always larger in a high pressure area than in a low pressure area.\n",
        "choicethree": "larger in the higher layers than in the lower layers.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the vicinity of industrial areas , smoke is most likely to affect surface visibility when ;\n",
        "answer": "there is a low level inversion.\n",
        "choiceone": "cumulus clouds have developed in the afternoon.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the surface wind is strong and gusty.\n",
        "choicethree": "a rapid moving cold front has just passed the area.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the weather briefing room during the pre-flight phase of a passenger flight from Zurich to Rome , you examine the\nfollowing weather reports of pressing importance at the time ;\n EINN SHANNON 2808 sigmet 2 valid 0800/1100 loc sev turb fcst einn fir blw fl 050 south of 53n wkn =\n LIMM MILANO 2809 sigmet 2 valid 0900/1500 mod sev cat btn fl 250 and fl 430 fcst limm fir stnr nc =\n EGLL LONDON 2808 sigmet nr01 valid 0800/1200 for london fir isol cb embd in lyr cloud fcst tops fl 300 btn 52n and 54n\n east of 002e sev ice sev turb ts also fcst mov e wkn =\n Which decision is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "Because of the expected turbulence you select a flight level below FL 250.\n",
        "choiceone": "You show no further interest in these reports , since they do not concern the route to be flown.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Owing to these reports and taking into account the presence of heavy thunderstorms at planned FL 310 you\n select a higher flight level ( FL 370 ).\n",
        "choicethree": "You cancel the flight since the expected dangerous weather conditions along the route would demand too\n much of the passengers.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the weather briefing room during the pre-flight phase of a passenger flight from Zurich to Rome , you examine the\nfollowing weather reports of pressing importance at the time ;\n EISN SIGMET 2 VALID 140800/141100 EINNSHANNON FIR LOC SEV TURB FCST BLW FL050 S OF N53 WKN\n LIMM SIGMET 2 VALID 140900/141500 LIMMMILANO UIR MOD TO SEV CAT FCST FL250/430 STNR NC\n EGTT SIGMET 1 VALID 140800/141200 EGRBLONDON FIR/UIR EMBD TS FCST BTN N52 AND N54 E OF E002\n TOP FL300 MOV E WKN\n Which decision is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "Because of the expected turbulence you select a flight level below FL 250.\n",
        "choiceone": "You show no further interest in these reports , since they do not concern the route to be flown.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Owing to these reports and taking into account the presence of heavy thunderstorms at planned FL 310 you\n select a higher flight level ( FL 370 ).\n",
        "choicethree": "You cancel the flight since the expected dangerous weather conditions along the route would demand too\n much of the passengers.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the weather pattern behind a cold front , the visibility outside precipitation is ;\n",
        "answer": "good and the precipitation is showers.\n",
        "choiceone": "good and the precipitation is steady rain.\n",
        "choicetwo": "low and the precipitation is steady rain.\n",
        "choicethree": "low and the precipitation is showers.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In this question the wind speed with straight isobars ( vst ) , the wind speed around a high-pressure system ( vhigh ) and the\nwind speed around a low-pressure system ( vlow ) in the southern hemisphere are being compared while pressure gradient and latitude\nconstant. Which statement is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "vst < vhigh and vst > vlow.\n",
        "choiceone": "vst > vhigh and vst > vlow.\n",
        "choicetwo": "vst < vhigh and vst < vlow.\n",
        "choicethree": "vst > vhigh and vst < vlow.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In towering cumulus clouds ;\n",
        "answer": "strong updraughts occur and the temperature in the cloud is higher than in the surrounding air at the same\n height.\n",
        "choiceone": "strong updraughts occur and the temperature in the cloud is lower than in the surrounding air at the same\n height.\n",
        "choicetwo": "weak vertical air motion exists and the temperature in the cloud is lower than in the surrounding air at the\n same height.\n",
        "choicethree": "weak vertical air motion exists and the temperature in the cloud is higher than in the surrounding air at the\n same height.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In unstable air , surface visibility is most likely to be restricted by ;\n",
        "answer": "showers of rain or snow.\n",
        "choiceone": "haze.\n",
        "choicetwo": "drizzle.\n",
        "choicethree": "low stratus.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-2510A )\n Annex 050-2510A\n In what height range and at what intensity could you encounter turbulence in CAT area n\u00b02 ?\n",
        "answer": "From FL 220 to FL 400 , moderate.\n",
        "choiceone": "From below FL 130 to FL 270 , light.\n",
        "choicetwo": "From FL 240 to FL 370 , light.\n",
        "choicethree": "From FL 250 to FL 320 , moderate.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what hPa range is an upper weather chart for FL 340 situated ?\n",
        "answer": "300 - 200 hPa 500 hPa \u2192 FL180 ISA \u201321\u00b0C , 300 hPa \u2192 FL300 ISA \u201345\u00b0C ,\n",
        "choiceone": "400 - 300 hPa\n",
        "choicetwo": "600 - 500 hPa\n",
        "choicethree": "500 - 400 hPa 850 hPa \u2192 FL50 ISA +5\u00b0C , 700 hPa \u2192 FL100 ISA \u20135\u00b0C ,\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which air mass are extremely low temperatures encountered ?\n",
        "answer": "Polar continental air.\n",
        "choiceone": "Polar maritime air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Arctic maritime air.\n",
        "choicethree": "Tropical continental air.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which approximate direction does the centre of a non-occluded frontal depression move ?\n",
        "answer": "In the direction of the warm sector isobars.\n",
        "choiceone": "In the direction of the sharpest pressure increase.\n",
        "choicetwo": "In the direction of the isobars behind the cold front.\n",
        "choicethree": "In the direction of the isobars ahead of the warm front.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which areas are easterly waves most likely to form ?\n",
        "answer": "In the trade wind zone.\n",
        "choiceone": "In the subtropical high pressure belt between 20\u00ba and 35\u00ba north or south.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Just north of the prevailing westerlies.\n",
        "choicethree": "In the region of the equator between 0\u00ba and 5\u00ba north or south.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which conditions would you most likely encounter clear icing , and how would it normally appear ?\n",
        "answer": "Cumuliform clouds , large water droplets , temperatures between 0\u00baC and -15\u00baC. Appears smooth and tends\n to spread back over an aicraft wing.\n",
        "choiceone": "Stratiform clouds , small water droplets , temperatures between -10\u00baC and -20\u00baC. Appears granular and tends\n to accumulate forward into the air stream.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Stratiform clouds , large water droplets , temperatures well below freezing. Appears opaque and builds\n forward from leading surface into a sharp edge.\n",
        "choicethree": "Cumuliform clouds , small water droplets , temperatures between -20\u00baC and -25\u00baC. Appears transparent and\n tends to take the shape of the surface on which it freezes.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which environment is aircraft structural ice most likely to have the highest accumulation rate ?\n",
        "answer": "Freezing rain.\n",
        "choiceone": "Stratus clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cumulus clouds.\n",
        "choicethree": "Cirrus clouds.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which environment is aircraft structural ice most likely to have the highest rate of accretion ?\n",
        "answer": "Freezing rain.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cirrus clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Snow.\n",
        "choicethree": "Stratus clouds.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which layer is most of the atmospheric humidity concentrated ?\n",
        "answer": "Troposphere.\n",
        "choiceone": "Stratosphere.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Tropopause.\n",
        "choicethree": "Stratopause.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which main direction does a polar front depression move ?\n",
        "answer": "Along the front towards the east.\n",
        "choiceone": "Along the front towards the west.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Across the front towards the north.\n",
        "choicethree": "Across the front towards the south.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which meteorological forecast chart is information about CAT regions found ?\n",
        "answer": "Significant Weather Chart.\n",
        "choiceone": "500 hPa chart.\n",
        "choicetwo": "300 hPa chart.\n",
        "choicethree": "24 hour surface forecast.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which month does the humid monsoon in India start ?\n",
        "answer": "In June.\n",
        "choiceone": "In December.\n",
        "choicetwo": "In March.\n",
        "choicethree": "In October.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which of the areas below does the intertropical convergence zone ( ITCZ ) have a significant impact ?\n",
        "answer": "western Africa between 10\u00baN and 20\u00baN and the northern coasts of the Arabian sea in July.\n",
        "choiceone": "western Africa , at a latitude of 25\u00baN in July.\n",
        "choicetwo": "western Africa , where it is situated between the 10\u00baN and 30\u00baN parallels , depending on the time of the year.\n",
        "choicethree": "the Atlanic ocean , between latitudes 10\u00baN and 30\u00baN , depending on the time of year.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which of the following 1850 UTC METAR reports , is the probability of fog formation , in the coming night , the highest ?\n",
        "answer": "VRB01KT 8000 SCT250 11/10 Q1028 BECMG 3000 BR =\n",
        "choiceone": "22004KT 6000 -RA SCT012 OVC030 17/14 Q1009 NOSIG =\n",
        "choicetwo": "00000KT 9999 SCT300 21/01 Q1032 NOSIG =\n",
        "choicethree": "VRB02KT 2500 HZ SCT120 14/M08 Q1035 NOSIG =\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which of the following areas do surface high pressure systems usually predominate over the North Atlantic region\nbetween 30\u00b0N and 65\u00b0N and the adjoining land areas during the northern summer ?\n",
        "answer": "Azores , SE USA , SW Europe.\n",
        "choiceone": "Greenland , SW Europe , NE Canada.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Iceland , SW USA , Azores.\n",
        "choicethree": "Greenland , Azores , NE Canada.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which of the following areas is the frequency of tropical revolving storms the highest ?\n",
        "answer": "South China Sea and the Philippines area.\n",
        "choiceone": "Arabian Sea ( Sea area west of India ).\n",
        "choicetwo": "South Atlantic Ocean.\n",
        "choicethree": "Indonesia.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which of the following areas is the highest frequency of thunderstorms encountered ?\n",
        "answer": "Tropical.\n",
        "choiceone": "Temperate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Polar.\n",
        "choicethree": "Subtropical.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which of the following bands of latitude is the intertropical convergence zone most likely to be encountered in January ,\nbetween Dakar and Rio de Janeiro ?\n",
        "answer": "0\u00b0 - 7\u00b0N.\n",
        "choiceone": "8\u00b0 - 12\u00b0S.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3\u00b0 - 8\u00b0S.\n",
        "choicethree": "7\u00b0 - 12\u00b0N.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which of the following changes of state is latent heat absorbed ?\n",
        "answer": "Solid to liquid.\n",
        "choiceone": "Gas to liquid.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Liquid to solid.\n",
        "choicethree": "Gas to solid.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which of the following changes of state is latent heat absorbed ?\n",
        "answer": "Solid to gas.\n",
        "choiceone": "Gas to liquid.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Liquid to solid.\n",
        "choicethree": "Gas to solid.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which of the following changes of state is latent heat absorbed ?\n",
        "answer": "Liquid to gas.\n",
        "choiceone": "Gas to solid.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Gas to liquid.\n",
        "choicethree": "Liquid to solid.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which of the following changes of state is latent heat released ?\n",
        "answer": "Gas to liquid.\n",
        "choiceone": "Solid to liquid.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Liquid to gas.\n",
        "choicethree": "Solid to gas.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which of the following changes of state is latent heat released ?\n",
        "answer": "Liquid to solid.\n",
        "choiceone": "Solid to liquid.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Solid to gas.\n",
        "choicethree": "Liquid to gas.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which of the following changes of state is latent heat released ?\n",
        "answer": "Gas to solid.\n",
        "choiceone": "Solid to liquid.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Liquid to gas.\n",
        "choicethree": "Solid to gas.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which of the following circumstances is a SIGMET issued ?\n",
        "answer": "Severe mountain waves.\n",
        "choiceone": "Fog or a thunderstorm at an aerodrome.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A sudden change in the weather conditions contained in the METAR.\n",
        "choicethree": "Clear ice on the runways of an aerodrome.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which of the following conditions is moderate to severe airframe icing most likely to be encountered ?\n",
        "answer": "In Nimbostratus cloud.\n",
        "choiceone": "Below the freezing level in clear air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Within cloud of any type.\n",
        "choicethree": "In clear air above the freezing level.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which of the following METAR reports , is the probability of fog formation in the coming night the highest ?\n",
        "answer": "201850Z 15003KT 6000 SCT120 05/04 Q1032 BECMG 1600 BR =\n",
        "choiceone": "201850Z 25010KT 4000 RA BKN012 OVC030 12/10 Q1006 TEMPO 1500 =\n",
        "choicetwo": "201850Z 21003KT 8000 SCT250 12/m08 Q1028 NOSIG =\n",
        "choicethree": "201850Z 06018G30KT 5000 -RA OVC010 04/01 Q1024 NOSIG =\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which of the following regions does polar maritime air originate ?\n",
        "answer": "East of Greenland\n",
        "choiceone": "Black Sea\n",
        "choicetwo": "Region of British Isles\n",
        "choicethree": "Baltic Sea\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which of the following situations can freezing rain be encountered ?\n",
        "answer": "Ahead of a warm front in the winter.\n",
        "choiceone": "Behind a warm front in the summer.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Ahead of a cold front in the winter.\n",
        "choicethree": "Ahead of a cold front in the summer.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which of the following situations is an aircraft most susceptible to icing ?\n",
        "answer": "Level flight below a rain producing cloud when OAT is below zero degrees C.\n",
        "choiceone": "Level flight in snowfall below a nimbostratus layer.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Flying in dense cirrus clouds.\n",
        "choicethree": "Flying in heavy drizzle.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which of the following situations is the probability for severe thunderstorms the highest ?\n",
        "answer": "Advection of maritime cold air over a warm sea surface.\n",
        "choiceone": "Advection of continental cold air over a warm land surface.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Advection of warm air over a cold land surface.\n",
        "choicethree": "Advection of maritime warm air over a cold sea surface.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which of these cloud types can icing be virtually ruled out ?\n",
        "answer": "CI\n",
        "choiceone": "CU\n",
        "choicetwo": "SC\n",
        "choicethree": "NS\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which of these cloud types can icing be virtually ruled out ?\n",
        "answer": "CS\n",
        "choiceone": "AS\n",
        "choicetwo": "SC\n",
        "choicethree": "NS\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which of these temperature bands is ice most likely to form on the aircraft\u2019s surface ?\n",
        "answer": "0\u00b0C to \u201310\u00b0C\n",
        "choiceone": "\u201335\u00b0C to \u201350\u00b0C\n",
        "choicetwo": "+10\u00b0C to 0\u00b0C\n",
        "choicethree": "\u201320\u00b0C to \u201335\u00b0C\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which situation is advection fog most likely to form ?\n",
        "answer": "An air mass moving inland from the coast in winter.\n",
        "choiceone": "A light breeze blowing colder air out to sea.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Warm moist air settling over a warmer surface under no-wind conditions.\n",
        "choicethree": "A warm moist air mass on the windward side of the mountains.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10810A )\n Annex 050-10810A\n In which squares are conditions most likely to cause the occurrence of low level wind shear ?\n",
        "answer": "3 A and 3 C.\n",
        "choiceone": "3 B and 3 C.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 A and 3 B.\n",
        "choicethree": "3 B and 3 D.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which stage of the life cycle of a single thunderstorm cell occur both up- and downdrafts simultaneously ?\n",
        "answer": "Mature stage\n",
        "choiceone": "Cumulus stage\n",
        "choicetwo": "In all stages\n",
        "choicethree": "Dissipating stage\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which weather report would you expect to find information about icing conditions on the runway ?\n",
        "answer": "METAR\n",
        "choiceone": "GAFOR\n",
        "choicetwo": "SIGMET\n",
        "choicethree": "TAF\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which zone of a polar front jet stream is the strongest CAT to be expected ?\n",
        "answer": "On the polar air side of the core.\n",
        "choiceone": "About 12000 ft above the core.\n",
        "choicetwo": "On the tropical air side of the core.\n",
        "choicethree": "Exactly in the centre of the core.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In winter , after breaking through a low level inversion during descent and assuming the pilot does not intervene ;\n",
        "answer": "thrust most likely will increase and visibility is likely to deteriorate.\n",
        "choiceone": "lift most likely will decrease and visibility is likely to deteriorate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "thrust most likely will decrease and visibility is likely to improve.\n",
        "choicethree": "lift most likely will increase and visibility is likely to improve.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In wintertime stratus is often formed when warm maritime air moves over cold land. How can such clouds be classified ?\n",
        "answer": "Turbulence clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "Frontal clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Convective clouds.\n",
        "choicethree": "Orographic clouds.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Zurich during a summer day the following weather observations were taken ;\n 160450Z 23015KT 3000 +RA SCT008 SCT020 OVC030 13/12 Q1010 NOSIG =\n 160650Z 25008KT 6000 SCT040 BKN090 18/14 Q1010 RERA NOSIG =\n 160850Z 25006KT 8000 SCT040 SCT100 19/15 Q1009 NOSIG =\n 161050Z 24008KT 9999 SCT040 SCT100 21/15 Q1008 NOSIG =\n 161250Z 23012KT CAVOK 23/16 Q1005 NOSIG =\n 161450Z 23016KT 9999 SCT040 BKN090 24/17 Q1003 BECMG 25020G40KT TS =\n 161650Z 24018G35KT 3000 +TSRA SCT006 BKN015CB 18/16 Q1002 NOSIG =\n 161850Z 28012KT 9999 SCT030 SCT100 13/11 Q1005 NOSIG =\n What do you conclude based on these observations ?\n",
        "answer": "A warm front passed the station early in the morning and a cold front during late afternoon.\n",
        "choiceone": "Storm clouds due to warm air came close to and grazed the station.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A trough line passed the station early in the morning and a warm front during late afternoon.\n",
        "choicethree": "A cold front passed the station early in the morning and a warm front during late afternoon.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Isobars on a surface chart are lines of equal ;\n",
        "answer": "QFF\n",
        "choiceone": "QNH\n",
        "choicetwo": "QNE\n",
        "choicethree": "QFE\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Isolated thunderstorms of a local nature are generally caused by ;\n",
        "answer": "thermal triggering.\n",
        "choiceone": "frontal lifting ( warm front ).\n",
        "choicetwo": "frontal lifting ( cold front ).\n",
        "choicethree": "frontal occlusion.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Isotachs are lines joining equal ;\n",
        "answer": "wind speeds.\n",
        "choiceone": "horizontal wind speed gradients.\n",
        "choicetwo": "wind speed lapse rates.\n",
        "choicethree": "sea-level pressures.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4385A )\n Annex 050-4385A\n Judging by the chart , on which of these routes can you expect to encounter moderate CAT at FL 300 ?\n",
        "answer": "Zurich - Athens\n",
        "choiceone": "Zurich - Stockholm\n",
        "choicetwo": "Madrid - Bordeaux\n",
        "choicethree": "London - Zurich\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4384A )\n Annex 050-4384A\n Judging by the chart , what wind speeds can you expect at FL 310 above London ?\n",
        "answer": "90 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "140 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "110 km/h\n",
        "choicethree": "300 kt\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Katabatic wind is ;\n",
        "answer": "a flow of cold air down the slope of a mountain.\n",
        "choiceone": "a flow of cold air blowing from sea to land.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a flow of warm air up te slope of a hill , caused by surface heating.\n",
        "choicethree": "a flow of warm air blowing from land to sea.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Large hail stones ;\n",
        "answer": "are typically associated with severe thunderstorms.\n",
        "choiceone": "only occur in frontal thunderstorms.\n",
        "choicetwo": "are entirely composed of clear ice.\n",
        "choicethree": "only occur in thunderstorms of mid-latitudes.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Lenticular clouds in mountainous areas indicate ;\n",
        "answer": "turbulence.\n",
        "choiceone": "an inversion.\n",
        "choicetwo": "unstable air.\n",
        "choicethree": "light variable winds.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4367A )\n Look at the chart. Assuming a normal vertical temperature gradient , at what altitude will the freezing level above Shannon\nbe found ?\n",
        "answer": "FL 60\n",
        "choiceone": "FL 20\n",
        "choicetwo": "FL 120\n",
        "choicethree": "FL 140\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4379A )\n Annex 050-4379A\n Looking at the chart , at what altitude above Frankfurt would you expect the tropopause to be located ?\n",
        "answer": "FL 360\n",
        "choiceone": "FL 390\n",
        "choicetwo": "FL 410\n",
        "choicethree": "FL 330\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Low level vertical wind shear can be expected during the night ;\n",
        "answer": "in association with radiation inversions.\n",
        "choiceone": "and early morning only in summer.\n",
        "choicetwo": "in unstable atmospheres.\n",
        "choicethree": "and early morning only in winter.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Low level wind shear is likely to be greatest ;\n",
        "answer": "at the top of a marked surface-based inversion.\n",
        "choiceone": "at the top of the friction layer.\n",
        "choicetwo": "at the condensation level when there is no night radiation.\n",
        "choicethree": "at the condensation level when there is strong surface friction.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Mark the correct statement concerning lightning discharge ;\n",
        "answer": "While flying through air that is electrically charged the aircraft is likely to become a charge carrier itself and\n can initiate a lightning discharge.\n",
        "choiceone": "The probability of a lightning discharge is reciprocally proportional to the strength of the electric field the\n aircraft intruded.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The set of possible effects of a lightning discharge does not include welding of aircraft parts such as joints or\n bearings.\n",
        "choicethree": "Because an aircraft acts as a \u201cFaraday\u2019s cage\u201d , the magnetisation associated with a lightning discharge\n hardly has an effect on the magnetic compass.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Mark the correct statement concerning the flight through an inversion caused by subsidence ;\n",
        "answer": "During climb , the reduced air density above the inversion layer will cause a certain decrease in the aircraft\n peformance ( i.e. lift and thrust ) and the pilot will experience a sudden improvement of visibility.\n",
        "choiceone": "During climb , the pilot of an aircraft probably will experience a slight deterioration of flight visibility when\n breaking through the top of the inversion layer and the general aircraft performance will decrease.\n",
        "choicetwo": "During climb , the increased air density above the inversion layer will cause a certain increase in the aircraft\n performance ( i.e. lift and thrust ) and the pilot will experience a gradual change of the cross wind component\n",
        "choicethree": "The pilot of an aircraft probably will experience a gradual increase of the cross wind component and a\n gradual improvement of flight visibility when breaking through the base of the inversion layer during descent\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Mark the statement most reasonable regarding a valley inversion ;\n",
        "answer": "Over night , cool dense air as a result of radiation cooling will descend along the mountain slopes into the\n basin and lead to the development of a valley inversion.\n",
        "choiceone": "If the incident solar radiation is non-uniform because of orographic conditions , the development of a valley\n inversion is very likely during daytime.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Provided that the lee side winds are able to displace the air at the bottom of the basin , the Foehn effect is the\n predominant factor in the development of a valley inversion.\n",
        "choicethree": "Small scale density variations due to turbulent mixing ( mainly caused y the roughness of rocks ) are a\n significant prerequisite for the formation of valley inversions.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Marseille Information gives you the following meteorological information for Ajaccio and Calvi for 1600 UTC ;\n Ajaccio :\n wind 360\u00b0/2 kt , visibility 2000 m, rain , BKN stratocumulus at 1000 FT , OVC altostratus at 8000 FT , QNH 1023 hPa.\n Calvi :\n wind 040\u00b0/2 kt , visibility 3000 m , mist , FEW stratus at 500 FT , SCT stratocumulus at 2000 FT , OVC altostratus at\n 9000 FT , QNH 1023 hPa.\n The ceilings ( more than 4 oktas ) are therefore ;\n",
        "answer": "1000 FT at Ajaccio and 9000 FT at Calvi.\n",
        "choiceone": "1000 FT at Ajaccio and 500 FT at Calvi.\n",
        "choicetwo": "8000 FT at Ajaccio and 9000 FT at Calvi.\n",
        "choicethree": "1000 FT at Ajaccio and 2000 FT at Calvi.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Maximum wind speeds associated with subtropical jet streams are usually located in the ;\n",
        "answer": "tropical air below the tropopause.\n",
        "choiceone": "polar air below the tropopause.\n",
        "choicetwo": "tropical air above the tropopause.\n",
        "choicethree": "polar air above the tropopause.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Moderate to severe CAT is encountered especially in ;\n",
        "answer": "an area with strongly curved , closely packed isohypses.\n",
        "choiceone": "a CB.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the laminar part of a mountain wave.\n",
        "choicethree": "the core of a jet stream.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Most tornadoes have a life span that lasts for ;\n",
        "answer": "a few minutes up to 30 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "approximately one hour.\n",
        "choicetwo": "not more than one minute.\n",
        "choicethree": "several hours.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Most tornadoes have a speed of movement that usually ranges from ;\n",
        "answer": "20 to 40 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "30 to 70 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "120 to 180 knots.\n",
        "choicethree": "100 to 140 knots.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Mountain waves should be expected ;\n",
        "answer": "on the downwind side of the mountain chain.\n",
        "choiceone": "directly over the mountain chain.\n",
        "choicetwo": "when instability is high.\n",
        "choicethree": "on the upwind side of the mountain chain.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Occlusions are formed when ;\n",
        "answer": "cold fronts overtake warm fronts.\n",
        "choiceone": "a cold front crosses a mountain ridge.\n",
        "choicetwo": "warm fronts overtake cold fronts.\n",
        "choicethree": "a warm front crosses a mountain ridge.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-2056A )\n Annex 050-2056A\n Of the four radio soundings , select the one that indicates ground fog ;\n",
        "answer": "2\n",
        "choiceone": "4\n",
        "choicetwo": "3\n",
        "choicethree": "1\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4319A )\n Annex 050-4319A\n Of the four radio soundings , select the one that indicates low stratus ;\n",
        "answer": "3\n",
        "choiceone": "4\n",
        "choicetwo": "1\n",
        "choicethree": "2\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Of what does lenticular cloud provide evidence ?\n",
        "answer": "Mountain waves.\n",
        "choiceone": "Stratospheric inversions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Areas of high level clear air turbulence.\n",
        "choicethree": "Jet streams.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a clear sky , continental ground surface , wind calm , the minimum temperature is reached approximately ;\n",
        "answer": "half an hour after sunrise.\n",
        "choiceone": "one hour before sunrise.\n",
        "choicetwo": "at the moment the sun rises.\n",
        "choicethree": "half an hour before sunrise.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a clear summer day , turbulence caused by solar heating is most pronounced ;\n",
        "answer": "during the early afternoon.\n",
        "choiceone": "about midmorning.\n",
        "choicetwo": "during early morning hours before sunrise.\n",
        "choicethree": "immediately after sunset.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a particular day part of a polar front jet stream runs from north to south in the northern hemisphere. This means that ;\n",
        "answer": "the polar air is below and to the east of the core of the jet.\n",
        "choiceone": "above the core of the jet the horizontal temperature gradient runs from north to south.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the polar air is on the eastern side and above the core of the jet.\n",
        "choicethree": "below the core of the jet the horizontal temperature gradient runs from north to south.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a route segment from A to B the highest terrain elevation is approximately 200 feet. For an instrument flight the\nminimum obstacle clearance is 1000 feet. The subscale of the altimeter is set to the local QNH of 1013 hPa and the temperature on the\nground is \u20135\u00b0C. Assume a standard temperature lapse rate. What is the approximate minimum acceptable altimeter indication during\nthe flight on this route segment ?\n",
        "answer": "1300 feet. 20 x ( 4 / 1000 ) x 1200 = 96 ft olarak bulunur. G\u00f6sterge irtifas\u0131 da ;\n",
        "choiceone": "1000 feet. Mania m\u00fcsaadesi 1000 ft olmas\u0131 gerekti\u011fine g\u00f6re minimum True altitude 1200\n",
        "choicetwo": "1400 feet. ft olmal\u0131d\u0131r. Yerdeki s\u0131cakl\u0131k \u20135\u00b0C oldu\u011funa g\u00f6re s\u0131cakl\u0131k ISA\u2019ya g\u00f6re ;\n",
        "choicethree": "1100 feet. 15\u00b0C \u2013 ( \u20135\u00b0C ) = 20\u00b0C daha so\u011fuktur. 1200 ft in s\u0131cakl\u0131k d\u00fczeltmesi ;\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-11907A )\n Annex 050-11907A\n On a Significant Weather Chart , hail is represented by symbol ;\n",
        "answer": "4.\n",
        "choiceone": "2.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1.\n",
        "choicethree": "3.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a Significant Weather Chart , we see the following for the area where a VFR-flight will take place ;\n BKN CU SC 100 / 023\n If the flight is planned at FL 85 , we can estimate that ;\n",
        "answer": "we will probably have to divert around some cumulus tops.\n",
        "choiceone": "we will fly just below the cloud base where the cloud cover is between 5 and 7 oktas.\n",
        "choicetwo": "we will fly above a solid cloud cover.\n",
        "choicethree": "we will be in solid clouds and consequently a VFR flight is not possible.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On an aerodrome , when a warm front is approaching ;\n",
        "answer": "QFE and QNH decrease.\n",
        "choiceone": "QFE increases and QNH decreases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "QFE decreases and QNH increases.\n",
        "choicethree": "QFE and QNH increase.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On an upper wind and temperature chart ;\n",
        "answer": "the pressure is constant all over the chart.\n",
        "choiceone": "the height is constant all over the chart.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the temperature is constant all over the chart.\n",
        "choicethree": "the wind increases from south to north.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On average , going from the equator to the north pole , the altitude of the tropopause ;\n",
        "answer": "decreases and its temperature increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "increases and its temperature increases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increases and its temperature decreases.\n",
        "choicethree": "decreases and its temperature decreases.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On the approach , the surface temperature is given as \u20135\u00b0C. The freezing level is at 3000 ft/AGL. At 4000 ft/AGL , there is a\nsolid cloud layer from which rain is falling. According to the weather briefing , the clouds are due to an inversion caused by warm\nair sliding up and over an inclined front. Would you expect icing ?\n",
        "answer": "Yes , between ground level and 3000 ft/AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "No , flights clear of cloud experience no icing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Yes , but only between 3000 and 4000 ft/AGL.\n",
        "choicethree": "No , absolutely no icing will occur.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On the European continent METARs of main airports are compiled and distributed with intervals of ;\n",
        "answer": "0.5 hour.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 hour.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 hours.\n",
        "choicethree": "2 hours.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On the Significant Weather Chart , we see the following indications ;\n 060 SCT CU 100 / 060\n The forecast charts for FL 050 and FL 100 both indicate a wind from 320\u00b0/15 kt. In flight at FL 055 over an area of plains\n( flat country ) during the validity period of the Significant Weather Chart , we observe moderate turbulence. This turbulence is\ncaused by ;\n",
        "answer": "the instability of the air mass between the surface and the top of Cumulus clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "a wind shear.\n",
        "choicetwo": "system waves.\n",
        "choicethree": "the surface radiation.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On the West coast of India it can be said in general that the wind blows ;\n",
        "answer": "for six month from the North East and for six month from the South West.\n",
        "choiceone": "the whole year from the South East.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the whole year from the North East.\n",
        "choicethree": "for six month from the North West and for six month from the South East.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On which coast of North America , is the danger of tropical revolving storms the greatest ?\n",
        "answer": "SE coast.\n",
        "choiceone": "W coast.\n",
        "choicetwo": "N coast.\n",
        "choicethree": "NE coast.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On which latitudes can the coriolis force in practice be neglected for meteorological purposes ?\n",
        "answer": "From 0 to about 10 degrees north and south.\n",
        "choiceone": "From about 30 to about 75 degrees north and south.\n",
        "choicetwo": "From about 75 to 90 degrees north and south.\n",
        "choicethree": "From about 10 to about 30 degrees north and south.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On which of the following aviation weather charts can a pilot most easily find a jetstream ?\n",
        "answer": "Significant weather chart.\n",
        "choiceone": "Surface chart.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Upper air chart.\n",
        "choicethree": "Wind / temperature chart.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4378A )\n Annex 050-4378A\n On which of the following routes can you expect icing to occur , on the basis of the chart ?\n",
        "answer": "Hamburg - Oslo\n",
        "choiceone": "Tunis - Rome\n",
        "choicetwo": "Copenhagen - Helsinki\n",
        "choicethree": "Rome - Frankfurt\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4388A )\n Annex 050-4388A\n On which of these routes would you not need to worry about icing at FL 170 ?\n",
        "answer": "London - Stockholm\n",
        "choiceone": "Paris - Lisbon\n",
        "choicetwo": "Madrid - Vienna\n",
        "choicethree": "Zurich - Athens\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On which side of an easterly wave are thunderstorms most likely to develop ?\n",
        "answer": "On the east side of the wave.\n",
        "choiceone": "On the west side of the wave.\n",
        "choicetwo": "On the south side of the wave.\n",
        "choicethree": "On the north side of the wave.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "One of the main reasons for radiation fog to dissipate or become low stratus is ;\n",
        "answer": "surface heating.\n",
        "choiceone": "decreasing wind speed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "lifting against the slope of a hill.\n",
        "choicethree": "surface cooling.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Orographic thunderstorms may occur ;\n",
        "answer": "at any time during day and night.\n",
        "choiceone": "mostly between sunset and 2 a.m.\n",
        "choicetwo": "mostly in the early morning.\n",
        "choicethree": "almost exclusively during the daylight hours.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-2555A )\n Annex 050-2555A\n Over Amsterdam , what amount and general type of cloud would you expect at FL 160 ?\n",
        "answer": "Mainly 5 to 8 oktas of stratiform cloud in layers.\n",
        "choiceone": "5 to 7 oktas towering cumuliform cloud and with moderate turbulence.\n",
        "choicetwo": "4 oktas broken cumulus.\n",
        "choicethree": "Isolated cumulonimbus only.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Over Central Europe what type of cloud cover is typical of the warm sector of a depression during winter ?\n",
        "answer": "ST.\n",
        "choiceone": "Fair weather CU.\n",
        "choicetwo": "CI , CS.\n",
        "choicethree": "CU , CB.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-2493A )\n Annex 050-2493A\n Over Madrid , what intensity of turbulence and icing is forecast at FL 200 ?\n",
        "answer": "Moderate turbulence , moderate icing.\n",
        "choiceone": "Moderate turbulence , light icing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Severe turbulence , severe icing.\n",
        "choicethree": "Severe turbulence , moderate icing.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-2503A )\n Annex 050-2503A\n Over Paris at what height would you expect to find the tropopause according to the map ?\n",
        "answer": "FL 300\n",
        "choiceone": "FL 330\n",
        "choicetwo": "FL 150\n",
        "choicethree": "FL 280\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Over the Indian Ocean and the Bay of Bengal tropical cyclones are ;\n",
        "answer": "occasionally observed , in the average 12 per year.\n",
        "choiceone": "frequently observed , in the average 15 per year over the Indian Ocean , but never over the Bay of Bengal.\n",
        "choicetwo": "never observed.\n",
        "choicethree": "rare , in the average one every two years.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Over which areas can tropical revolving storms occur ?\n",
        "answer": "Caribbean Sea , Gulf of Bengal , Indian Ocean east of Madagascar.\n",
        "choiceone": "Australia , Gulf of Bengal , Atlantic Ocean at 20\u00b0S.\n",
        "choicetwo": "India , Arabic Sea , Atlantic Ocean at 2\u00b0S.\n",
        "choicethree": "Caribbean Sea , Indian Ocean at 20\u00b0S , Pacific Ocean at 2\u00b0N.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Precipitation in the form of showers occurs from ;\n",
        "answer": "convective clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "clouds containing only ice crystals.\n",
        "choicetwo": "stratified clouds.\n",
        "choicethree": "cirro-type clouds.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Pressure altitude is obtained by ;\n",
        "answer": "setting the altimeter to standard sea level pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "correcting the altimeter for temperature deviation from ISA.\n",
        "choicetwo": "setting the altimeter to a station pressure which has been corrected to sea level.\n",
        "choicethree": "setting the altimeter to QFF pressure.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "QNH is defined as ;\n",
        "answer": "QFE reduced to MSL using the values of the standard atmosphere.\n",
        "choiceone": "QFE reduced to MSL using the values of the actual atmosphere.\n",
        "choicetwo": "pressure at MSL in the actual atmosphere.\n",
        "choicethree": "pressure at MSL in the standard atmosphere.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Radiation fog most frequently occurs in ;\n",
        "answer": "high pressure systems over land.\n",
        "choiceone": "high pressure systems over sea.\n",
        "choicetwo": "low pressure systems over sea.\n",
        "choicethree": "low pressure systems over land.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Read this description ;\n \u201cAfter such a fine day , the ring around the moon was a bad sign yesterday evening for the weather today. And , sure enough\n, it is pouring down outside. The clouds are making an oppressively low ceiling of uniform grey , but at least it has become a little bit\nwarmer\u201d. Which of these weather phenomena is being described ?\n",
        "answer": "A warm front.\n",
        "choiceone": "A blizzard.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Weather at the back of a cold front.\n",
        "choicethree": "A cold front.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Refer to the following TAF extract ;\n BECMG 1821 2000 BR BKN004 BECMG 2124 0500 FG VV001\n What does the abbreviation \u201cBKN004\u201d mean ?\n",
        "answer": "5 - 7 oktas , ceiling 400 ft.\n",
        "choiceone": "4 - 8 oktas , ceiling 400 m.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 - 4 oktas , ceiling 400 m.\n",
        "choicethree": "1 - 4 oktas , ceiling 400 ft.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Refer to the following TAF extract ;\n BECMG 1821 2000 BR BKN004 BECMG 2124 0500 FG VV001\n What does the abbreviation \u201cVV001\u201d mean ?\n",
        "answer": "Vertical visibility 100 ft.\n",
        "choiceone": "RVR less than 100 m.\n",
        "choicetwo": "RVR greater than 100 m.\n",
        "choicethree": "Vertical visibility 100 m.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Refer to the following TAF extract ;\n BECMG 1821 2000 BR BKN004 BECMG 2124 0500 FG VV001\n What does the \u201cBECMG\u201d data indicate for the 18 to 21 hour time frame ?\n",
        "answer": "The new conditions are achieved between 1800 and 2100 UTC.\n",
        "choiceone": "Many long term changes in the original weather.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Many short term changes in the original weather.\n",
        "choicethree": "A quick change to new conditions between 1800 and 1900 UTC.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Refer to the following TAF extract ;\n BECMG 1821 2000 BR BKN004 BECMG 2124 0500 FG VV001\n What visibility is forecast for 2400 UTC ?\n",
        "answer": "500 m.\n",
        "choiceone": "2000 m.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Between 0 m and 1000 m.\n",
        "choicethree": "Between 500 m and 2000 m.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Refer to the following TAF extract ;\n BECMG 1821 2000 BR BKN004 PROB30 TEMPO 2124 0500 FG VV001\n What does the abbreviation \u201cPROB30\u201d mean ?\n",
        "answer": "Probability of 30%.\n",
        "choiceone": "Change expected in less than 30 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Conditions will last for at least 30 minutes.\n",
        "choicethree": "The cloud ceiling should lift to 3000 ft.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Refer to the following TAF message ;\n LFXX 180800Z 180918 22020KT 6000 SCT015 SCT080 BECMG 1214 24025KT 2000 RA BKN009 OVC070 =\n At 1400 UTC , the lowest cloud base will be ;\n",
        "answer": "at 900 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "between 900 and 1500 feet AMSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "between 900 and 1500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choicethree": "at 1500 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Relative humidity ;\n",
        "answer": "changes when water vapour is added , even though the temperature remains constant.\n",
        "choiceone": "does not change when water vapour is added provided the temperature of the air remains constant.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is not affected by temperature changes of the air.\n",
        "choicethree": "is not affected when air is ascending or descending.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Relative humidity ;\n",
        "answer": "increases if the air is cooled whilst maintaining the vapour pressure constant.\n",
        "choiceone": "decreases if the air is cooled whilst maintaining the vapour pressure constant.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is higher in warm air than in cool air.\n",
        "choicethree": "is higher in cool air than in warm air.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Relative humidity at a given temperature is the relation between ;\n",
        "answer": "actual water vapour content and saturated water vapour content.\n",
        "choiceone": "water vapour weight and humid air volume.\n",
        "choicetwo": "water vapour weight and dry air weight.\n",
        "choicethree": "dew point and air temperature.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Relative humidity depends on ;\n",
        "answer": "moisture content and temperature of the air.\n",
        "choiceone": "moisture content of the air only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "moisture content and pressure of the air.\n",
        "choicethree": "temperature of the air only.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Rime ice forms through the freezing onto aircraft surfaces of ;\n",
        "answer": "small supercooled water drops.\n",
        "choiceone": "snow.\n",
        "choicetwo": "large supercooled water drops.\n",
        "choicethree": "water vapour.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Rising air cools because ;\n",
        "answer": "it expands.\n",
        "choiceone": "surrounding air is cooler at higher levels.\n",
        "choicetwo": "it becomes more moist.\n",
        "choicethree": "it contracts.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Runway visual range can be reported in ;\n",
        "answer": "a METAR.\n",
        "choiceone": "a TAF.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a SIGMET.\n",
        "choicethree": "both a TAF and a METAR.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Runway visual range is calculated from values derived from ;\n",
        "answer": "transmissometers.\n",
        "choiceone": "anemometers.\n",
        "choicetwo": "psychrometers.\n",
        "choicethree": "ceilometers.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Runway visual range is calculated from values derived from ;\n",
        "answer": "forward-scatter meters.\n",
        "choiceone": "psychrometers.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ceilometers.\n",
        "choicethree": "pluviometers.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Runway Visual Range ( RVR ) is ;\n",
        "answer": "usually better than visibility.\n",
        "choiceone": "measured with ceilometers alongside the runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "reported when visibility is less than 2000 m.\n",
        "choicethree": "reported in AIRMET and METAR.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Sea breezes are most likely to occur when ;\n",
        "answer": "slack pressure gradient and clear skies result in relatively high land temperatures.\n",
        "choiceone": "a slack pressure gradient , relatively high sea temperatures and overcast conditions persist.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a strong pressure gradient , relatively high sea temperatures and overcast conditions persist.\n",
        "choicethree": "a strong pressure gradient , relatively high sea temperatures and clear skies at night exist.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4371A rev. 10.11.2002 )\n Annex 050-4371A\n Select from the map the average temperature for the route Athens - Geneva at FL 150.\n",
        "answer": "\u201314\u00b0C\n",
        "choiceone": "\u201311\u00b0C\n",
        "choicetwo": "\u201321\u00b0C\n",
        "choicethree": "\u201327\u00b0C\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4375A rev. 10.11.2002 )\n Annex 050-4375A\n Select from the map the average temperature for the route Geneva -Stockholm at FL 260.\n",
        "answer": "\u201347\u00b0C\n",
        "choiceone": "\u201355\u00b0C\n",
        "choicetwo": "\u201363\u00b0C\n",
        "choicethree": "\u201351\u00b0C\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4375A )\n Annex 050-4375A\n Select from the map the average temperature for the route Zurich - Lisboa at FL 200.\n",
        "answer": "\u201333\u00b0C\n",
        "choiceone": "\u201330\u00b0C\n",
        "choicetwo": "\u201341\u00b0C\n",
        "choicethree": "\u201349\u00b0C\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4365A )\n Annex 050-4365A\n Select from the map the average temperature for the route Zurich - Rome at FL 110.\n",
        "answer": "\u20139\u00b0C\n",
        "choiceone": "\u201312\u00b0C\n",
        "choicetwo": "+5\u00b0C\n",
        "choicethree": "\u20136\u00b0C\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4371A rev. 10.11.2002 )\n Annex 050-4371A\n Select from the map the average wind for the route Athens - Geneva at FL 160.\n",
        "answer": "240/40\n",
        "choiceone": "210/25\n",
        "choicetwo": "260/40\n",
        "choicethree": "050/35\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4368A rev. 10.11.2002 )\n Annex 050-4368A\n Select from the map the average wind for the route Frankfurt - Rome at FL 170.\n",
        "answer": "230/40\n",
        "choiceone": "030/35\n",
        "choicetwo": "200/50\n",
        "choicethree": "050/40\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4376A rev. 10.11.2002 )\n Annex 050-4376A\n Select from the map the average wind for the route Shannon - Lisboa at FL 290.\n",
        "answer": "360/80\n",
        "choiceone": "340/90\n",
        "choicetwo": "030/70\n",
        "choicethree": "190/75\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4374A )\n Annex 050-4374A\n Select from the map the average wind for the route Zurich - Hamburg at FL 240.\n",
        "answer": "230/20\n",
        "choiceone": "200/15\n",
        "choicetwo": "260/25\n",
        "choicethree": "020/20\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4365A )\n Annex 050-4365A\n Select from the map the average wind for the route Zurich - Rome at FL110.\n",
        "answer": "230/10\n",
        "choiceone": "250/20\n",
        "choicetwo": "200/30\n",
        "choicethree": "040/10\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-2522A )\n Annex 050-2522A\n Select from the map the wind for the route Zurich - London at FL 280 ;\n",
        "answer": "220/60\n",
        "choiceone": "040/60\n",
        "choicetwo": "160/90\n",
        "choicethree": "250/80\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Select the answer which you consider will complete correctly the following statement in relation to the main pressure\nsystems affecting the North Atlantic region between 30\u00b0N and 65\u00b0N. During winter the predominant mean low pressure system at the\nsurface is usually centred over ;\n",
        "answer": "Iceland / Greenland.\n",
        "choiceone": "USA.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Azores.\n",
        "choicethree": "Siberia.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Select the true statement concerning isobars and wind flow patterns around highand low-pressure systems that are shown on\na surface weather chart.\n",
        "answer": "When the isobars are close together , the pressure gradient force is greater and wind velocities are stronger.\n",
        "choiceone": "Isobars connect contour lines of equal temperature.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Surface winds flow perpendicular to the isobars.\n",
        "choicethree": "When the isobars are far apart , crest of standing waves may be marked by stationary lenticular clouds.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "SIGMET information is issued as a warning for significant weather to ;\n",
        "answer": "all aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "VFR operations only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "heavy aircraft only.\n",
        "choicethree": "light aircraft only.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Snow grains ;\n",
        "answer": "fall from stratus or supercooled fog.\n",
        "choiceone": "are typically formed inside a CB , where they are being tossed up and down while growing to such size that\n they could no longer be supported in the updraught.\n",
        "choicetwo": "are mainly formed inside altostratus and nimbostratus.\n",
        "choicethree": "are normally transparent.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Solid precipitation which is transparent or translucent and has a diameter of 5 mm or less formed by the freezing of raindrops\nor refreezing of melted snow , and usually bounces off hard surfaces , is a description of ;\n",
        "answer": "ice pellets.\n",
        "choiceone": "snow grains.\n",
        "choicetwo": "small hail.\n",
        "choicethree": "hail.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Steady precipitation , in contrast to showery precipitation falls from ;\n",
        "answer": "stratiform clouds with little or no turbulence.\n",
        "choiceone": "convective clouds with little or no turbulence.\n",
        "choicetwo": "convective clouds with moderate turbulence.\n",
        "choicethree": "stratiform clouds with severe turbulence.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Steaming fog ( arctic sea smoke ) occurs in air ;\n",
        "answer": "with cold mass properties.\n",
        "choiceone": "with warm mass properties.\n",
        "choicetwo": "that is absolutely stable.\n",
        "choicethree": "that is stable.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Stratus formed by turbulence will occur when ;\n",
        "answer": "in the friction layer mixing occurs by turbulence and the condensation level is situated below the top of the\n turbulent layer.\n",
        "choiceone": "the wind speed is greater than 10 kt and the condensation level is situated just above the turbulent layer.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the wind speed is less than 10 kt and the air is heated by the earth\u2019s surface.\n",
        "choicethree": "absolute instability exists at low level.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Strongest clear air turbulence is to be expected ;\n",
        "answer": "on the cold air side of the jet stream core.\n",
        "choiceone": "about 10.000 ft above the jet stream core.\n",
        "choicetwo": "on the warm air side of the jet stream core.\n",
        "choicethree": "in the jet stream core.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Strongly developed cumulus clouds are an indication of ;\n",
        "answer": "instability in the atmosphere.\n",
        "choiceone": "the presence of warm air aloft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the presence of a low level inversion.\n",
        "choicethree": "poor surface visibility.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Subsidence is ;\n",
        "answer": "vertically downwards motion of air.\n",
        "choiceone": "the same as convection.\n",
        "choicetwo": "horizontal motion of air.\n",
        "choicethree": "vertically upwards motion of air.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Supercooled droplets are always ;\n",
        "answer": "at a temperature below freezing.\n",
        "choiceone": "small and at a temperature below freezing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "at a temperature below -60\u00b0C.\n",
        "choicethree": "large and at a temperature below freezing.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Supercooled droplets can be encountered ;\n",
        "answer": "at any time of the year.\n",
        "choiceone": "only in winter at high altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "only in winter above 10.000 ft.\n",
        "choicethree": "in winter only in high clouds.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Supercooled droplets can occur in ;\n",
        "answer": "clouds , fog and precipitation.\n",
        "choiceone": "precipitation but not in clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "clouds but not in precipitation.\n",
        "choicethree": "clouds but not in fog.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Surface-based temperature inversions are common during ;\n",
        "answer": "cloud-free nights in winter when the ground is dry.\n",
        "choiceone": "cloudy days in summer when the ground is wet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "cloudy days in winter when the ground is wet.\n",
        "choicethree": "cloud-free days in summer when the ground is dry.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Surface temperature inversions are frequently generated by ;\n",
        "answer": "terrestrial radiation on a calm clear night.\n",
        "choiceone": "an unstable air mass causing convection currents and mixing of the atmosphere at lower levels.\n",
        "choicetwo": "gusting winds increasing surface friction during the day with consequent mixing at the lower levels.\n",
        "choicethree": "compression causing the release of latent heat in a layer of stratiform cloud.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "TAF EHAM 142300Z 150009 33005KT 9999 SCT025 BKN100 BECMG 0002 27015KT 4500 -SN SCT008 OVC015\n TEMPO 0206 0400 +SN VV002 BECMG 0406 01008KT 9999 NSW SCT030 TEMPO 0709 03015G25KT 1200 SNSH\n SCT006 SCT015CB =\n What is the expected visibility at 0300 UTC ?\n",
        "answer": "Between 400 m and 4500 m.\n",
        "choiceone": "Between 400 m and 10 km or more.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Between 4500 m and 10 km or more.\n",
        "choicethree": "4500 m.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "TAF LSZH 250600Z 250716 00000KT 0100 FG VV001 BECMG 0810 0800 VV002 BECMG 1012 23005KT 2500 BR\n BKN005 TEMPO 1316 6000 SCT007 =\n Which of these statements best describes the weather that can be expected at 1200 UTC ?\n",
        "answer": "Visibility 2.5 kilometres , mist , cloud base 500 feet , wind speed 5 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "Visibility 6 kilometres , cloud base 500 feet , wind speed 5 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Visibility 800 metres , fog , vertical visibility 200 feet , calm.\n",
        "choicethree": "Visibility 800 metres , fog, wind from 230\u00b0 , cloud base 500 feet.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "TAF LSZH 250716 00000KT 0100 FG VV001 BECMG 0810 0800 VV002 BECMG 1012 23005KT 2500 BKN005\n TEMPO 1316 6000 SCT007 =\n Which of these statements best describes the weather that can be expected at 1200 UTC ?\n",
        "answer": "Visibility 2.5 kilometres , cloud base 500 feet , wind speed 5 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "Visibility 800 metres , wind from 230\u00ba , cloud base 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Visibility 6 kilometres , cloud base 500 feet , wind speed 5 knots.\n",
        "choicethree": "Visibility 800 metres , vertical visibility 200 feet , calm.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The 0\u00b0 isotherm is forecast to be at FL 50. At what FL would you expect a temperature of \u20136\u00b0 C ?\n",
        "answer": "FL 80\n",
        "choiceone": "FL 20\n",
        "choicetwo": "FL 100\n",
        "choicethree": "FL 110\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10748A )\n Annex 050-10748A\n The air mass affecting position \u201cA\u201d is most likely to be ;\n",
        "answer": "Polar Maritime.\n",
        "choiceone": "Polar Continental.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Tropical Continental.\n",
        "choicethree": "Tropical Maritime.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10751A )\n Annex 050-10751A\n The air mass affecting position \u201cP\u201d is most likely to be ;\n",
        "answer": "Polar Continental.\n",
        "choiceone": "Tropical Continental.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Tropical Maritime.\n",
        "choicethree": "Polar Maritime.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10752A )\n Annex 050-10752A\n The air mass affecting position \u201cR\u201d is most likely to be ;\n",
        "answer": "Tropical Continental.\n",
        "choiceone": "Polar Maritime.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Tropical Maritime.\n",
        "choicethree": "Polar Continental.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10843A )\n Annex 050-10843A\n The air mass affecting position \u201cR\u201d is most likely to be ;\n",
        "answer": "Polar Maritime.\n",
        "choiceone": "Tropical Continental.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Tropical Maritime.\n",
        "choicethree": "Polar Continental.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10750A )\n Annex 050-10750A\n The air mass affecting position \u201cS\u201d is most likely to be ;\n",
        "answer": "Tropical Maritime and stable.\n",
        "choiceone": "Tropical Continental and unstable.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Polar Maritime and stable.\n",
        "choicethree": "Polar Maritime and unstable.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10839A )\n Annex 050-10839A\n The air mass at position \u201cX\u201d is most likely to be ;\n",
        "answer": "Tropical Maritime.\n",
        "choiceone": "Tropical Continental.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Polar Maritime.\n",
        "choicethree": "Polar Continental.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The air mass in the warm sector of a polar front is ;\n",
        "answer": "tropical air.\n",
        "choiceone": "arctic air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "polar air.\n",
        "choicethree": "equatorial air.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10842A )\n Annex 050-10842A\n The air mass type advected from a direction indicated by arrow number 6 is designated ;\n",
        "answer": "maritime polar.\n",
        "choiceone": "maritime arctic.\n",
        "choicetwo": "continental polar.\n",
        "choicethree": "continental arctic.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10842A )\n Annex 050-10842A\n The air mass type indicated by arrow number 4 is designated ;\n",
        "answer": "Tropical Maritime.\n",
        "choiceone": "Polar Maritime.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Polar Continental.\n",
        "choicethree": "Tropical Continental.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The air masses that are observed most frequently over western Europe are ;\n",
        "answer": "polar air and tropical air.\n",
        "choiceone": "arctic air and tropical air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "polar air and equatorial air.\n",
        "choicethree": "arctic air and polar air.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The amount of water vapour which air can hold largely depends on ;\n",
        "answer": "air temperature.\n",
        "choiceone": "relative humidity.\n",
        "choicetwo": "stability of air.\n",
        "choicethree": "the dew point.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The approximate inclined plane of a warm front is ;\n",
        "answer": "1/150.\n",
        "choiceone": "1/300.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1/50.\n",
        "choicethree": "1/500.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The arctic front is the boundary between ;\n",
        "answer": "polar air and arctic air.\n",
        "choiceone": "arctic air and tropical air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "cold polar air and less cold polar air.\n",
        "choicethree": "polar air and tropical air.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10788A )\n Annex 050-10788A\n The arrows labelled \u201cr\u201d represent the mean tracks of tropical revolving storms which occur mainly from ;\n",
        "answer": "December to April and are called cyclones.\n",
        "choiceone": "June to October and are called hurricanes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "December to April and are called tornadoes.\n",
        "choicethree": "June to October and are called typhoons.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10788A )\n Annex 050-10788A\n The arrows labelled \u201cs\u201d represent the mean tracks of tropical revolving storms which occur mainly from ;\n",
        "answer": "May to November and are called cyclones.\n",
        "choiceone": "May to November and are called hurricanes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "December to April and are called typhoons.\n",
        "choicethree": "December to April and are called cyclones.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10788A )\n Annex 050-10788A\n The arrows labelled \u201ct\u201d represents the mean tracks of tropical revolving storms which occur mainly from ;\n",
        "answer": "June to October and are called cyclones.\n",
        "choiceone": "June to October and are called hurricanes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "December to April and are called hurricanes.\n",
        "choicethree": "June to October and are called tornadoes.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10788A )\n Annex 050-10788A\n The arrows labelled \u201cu\u201d represent the tracks of tropical revolving storms which occur mainly from ;\n",
        "answer": "July to October and are called typhoons.\n",
        "choiceone": "January to March and are called willy-willies.\n",
        "choicetwo": "December to April and are called tornadoes.\n",
        "choicethree": "May to July and are called cyclones.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10788A )\n Annex 050-10788A\n The arrows labelled \u201cv\u201d represent the mean tracks of tropical revolving storms which occur mainly from ;\n",
        "answer": "December to April and are called cyclones.\n",
        "choiceone": "May to November and are called typhoons.\n",
        "choicetwo": "December to April and are called hurricanes.\n",
        "choicethree": "May to November and are called Willy Willys.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4393A )\n Annex 050-4393A\n The attached chart shows isobars and fronts at 1200 UTC on October 10. Which of the following reports reflects weather\ndevelopment at Zurich Airport ( LSZH ) ?\n",
        "answer": "TAF LSZH 101500Z 101601 VRB02KT 8000 SCT280 BECMG 1618 00000KT 3500 MIFG BECMG 1820\n 1500 BCFG BECMG 2022 0100 FG VV001 =\n",
        "choiceone": "TAF LSZH 101500Z 101601 23012KT 6000 RA BKN012 OVC030 TEMPO 2023 22025G40KT 1600\n +SNRA BKN003 OVC015 =\n",
        "choicetwo": "TAF LSZH 101500Z 101601 32008KT 9999 SCT030TCU TEMPO 2201 32020G32KT 3000 TSRA\n BKN020CB =\n",
        "choicethree": "TAF LSZH 101500Z 101601 05020G35KT 8000 BKN015 TEMPO 1720 05018KT 0300 +SHSN VV002 =\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10900A )\n Annex 050-10900A\n The average forecast wind for the leg from Madrid to Dhahran at FL 390 is ;\n",
        "answer": "270/50.\n",
        "choiceone": "310/50.\n",
        "choicetwo": "320/70.\n",
        "choicethree": "270/30.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The average height of the tropopause at 50\u00b0N is about ;\n",
        "answer": "11 km.\n",
        "choiceone": "14 km.\n",
        "choicetwo": "16 km.\n",
        "choicethree": "8 km.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The average position of the polar front in the northern hemisphere is ;\n",
        "answer": "more southerly during the winter than during the summer.\n",
        "choiceone": "located near 65\u00baN during the whole year.\n",
        "choicetwo": "located near 55\u00baN during the whole year.\n",
        "choicethree": "more southerly during the summer than during the winter.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The average slope of a cold front is in the order of ;\n",
        "answer": "1:80\n",
        "choiceone": "1:500\n",
        "choicetwo": "1:800\n",
        "choicethree": "1:10\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The average thickness of the troposphere varies with ;\n",
        "answer": "latitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "rotation of the earth.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the wind.\n",
        "choicethree": "longitude.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The barometric compensator of an altimeter is locked on reference 1013.2 hPa. The aircraft has to land on a point with an\nelevation of 290 feet where the QNH is 1023 hPa. The reading on the altimeter on the ground will be ;\n",
        "answer": "20 ft.\n 1023 \u2013 1013 = 10 hPa , 1 hPa\u2019\u0131 27 ft olarak de\u011ferlendirirsek ;\n",
        "choiceone": "11 ft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "560 ft.\n 10 x 27 = 270 ft , altimetre meydan rak\u0131m\u0131na g\u00f6re daha d\u00fc\u015f\u00fck bir\n",
        "choicethree": "\u201310 ft.\n de\u011fer g\u00f6sterecektir ; 290 \u2013 270 = 20 ft.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Bora is a ;\n",
        "answer": "cold catabatic wind with the possibility of violent gusts.\n",
        "choiceone": "cold catabatic wind with gusts associated with a maritime air mass.\n",
        "choicetwo": "cold catabatic wind always associated with clouds and heavy showers.\n",
        "choicethree": "squally warm catabatic wind which occurs mainly in summer.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Chinook is a ;\n",
        "answer": "warm and dry wind that forms as air descends on the leeward side of the Rocky Mountains.\n",
        "choiceone": "warm anabatic wind up the slopes of snowfields or glaciers.\n",
        "choicetwo": "downslope wind that occurs particularly at night as air cools along mountain slopes.\n",
        "choicethree": "very cold wind with blowing snow.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The cloud base , reported in the METAR , is the height above ;\n",
        "answer": "airfield level.\n",
        "choiceone": "the highest terrain within a radius of 8 km from the observation station.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the pressure altitude of the observation station at the time of observation.\n",
        "choicethree": "mean sea level.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10758A )\n CI\n Annex 050-10758A\n The cloud most likely to be experienced in square 1E is ;\n",
        "answer": "CI\n",
        "choiceone": "CS\n",
        "choicetwo": "CB\n",
        "choicethree": "AS\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10768A )\n SC\n Annex 050-10768A\n The cloud type most applicable to most of square 3B is ;\n",
        "answer": "SC\n",
        "choiceone": "NS\n",
        "choicetwo": "AS\n",
        "choicethree": "CS\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10777A )\n CS\n Annex 050-10777A\n The cloud type most applicable to square 1E is ;\n",
        "answer": "CS\n",
        "choiceone": "CB\n",
        "choicetwo": "SC\n",
        "choicethree": "NS\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 5 )\n CI\n Image 5\n The cloud type most applicable to square 1E is ;\n",
        "answer": "CI\n",
        "choiceone": "CB\n",
        "choicetwo": "AC\n",
        "choicethree": "AS\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10779A )\n CB\n Annex 050-10779A\n The cloud type most applicable to square 2B is ;\n",
        "answer": "CB\n",
        "choiceone": "SC\n",
        "choicetwo": "CS\n",
        "choicethree": "ST\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10778A )\n AS\n Annex 050-10778A\n The cloud type most applicable to square 2C is ;\n",
        "answer": "AS\n",
        "choiceone": "CS\n",
        "choicetwo": "CB\n",
        "choicethree": "CU\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10759A )\n AS\n Annex 050-10759A\n The cloud type most applicable to square 2D is ;\n",
        "answer": "AS\n",
        "choiceone": "CS\n",
        "choicetwo": "CU\n",
        "choicethree": "CB\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10760A )\n NS\n Annex 050-10760A\n The cloud type most applicable to square 3C is ;\n",
        "answer": "NS\n",
        "choiceone": "AS\n",
        "choicetwo": "AC\n",
        "choicethree": "CB\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-2055A rev. 20.01.2003 )\n Annex 050-2055A\n The cold front is indicated with a number at position ;\n",
        "answer": "number 2.\n",
        "choiceone": "number 3.\n",
        "choicetwo": "number 1.\n",
        "choicethree": "number 4.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The conditions most favourable to the formation of mountain waves are ;\n",
        "answer": "wind direction approximately at right angles to the mountain range - wind speed 30 kt and steadily increasing\n with height - an inversion just above the crest level with less stable air above and below.\n",
        "choiceone": "wind direction parallel to the general alignment of the mountain range - wind speed increasing with height -\n intense surface heating.\n",
        "choicetwo": "wind speed less than 15 kt and wind direction at right angles to mountains - intense radiation cooling at night\n particularly at the higher levels.\n",
        "choicethree": "wind direction parallel to the mountain range - wind speed increasing with height - extensive isothermal layer\n between mountain crests and the tropopause.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The core of the polar front jet stream is usually located in the ;\n",
        "answer": "tropical air below the tropopause.\n",
        "choiceone": "polar air above the tropopause.\n",
        "choicetwo": "polar air below the tropopause.\n",
        "choicethree": "tropical air above the tropical tropopause.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The decrease in temperature , per 100 metres , in a saturated rising parcel of air at lower level of the atmosphere is\napproximately ;\n",
        "answer": "0.6\u00b0C\n",
        "choiceone": "1\u00b0C\n",
        "choicetwo": "0.35\u00b0C\n",
        "choicethree": "1.5\u00b0C\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The decrease in temperature , per 100 metres , in an unsaturated rising parcel of air is ;\n",
        "answer": "1\u00b0C\n",
        "choiceone": "0.65\u00b0C\n",
        "choicetwo": "0.5\u00b0C\n",
        "choicethree": "2\u00b0C\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The degree of clear air turbulence experienced by an aircraft is proportional to the ;\n",
        "answer": "intensity of vertical and horizontal wind shear.\n",
        "choiceone": "height of the aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "stability of the air.\n",
        "choicethree": "intensity of the solar radiation.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The dewpoint temperature ;\n",
        "answer": "can be equal to the air temperature.\n",
        "choiceone": "can not be equal to the air temperature.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is always higher than the air temperature.\n",
        "choicethree": "is always lower than the air temperature.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The dewpoint temperature ;\n",
        "answer": "can be reached by cooling the air whilst keeping pressure constant.\n",
        "choiceone": "can be reached by lowering the pressure whilst keeping temperature constant.\n",
        "choicetwo": "can not be lower than the air temperature.\n",
        "choicethree": "can not be equal to the air temperature.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-11897A )\n Annex 050-11897A\n The diagram of the system in annex represents a ;\n",
        "answer": "warm occlusion.\n",
        "choiceone": "cold occlusion.\n",
        "choicetwo": "warm front.\n",
        "choicethree": "cold front.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The diameter of a typical tornado is ;\n",
        "answer": "100 to 150 metres.\n",
        "choiceone": "in the order of 10 km.\n",
        "choicetwo": "about 2 to 6 km.\n",
        "choicethree": "only a few metres.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The difference between geostrophic wind and gradient wind is caused by ;\n",
        "answer": "curvature of isobars.\n",
        "choiceone": "friction.\n",
        "choicetwo": "slope of pressure surfaces.\n",
        "choicethree": "horizontal temperature gradients.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The diurnal variation in temperature is largest when ;\n",
        "answer": "the sky is clear and the wind is weak.\n",
        "choiceone": "the sky is overcast and the wind is weak.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the sky is overcast and the wind is strong.\n",
        "choicethree": "the sky is clear and the wind is strong.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10788A )\n Annex 050-10788A\n The dotted line labelled \u201cY\u201d represents the ;\n",
        "answer": "mean position of the intertropical convergence zone ( ITCZ ) during January.\n",
        "choiceone": "axis of the equatorial jet stream during July.\n",
        "choicetwo": "axis of the subtropical jet stream during January.\n",
        "choicethree": "mean position of the intertropical convergence zone ( ITCZ ) during July.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10788A )\n Annex 050-10788A\n The dotted line designated \u201cZ\u201d represents the ;\n",
        "answer": "mean position of the intertropical front ( ITCZ ) during July.\n",
        "choiceone": "mean position of the intertropical front ( ITCZ ) during January.\n",
        "choicetwo": "northerly limit of the SE trade winds during January.\n",
        "choicethree": "northerly limit of the sub tropical jet stream during July.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The dry adiabatic lapse rate ;\n",
        "answer": "has a constant fixed value.\n",
        "choiceone": "is greater during the night than during the day.\n",
        "choicetwo": "has a variable value.\n",
        "choicethree": "is greater in summer than in winter.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The dry adiabatic lapse rate has a value of ;\n",
        "answer": "1\u00b0C/100 m.\n",
        "choiceone": "0.65\u00b0C/100 m.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2\u00b0C/1000 ft.\n",
        "choicethree": "0.5\u00b0C/100 m.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The environmental lapse rate in an actual atmosphere ;\n",
        "answer": "varies with time.\n",
        "choiceone": "has a fixed value of 2\u00b0C/1000 ft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "has a fixed value of 0.65\u00b0C/100 m.\n",
        "choicethree": "has a fixed value of 1\u00b0C/100 m.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The equatorial easterly jet is a jet stream that occurs ;\n",
        "answer": "only in the summer of the northern hemisphere at approx. 45.000 ft.\n",
        "choiceone": "during the whole year in the southern hemisphere.\n",
        "choicetwo": "only in the winter of the northern hemisphere at approx. 30.000 ft.\n",
        "choicethree": "during the whole year in the northern hemisphere.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The eye of a hurricane ;\n",
        "answer": "extends from the surface to the top of the hurricane.\n",
        "choiceone": "can not be spotted by satellites.\n",
        "choicetwo": "has a diameter of at least 100 nautical miles.\n",
        "choicethree": "is filled with air which is colder than the air in the surrounding regions.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The first clouds are thin , wispy cirrus , followed by sheets of cirrus and cirrostratus , and altostratus. The sun is obscured as\nthe altostratus thickens and drizzle or rain begins to fall. The cloud base is lowering as Nimbostratus arrives. These phenomena\ndescribe the approach of a ;\n",
        "answer": "warm front.\n",
        "choiceone": "sea-breeze front.\n",
        "choicetwo": "cold front.\n",
        "choicethree": "trade wind front.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Foehn wind is a ;\n",
        "answer": "warm katabatic wind.\n",
        "choiceone": "warm anabatic wind.\n",
        "choicetwo": "cold anabatic wind.\n",
        "choicethree": "cold katabatic wind.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The following sequence of clouds is observed at an airport ; cirrus , cirrostratus , altostratus , nimbostratus. This is typical\nfor ;\n",
        "answer": "tha passage of a warm front.\n",
        "choiceone": "the passage of a cold front.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the passage of a squall line.\n",
        "choicethree": "anticyclonic weather.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The following statements deal with precipitation , turbulence and icing. Select the list containing the most likely alternatives\nfor NS cloud.\n",
        "answer": "Precipitation may be snow , sleet or rain. Icing is probable and may range between light and severe.\n Turbulence is rarely more than moderate.\n",
        "choiceone": "Precipitation may be snow , sleet or rain. Icing and turbulence are frequently severe.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Precipitation and icing are usually nil. Turbulence is rarely more than moderate.\n",
        "choicethree": "Precipitation is frequently in the form of hail. Icing and turbulence are frequently severe.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The following temperatures have been observed over a station at 1200 UTC. Assume the station is at MSL. Height in feet.\nTemperature in degrees C.\n 20000.-12 18000.-11 16000.-10 14000.-10 12000.-6 10000.-2 8000. +2 6000. +6 4000. +12 2000. +15 surface +15.\n Which of the following statements is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "Assuming that the MSL pressure is 1013.25 hPa the true altitude of an aircraft would actually be higher than\n the indicated altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "The temperature at 10000 ft is in agreement with the temperature in the ICAO Standard Atmosphere.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The layer between 16000 and 18000 ft is absolutely unstable.\n",
        "choicethree": "The height of the freezing level over the station is approximately 12000 ft.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The following weather message ;\n EDDM 241200Z 241322 VRB03KT 1500 BR OVC004 BECMG 1517 00000KT 0500 FG VV002 TEMPO 2022 0400 FG\n VV001 is a ;\n",
        "answer": "9 hour TAF.\n",
        "choiceone": "24 hour TAF.\n",
        "choicetwo": "SPECI.\n",
        "choicethree": "METAR.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The formation of clear ice on the leading edges of an aircraft is most likely to be caused by the ;\n",
        "answer": "relatively slow freezing of large supercooled water droplets.\n",
        "choiceone": "relatively slow freezing of small supercooled water droplets and ice crystals.\n",
        "choicetwo": "instantaneous freezing of large supercooled water droplets and snow crystals.\n",
        "choicethree": "instantaneous freezing of small supercooled water droplets.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The formation of morning fog before sunrise is possible if ;\n",
        "answer": "air temperature and dew point are equal or close to one another.\n",
        "choiceone": "the sky is overcast.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the wind is strong.\n",
        "choicethree": "the turbulence in the lower layers is moderate.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10819A )\n Annex 050-10819A\n The front at the bottom of the diagram , south of position C , is ;\n",
        "answer": "an occlusion on the surface.\n",
        "choiceone": "an occlusion above the surface.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a cold front.\n",
        "choicethree": "a warm front.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10879A )\n Annex 050-10879A\n The front labelled \u201cE\u201d is a ;\n",
        "answer": "cold front.\n",
        "choiceone": "warm front.\n",
        "choicetwo": "warm occlusion.\n",
        "choicethree": "cold occlusion.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-2539A )\n Annex 050-2539A\n The front labelled \u201cZ\u201d is a ;\n",
        "answer": "Warm front.\n",
        "choiceone": "Warm occlusion.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cold occlusion.\n",
        "choicethree": "Cold front.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10876A )\n Annex 050-10876A\n The front located from 10\u00b0W to 10\u00b0E is most likely to be ;\n",
        "answer": "a quasi-stationary front.\n",
        "choiceone": "an active occlusion moving south.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an active warm front moving north.\n",
        "choicethree": "a cold front moving south.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The geostrophic wind depends on ;\n",
        "answer": "density , earth\u2019s rotation , geographic latitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "geographic latitude , centripetal force , height.\n",
        "choicetwo": "centripetal force , height , pressure gradient.\n",
        "choicethree": "earth\u2019s rotation , geographic latitude , centripetal force.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The geostrophic wind is greater than the gradient wind around a low pressure system because the ;\n",
        "answer": "centrifugal force opposes the pressure gradient.\n",
        "choiceone": "coriolis force is added to the pressure gradient.\n",
        "choicetwo": "centrifugal force is added to the pressure gradient.\n",
        "choicethree": "coriolis force opposes to the centrifugal force.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The geostrophic wind is less than the gradient wind around an anticyclone because the ;\n",
        "answer": "centrifugal force is added to the pressure gradient.\n",
        "choiceone": "effect of coriolis is added to friction.\n",
        "choicetwo": "centrifugal force opposes the pressure gradient.\n",
        "choicethree": "coriolis effect opposes the centrifugal force.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The geostrophic wind speed is directly proportional to the ;\n",
        "answer": "horizontal pressure gradient.\n",
        "choiceone": "curvature of isobars.\n",
        "choicetwo": "sine of latitude.\n",
        "choicethree": "density of the air.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The greater the pressure gradient the ;\n",
        "answer": "closer the isobars and the stronger the wind.\n",
        "choiceone": "closer the isobars and the lower the temperatures.\n",
        "choicetwo": "further the isobars will be apart and the weaker the wind.\n",
        "choicethree": "further the isobars will be apart and the higher the temperature.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Harmattan is a ;\n",
        "answer": "NE wind affecting north-west Africa during November to April reducing visibility in rising dust.\n",
        "choiceone": "warm southerly dust-bearing wind affecting the coast of North Africa.\n",
        "choicetwo": "localised depression giving squally winds.\n",
        "choicethree": "SW monsoonal wind causing extensive areas of advection fog along the West African coast south of 15\u00baN.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The height and the temperature of the tropopause are respectively in the order of ;\n",
        "answer": "16 km and \u201375\u00b0C over the equator.\n",
        "choiceone": "8 km and \u201375\u00b0C over the poles.\n",
        "choicetwo": "8 km and \u201340\u00b0C over the equator.\n",
        "choicethree": "16 km and \u201340\u00b0C over the poles.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The height of the lifting condensation level is determined by ;\n",
        "answer": "temperature and dewpoint at the surface.\n",
        "choiceone": "temperature at surface and air pressure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "wet adiabatic lapse rate and dewpoint at the surface.\n",
        "choicethree": "wind and dewpoint at the surface.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Hurricane season is mainly from ;\n",
        "answer": "July until November.\n",
        "choiceone": "October until January.\n",
        "choicetwo": "April until July.\n",
        "choicethree": "January until April.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ICAO Standard Atmosphere ( ISA ) assumes that temperature will reduce at the rate of ;\n",
        "answer": "1.98\u00b0C per 1000 ft up to 36090 ft after which it remains constant to 65617 ft.\n",
        "choiceone": "2\u00b0C per 1000 ft up to 36090 ft and will then increase at 0.3\u00b0C per 1000 ft up to 65617 ft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2\u00b0C per 1000 ft up to 65617 ft after which it will remain constant to 104987 ft.\n",
        "choicethree": "1.98\u00b0C per 1000 ft up to 36090 ft and will then rise at 0.3\u00b0C per 1000 ft up to 65617 ft when it will\n remain constant.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The intertropical convergence zone ;\n",
        "answer": "is characterized by different wind directions on both sides of the zone.\n",
        "choiceone": "forms the boundary between tropical and equatorial air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is always characterized by CB clouds with high tops.\n",
        "choicethree": "nearly always coincides with the geographical equator.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The intertropical convergence zone ( ITCZ ) particularly affects ;\n",
        "answer": "western Africa between 10\u00b0N and 20\u00b0N and the northern coasts of the Arabian sea in July.\n",
        "choiceone": "western Africa , at a latitude of 25\u00b0N in July.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the Atlantic ocean , between latitudes 10\u00b0N and 30\u00b0N , depending on the time of year.\n",
        "choicethree": "western Africa , where it is situated between the 10\u00b0N and 30\u00b0N parallels , depending on the time of the year.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The isobars drawn on a surface weather chart represent lines of equal pressure ;\n",
        "answer": "reduced to sea level.\n",
        "choiceone": "at height of observatory.\n",
        "choicetwo": "at a determined density altitude.\n",
        "choicethree": "at flight level.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The jetstream and associated clear air turbulence can sometimes be visually identified in flight by ;\n",
        "answer": "long streaks of cirrus clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "a constant outside air temperature.\n",
        "choicetwo": "dust or haze at high level.\n",
        "choicethree": "a high-pressure centre at high level.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The length , width and height of a typical mid-latitude jet stream are respectively ;\n",
        "answer": "1000 nautical miles , 150 nautical miles , 10000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "200 nautical miles , 5 nautical miles , 10000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1000 nautical miles , 150 nautical miles , 30000 feet.\n",
        "choicethree": "1000 nautical miles , 5000 to 8000 feet , 30000 feet.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The lowest cloud base forecast at ETA Zurich ( 1200 UTC ) is ;\n LSZH 061019 20018G30KT 9999 -RA SCT050 BKN080 TEMPO 23012KT 6000 -DZ BKN015 BKN030 BECMG 1518\n 23020G35KT 4000 RA OVC010 =\n",
        "answer": "1500 ft.\n",
        "choiceone": "1500 m.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5000 ft.\n",
        "choicethree": "1000 ft.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The lowest cloud type observed is Stratus fractus , and there is moderate continuous rain. The area in which you are at this\nmoment is most likely situated ;\n",
        "answer": "in the main body of a warm or cold front.\n",
        "choiceone": "in a high pressure area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "well behind a cod front.\n",
        "choicethree": "in a warm sector.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The lowest cloud type observed in Stratus fractus , and there is moderate continuous rain. The area of the system in which\nyou are at this moment is ;\n",
        "answer": "the main body of the warm or cold front , or of the occlusion.\n",
        "choiceone": "the warm sector.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the high pressure area.\n",
        "choicethree": "behind the cold front.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The lowest visibility forecast at ETA Zurich 1430 UTC is ;\n LSZH 261019 20018G30KT 9999 -RA SCT050 BKN080 TEMPO 23012KT 6000 -DZ BKN015 BKN030 BECMG 1518\n 23020G35KT 4000 RA OVC010 =\n",
        "answer": "6 km.\n",
        "choiceone": "4 km.\n",
        "choicetwo": "10 km.\n",
        "choicethree": "6 NM.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The main components of a cirrostratus are ;\n",
        "answer": "ice crystals.\n",
        "choiceone": "ice crystals and water droplets.\n",
        "choicetwo": "water droplets and water vapour.\n",
        "choicethree": "water droplets.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The main components of an altostratus are ;\n",
        "answer": "ice crystals and water droplets.\n",
        "choiceone": "water droplets and water vapour.\n",
        "choicetwo": "water droplets and snow grains.\n",
        "choicethree": "ice crystals and ice pellets.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The main factor which contributes to the formation of very low clouds ahead of a warm front is the ;\n",
        "answer": "saturation of the cold air by rain falling into it and evaporating.\n",
        "choiceone": "saturation of the warm air by rain falling into it and evaporating.\n",
        "choicetwo": "warm air moving over a cold surface.\n",
        "choicethree": "reduction of outgoing radiation due to clouds.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The maximum amount of water vapour that the air can contain depends on the ;\n",
        "answer": "air temperature.\n",
        "choiceone": "relative humidity.\n",
        "choicetwo": "dewpoint.\n",
        "choicethree": "stability of the air.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The maximum vapour pressure over a flat supercooled water surface and the maximum vapour pressure over a flat ice\nsurface of the same temperature are compared. The maximum vapour pressure is ;\n",
        "answer": "greater over the water surface.\n",
        "choiceone": "equal over both surfaces.\n",
        "choicetwo": "smaller over the water surface.\n",
        "choicethree": "the same over both surfaces if the air pressure is the same.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The mean height of the tropical tropopause is ;\n",
        "answer": "54.000 ft\n",
        "choiceone": "59.000 ft\n",
        "choicetwo": "49.000 ft\n",
        "choicethree": "44.000 ft\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The mean height of the tropical zero degree isotherm is ;\n",
        "answer": "16.000 ft\n",
        "choiceone": "19.000 ft\n",
        "choicetwo": "12.000 ft\n",
        "choicethree": "14.000 ft\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10935A )\n Annex 050-10935A\n The mean temperature that may be expected to affect that segment of the route from the coast of SE England to Geneva at\nFL 270 is ;\n",
        "answer": "\u201338\u00b0C.\n",
        "choiceone": "\u201330\u00b0C.\n",
        "choicetwo": "\u201342\u00b0C.\n",
        "choicethree": "\u201334\u00b0C.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10934A )\n Annex 050-10934A\n The mean wind that may be expected to affect the route segment from the coast of SE England to Geneva at FL 270 is ;\n",
        "answer": "220/70.\n",
        "choiceone": "270/70.\n",
        "choicetwo": "240/90.\n",
        "choicethree": "245/55.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The morning following a clear , calm night when the temperature has dropped to the dewpoint , is likely to produce ;\n",
        "answer": "radiation fog.\n",
        "choiceone": "good clear weather.\n",
        "choicetwo": "advection fog.\n",
        "choicethree": "a cold front.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The most dangerous form of airframe icing is ;\n",
        "answer": "clear ice.\n",
        "choiceone": "hoar frost.\n",
        "choicetwo": "dry ice.\n",
        "choicethree": "rime ice.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The most dangerous icing conditions are encountered in ;\n",
        "answer": "supercooled precipitation.\n",
        "choiceone": "icy clouds at high levels.\n",
        "choicetwo": "unstable clouds at medium levels.\n",
        "choicethree": "zones where the air temperature is below -15\u00b0C.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The most dangerous low level wind shears are encountered ;\n",
        "answer": "when strong ground inversions are present and near thunderstorms.\n",
        "choiceone": "in areas with layered clouds and wind speeds higher than 35 kt.\n",
        "choicetwo": "during any period when wind speed is greater than 35 kt and near valleys.\n",
        "choicethree": "near valleys and at the windward side of mountains.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The most effective way to dissipate cloud is by ;\n",
        "answer": "subsidence.\n",
        "choiceone": "convection.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a decrease in temperature.\n",
        "choicethree": "a decrease in pressure.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The most frequent wind direction in a valley caused by thermal effects is toward the ;\n",
        "answer": "mountain during daylight hours.\n",
        "choiceone": "mountain at night.\n",
        "choicetwo": "valley during daylight as much as at night.\n",
        "choicethree": "valley during daylight hours.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The most hazardous type of cloud that may be encountered on a cross country flight is ;\n",
        "answer": "cumulonimbus.\n",
        "choiceone": "cirrus.\n",
        "choicetwo": "stratocumulus.\n",
        "choicethree": "cumulus.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The most likely place to encounter clear air turbulence associated with a jet stream is ;\n",
        "answer": "close to the core on the side facing the polar air.\n",
        "choiceone": "well below the core.\n",
        "choicetwo": "on the tropical side of the core.\n",
        "choicethree": "5.000 feet or more above the core.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The most likely reason for radiation fog to dissipate or become low stratus is ;\n",
        "answer": "increasing surface wind speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "a low level temperature inversion.\n",
        "choicetwo": "surface cooling.\n",
        "choicethree": "an increasingly stable atmosphere.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10762A )\n Annex 050-10762A\n The occurrence of freezing rain at FL 60 is most likely in square ;\n",
        "answer": "3C\n",
        "choiceone": "3B\n",
        "choicetwo": "2D\n",
        "choicethree": "2A\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The passage of a warm front can be associated with areas of fog. The types of fog just in advance and just after the passage\nare respectively ;\n",
        "answer": "frontal fog and advection fog.\n",
        "choiceone": "arctic smoke and frontal fog.\n",
        "choicetwo": "advection fog and radiation fog.\n",
        "choicethree": "advection fog and steaming fog.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The polar front is ;\n",
        "answer": "the boundary between polar and tropical air masses.\n",
        "choiceone": "the boundary between arctic and tropical air masses.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the constant frontal activity situated at about 80 degrees north and south.\n",
        "choicethree": "the boundary between arctic and polar air masses.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The polar front is the boundary between ;\n",
        "answer": "polar air and tropical air.\n",
        "choiceone": "arctic air and tropical air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "arctic air and polar air.\n",
        "choicethree": "maritime polar air and continental polar air.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The position of the intertropical convergence zone ;\n",
        "answer": "shows more variation over the continents than over the oceans.\n",
        "choiceone": "shows more variation over the oceans than over the continents.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is more to the north in January than in July.\n",
        "choicethree": "depends on the activity of thunderstorm cloud.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The presence of altocumulus castellanus indicates ;\n",
        "answer": "instability in the middle troposphere.\n",
        "choiceone": "subsidence in a large part of the troposphere.\n",
        "choicetwo": "stability in the higher troposphere.\n",
        "choicethree": "strong convection at low height.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The presence of altocumulus lenticularis is an indication of the ;\n",
        "answer": "presence of mountain waves.\n",
        "choiceone": "presence of valley winds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "development of thermal lows.\n",
        "choicethree": "risk of orographic thunderstorms.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The presence of ice pellets at the surface is evidence that ;\n",
        "answer": "freezing rain occurs at a higher altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "a warm front has passed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "there are thunderstorms in the area.\n",
        "choicethree": "a cold front has passed.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The presence of ice pellets at the surface is evidence that ;\n",
        "answer": "temperatures are above freezing at some higher altitudes.\n",
        "choiceone": "a cold front has passed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "there are thunderstorms in the area.\n",
        "choicethree": "after take-off you can climb to a higher altitude without encountering more than light icing conditions.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The pressure altitude is equal to the true altitude if ;\n",
        "answer": "standard atmospheric conditions occur.\n",
        "choiceone": "the outside air temperature is standard for that height.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the air pressure is 1013.25 hPa at the surface.\n",
        "choicethree": "the indicated altitude is equal to the pressure altitude.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 11 )\n Image 11\n The pressure distribution located mainly in square 2A is a ;\n",
        "answer": "ridge of high pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "trough of low pressure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "depression.\n",
        "choicethree": "col.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10784A )\n Annex 050-10784A\n The pressure system at position \u201cD\u201d is a ;\n",
        "answer": "col.\n",
        "choiceone": "trough of low pressure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ridge of high pressure.\n",
        "choicethree": "secondary low.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The pressure system indicated in a vertical cross section by pressure surfaces at lower heights bulging upward and pressure\nsurfaces at greater heights bulging downward , is a ;\n",
        "answer": "cold high pressure area.\n",
        "choiceone": "warm low pressure area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "cold low pressure area.\n",
        "choicethree": "warm high pressure area.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The pressure system indicated when , in a vertical cross section , the lower situated pressure surfaces bulge upward and the\nhigher situated pressure surfaces bulge downward is a ;\n",
        "answer": "cold high pressure area.\n",
        "choiceone": "warm low pressure area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "warm high pressure area.\n",
        "choicethree": "cold low pressure area.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The prevailing surface wind in the area of the west coast of Africa north of the equator ( gulf of Guinea ) is a ;\n",
        "answer": "SW monsoon in summer and NE tradewind in winter.\n",
        "choiceone": "NE monsoon in winter and SE tradewind in summer.\n",
        "choicetwo": "SW monsoon in winter and NE monsoon in summer.\n",
        "choicethree": "NE tradewind in summer and SE tradewind in winter.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The process by which water vapour is transformed directly into ice is known as ;\n",
        "answer": "sublimation.\n",
        "choiceone": "radiation cooling.\n",
        "choicetwo": "supercooling.\n",
        "choicethree": "supersaturation.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The processes and/or effects which cause clouds to release precipitation are ;\n",
        "answer": "coalescence process and Bergeron-Findeisen process.\n",
        "choiceone": "convection effect and advection effect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "advection effect and coalescence process.\n",
        "choicethree": "Bergeron-Findeisen process and convection effect.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The QFF at an airfield in California located 69 metres below sea level is 1030 hPa. The air temperature is 10\u00b0C lower than a\nstandard atmosphere. What is the QNH ?\n",
        "answer": "More than 1030 hPa. ise QNH > QFF olur.\n",
        "choiceone": "Less than 1030 hPa.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1030 hPa. QFF datumu MSL\u2019\u0131n alt\u0131nda bir seviyede\n",
        "choicethree": "It is not possible to give a definitive answer. ve hava s\u0131cakl\u0131\u011f\u0131 ISA\u2019ya g\u00f6re daha so\u011fuk\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The QFF at an airfield located 400 metres above sea level is 1016 hPa. The air temperature is 10\u00b0C higher than a standard\natmosphere. What is the QNH ?\n",
        "answer": "More than 1016 hPa. QNH > QFF olur.\n",
        "choiceone": "1016 hPa.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It is not possible to give a definitive answer. QFF datumu MSL\u2019\u0131n \u00fczerinde bir seviyede\n",
        "choicethree": "Less than 1016 hPa. ve hava s\u0131cakl\u0131\u011f\u0131 ISA\u2019ya g\u00f6re daha s\u0131cak ise\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The QFF at an airfield located 400 metres above sea level is 1016 hPa. The air temperature is 10\u00b0C lower than a standard\natmosphere. What is the QNH ?\n",
        "answer": "Less than 1016 hPa.\n",
        "choiceone": "More than 1016 hPa. QFF datumu MSL\u2019\u0131n \u00fczerinde bir seviyede\n",
        "choicetwo": "1016 hPa. ve hava s\u0131cakl\u0131\u011f\u0131 ISA\u2019ya g\u00f6re daha so\u011fuk\n",
        "choicethree": "It is not possible to give a definitive answer. ise QNH < QFF olur.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The QNH at an airfield in California located 69 metres below sea level is 1018 hPa. The air temperature is 10\u00b0C higher than\na standard atmosphere. What is the QFF ?\n",
        "answer": "More than 1018 hPa. QFF datumu MSL\u2019\u0131n alt\u0131nda bir seviyede\n",
        "choiceone": "1018 hPa.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It is not possible to give a definitive answer. ve hava s\u0131cakl\u0131\u011f\u0131 ISA\u2019ya g\u00f6re daha s\u0131cak\n",
        "choicethree": "Less than 1018 hPa. ise QNH < QFF olur.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The QNH at an airfield located 0 metres above sea level is 1022 hPa. The air temperature is not available. What is the QFF ?\n",
        "answer": "1022 hPa. QNH = QFF olur.\n",
        "choiceone": "More than 1022 hPa.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It is not possible to give a definitive answer.\n",
        "choicethree": "Less than 1022 hPa. QFF datumu MSL seviyesinde ise\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The QNH at an airfield located 200 metres above sea level is 1009 hPa. The air temperature is 10\u00b0C lower than a standard\natmosphere. What is the QFF ?\n",
        "answer": "More than 1009 hPa.\n",
        "choiceone": "Less than 1009 hPa. QFF datumu MSL\u2019\u0131n \u00fczerinde bir seviyede\n",
        "choicetwo": "1009 hPa. ve hava s\u0131cakl\u0131\u011f\u0131 ISA\u2019ya g\u00f6re daha so\u011fuk ise\n",
        "choicethree": "It is not possible to give a definitive answer. QNH < QFF olur.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The QNH at an airfield located 200 m above sea level is 1022 hPa. The air temperature is not available. What is the QFF ?\n",
        "answer": "It is not possible to give a definitive answer.\n",
        "choiceone": "1022 hPa.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Less than 1022 hPa.\n",
        "choicethree": "More than 1022 hPa.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The QNH is equal to the QFE if ;\n",
        "answer": "the elevation = 0.\n",
        "choiceone": "T actual = T standard.\n",
        "choicetwo": "T actual > T standard.\n",
        "choicethree": "T actual < T standard.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The QNH of an airport at sea level is 983 hPa and the temperature deviation from ISA is \u201315\u00b0C below FL 100. What is the\ntrue altitude of FL 100 ?\n",
        "answer": "8640 ft. 10000 \u2013 810 = 9190 ft ,\n",
        "choiceone": "11460 ft. 1013 \u2013 983 = 30 mb ,\n",
        "choicetwo": "9740 ft. 30 x 27 = 810 ft ,\n",
        "choicethree": "10160 ft. TEC = \u201315\u00b0C x ( 4 : 1000 ) x 9190 = 551,4 \u2248 550 ft ,\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The radiation of the sun heats ;\n",
        "answer": "the surface of the earth , which heats the air in the troposphere.\n",
        "choiceone": "the air in the troposphere only directly if no clouds are present.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the water vapour in the air of the troposphere.\n",
        "choicethree": "the air in the troposphere directly.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The radiosonde can directly measure ;\n",
        "answer": "atmospheric pressure , air temperature , humidity.\n",
        "choiceone": "humidity , wind , atmospheric pressure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "wind , atmospheric pressure , air temperature.\n",
        "choicethree": "air temperature , humidity , wind.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The range of wind speed in which radiation fog is most likely to form is ;\n",
        "answer": "below 5 kt.\n",
        "choiceone": "between 5 and 10 kt.\n",
        "choicetwo": "between 10 and 15 kt.\n",
        "choicethree": "above 15 kt.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The rate of cooling of ascending saturated air is less than the rate of cooling of ascending unsaturated air because ;\n",
        "answer": "heat is released during the condensation process.\n",
        "choiceone": "water vapour doesn\u2019t cool as rapidly as dry air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "water vapour absorbs the incoming heat from the sun.\n",
        "choicethree": "moist air is heavier than dry air.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The reason for the fact , that the atmospheric pressure of a polar front depression is normally lower in winter than in summer\nis that ;\n",
        "answer": "the temperature contrasts between arctic and equatorial areas are much greater in winter.\n",
        "choiceone": "the strong winds of the north Atlantic in winter are favourable for the development of lows.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the low pressure activity of the sea east of Canada is higher in winter.\n",
        "choicethree": "converging air currents are of greater intensity in winter.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The region of the globe where the greatest number of tropical revolving storms occur is ;\n",
        "answer": "the north-west Pacific , affecting Japan , Taiwan , Korea and the Chinese coastline.\n",
        "choiceone": "the Caribbean sea , affecting the West Indies , Mexico and the south-east coastline of the USA.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the south-western Indian ocean , affecting Madagascar , Mauritius and the Island of R\u00e9union.\n",
        "choicethree": "the northern Indian ocean , affecting India , Sri Lanka and Bangladesh.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The relative humidity of a sample air mass is 50%. How is the relative humidity of this air mass influenced by changes of the\namount of water vapour in it ?\n",
        "answer": "It increases with increasing water vapour.\n",
        "choiceone": "It decreases with increasing water vapour.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It is only influenced by temperature.\n",
        "choicethree": "It is not influenced by changing water vapour.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The RVR , as reported in a METAR , is always the ;\n",
        "answer": "value representative of the touchdown zone.\n",
        "choiceone": "highest value of the A- , B- and C-position.\n",
        "choicetwo": "lowest value of the A- , B- and C-position.\n",
        "choicethree": "average value of the A- , B- and C-position.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The sea breeze is a wind from the sea ;\n",
        "answer": "occurring only in the lower layers of the atmosphere in daytime.\n",
        "choiceone": "that reaches up to the tropopause in daytime.\n",
        "choicetwo": "occurring only in mid-latitudes and in daytime.\n",
        "choicethree": "blowing at night in mid-latitudes.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The slope and speed of a warm front compared to the slope and speed of a cold front is in general ;\n",
        "answer": "smaller and slower.\n",
        "choiceone": "greater and faster.\n",
        "choicetwo": "greater and slower.\n",
        "choicethree": "smaller and faster.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The stability in a layer increases by advection of ;\n",
        "answer": "cold air in the lower part.\n",
        "choiceone": "dry air in the upper part.\n",
        "choicetwo": "warm air in the lower part.\n",
        "choicethree": "moist air in the lower part.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The stability in a layer is increasing if ;\n",
        "answer": "warm air is advected in the upper part and cold air in the lower part.\n",
        "choiceone": "warm air is advected in the lower part and cold air in the upper part.\n",
        "choicetwo": "cold and dry air is advected in the upper part.\n",
        "choicethree": "warm and moist air is advected in the lower part.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The stable layer at some height in the low troposphere of an older high pressure area in the mid-latitudes is called ;\n",
        "answer": "subsidence inversion.\n",
        "choiceone": "trade wind inversion.\n",
        "choicetwo": "radiation inversion.\n",
        "choicethree": "friction inversion.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The station pressure used in surface weather charts is ;\n",
        "answer": "QFF\n",
        "choiceone": "QFE\n",
        "choicetwo": "QNH\n",
        "choicethree": "QNE\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The SW monsoon starts in the month of ;\n",
        "answer": "June in southern India to reach Pakistan in July.\n",
        "choiceone": "March in southern India to reach Pakistan end of April.\n",
        "choicetwo": "December in southern India to reach Pakistan in May.\n",
        "choicethree": "September in Pakistan to reach southern India in November.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The TAF weather messages are ;\n",
        "answer": "airport forecasts.\n",
        "choiceone": "hourly or semi-hourly weather observations.\n",
        "choicetwo": "landing forecasts of the \u201ctrend\u201d type.\n",
        "choicethree": "special weather observations.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The temperature at 10.000 ft in the ICAO Standard Atmosphere is ;\n",
        "answer": "\u20135\u00b0C\n",
        "choiceone": "\u201335\u00b0C S\u0131cakl\u0131k ISA\u2019ya g\u00f6re ; y\u00fckseldik\u00e7e her 1000 feet\u2019de 2\u00b0C\n",
        "choicetwo": "\u201320\u00b0C azalaca\u011f\u0131na ve MSL\u2019da s\u0131cakl\u0131k +15\u00b0C olarak kabul\n",
        "choicethree": "0\u00b0C edildi\u011fine g\u00f6re ;15\u00b0C \u2013 ( 10 x 2\u00b0C ) = \u20135\u00b0C\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The temperature at FL 80 is +6\u00b0C. What will the temperature be at FL 130 if the ICAO standard lapse rate is applied ?\n",
        "answer": "\u20134\u00b0C \u2013 ( 5 x 2\u00b0C ) = \u201310\u00b0C \u2192 +6\u00b0C + (\u201310\u00b0C ) = \u20134\u00b0C\n",
        "choiceone": "0\u00b0C\n",
        "choicetwo": "6\u00b0C S\u0131cakl\u0131k ISA\u2019ya g\u00f6re ; y\u00fckseldik\u00e7e her 1000 feet\u2019de 2\u00b0C\n",
        "choicethree": "+2\u00b0C azalaca\u011f\u0131na g\u00f6re ; FL130 \u2013 FL80 = 5000 ft ,\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The temperature at FL 110 is \u20135\u00b0C. What will the temperature be at FL 50 if the ICAO standard lapse rate is applied ?\n",
        "answer": "+7\u00b0C\n",
        "choiceone": "\u20133\u00b0C S\u0131cakl\u0131k ISA\u2019ya g\u00f6re ; al\u00e7ald\u0131k\u00e7a her 1000 feet\u2019de 2\u00b0C\n",
        "choicetwo": "+3\u00b0C artaca\u011f\u0131na g\u00f6re ; FL110 \u2013 FL50 = 6000 ft ,\n",
        "choicethree": "0\u00b0C ( 6 x 2\u00b0C ) = +12\u00b0C \u2192 \u20135\u00b0C + ( +12\u00b0C ) = +7\u00b0C\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The temperature at FL 140 is \u201312\u00b0C. What will the temperature be at FL 110 if the ICAO standard lapse rate is applied ?\n",
        "answer": "\u20136\u00b0C. ( 3 x 2\u00b0C ) = +6\u00b0C \u2192 \u201312\u00b0C + ( +6\u00b0C ) = \u20136\u00b0C\n",
        "choiceone": "\u201318\u00b0C.\n",
        "choicetwo": "\u20139\u00b0C. S\u0131cakl\u0131k ISA\u2019ya g\u00f6re ; al\u00e7ald\u0131k\u00e7a her 1000 feet\u2019de 2\u00b0C\n",
        "choicethree": "\u201315\u00b0C. artaca\u011f\u0131na g\u00f6re ; FL140 \u2013 FL110 = 3000 ft ,\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The temperature at FL 160 is \u201322\u00b0C. What will the temperature be at FL 90 if the ICAO standard lapse rate is applied ?\n",
        "answer": "\u20138\u00b0C\n",
        "choiceone": "+4\u00b0C\n S\u0131cakl\u0131k ISA\u2019ya g\u00f6re ; al\u00e7ald\u0131k\u00e7a her 1000 feet\u2019de 2\u00b0C\n",
        "choicetwo": "0\u00b0C\n artaca\u011f\u0131na g\u00f6re ; FL160 \u2013 FL90 = 7000 ft ,\n",
        "choicethree": "\u20134\u00b0C\n ( 7 x 2\u00b0C ) = +14\u00b0C \u2192 \u201322\u00b0C + ( +14\u00b0C ) = \u20138\u00b0C\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-2529A )\n Annex 050-2529A\n The temperature at FL 330 overhead London will be ;\n",
        "answer": "\u201345\u00b0C\n",
        "choiceone": "\u201357\u00b0C\n",
        "choicetwo": "\u201339\u00b0C\n",
        "choicethree": "\u201333\u00b0C\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The temperature at the surface is given as +15\u00b0C and at 4000 ft it is +9\u00b0C , the state of this layer is said to be ;\n",
        "answer": "stable.\n",
        "choiceone": "conditionally unstable.\n",
        "choicetwo": "absolutely unstable.\n",
        "choicethree": "unstable.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 3 )\n Image 3\n The temperature deviation from ISA ( to the nearest \u00b0C ) overhead Charleston at FL 340 is ;\n",
        "answer": "+5\n",
        "choiceone": "+3\n",
        "choicetwo": "\u20135\n",
        "choicethree": "\u20137\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The temperature lapse rate of the ICAO standard atmosphere in the troposphere is ;\n",
        "answer": "2\u00b0C/1000 ft.\n",
        "choiceone": "2.5\u00b0C/1000 ft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3\u00b0C/1000 ft.\n",
        "choicethree": "6.5\u00b0C/1000 ft.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The term CAVOK is used when weather conditions are ;\n",
        "answer": "9999 , NSC , NSW.\n",
        "choiceone": "9999 , NSC , NOSIG.\n",
        "choicetwo": "8000 , HAZARDOUS WX NIL , NOSIG.\n",
        "choicethree": "9000 , SKC , NOSIG.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The term PROB as used in a TAF message , indicates the probability in percentage , of phenomena described during a\nspecific period. The numerical values immediately following the term PROB , are ;\n",
        "answer": "30 or 40.\n",
        "choiceone": "25 or 35.\n",
        "choicetwo": "20 or 30.\n",
        "choicethree": "35 or 50.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The thickness of the troposphere varies with ;\n",
        "answer": "latitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "the wind.\n",
        "choicetwo": "rotation of the earth.\n",
        "choicethree": "longitude.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The trade winds on the northern hemisphere blow from ;\n",
        "answer": "north-east.\n",
        "choiceone": "north.\n",
        "choicetwo": "west.\n",
        "choicethree": "south-west.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The transition from SW to NE monsoon in India occurs in ;\n",
        "answer": "September , October , November.\n",
        "choiceone": "February , March , April.\n",
        "choicetwo": "July , August , September.\n",
        "choicethree": "December , January , February.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The tropopause is a level at which ;\n",
        "answer": "temperature ceases to fall with increasing height.\n",
        "choiceone": "water vapour content is greatest.\n",
        "choicetwo": "pressure remains constant.\n",
        "choicethree": "vertical currents are strongest.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The tropopause is lower ;\n",
        "answer": "over the North Pole than over the equator.\n",
        "choiceone": "over the equator than over the South Pole.\n",
        "choicetwo": "in summer than winter in moderate latitudes.\n",
        "choicethree": "south of the equator than north of it.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The troposphere ;\n",
        "answer": "has a greater vertical extent above the equator than above the poles.\n",
        "choiceone": "reaches the same height at all latitudes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "contains all oxygen of the stratosphere.\n",
        "choicethree": "is the separation layer between the stratosphere and atmosphere.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The troposphere is the ;\n",
        "answer": "part of the atmosphere below the tropopause.\n",
        "choiceone": "boundary between the mesosphere and thermosphere.\n",
        "choicetwo": "boundary between the stratosphere and the mesosphere.\n",
        "choicethree": "part of the atmosphere above the stratosphere.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The turbulence which occurs at high flight levels ( above FL 250 ) is mainly of the type Clear Air Turbulence. In what way\ncan moderate to severe Clear Air Turbulence affect an aircraft , the flight and the passengers ?\n",
        "answer": "The turbulence is a small scale one and can cause damage. The manoeuvring of the aircraft will be made\n more difficult or even impossible. For the passengers the flight will be unpleasant.\n",
        "choiceone": "The turbulence is a large scale one (waving) so that the aircraft will be difficult to manoeuvre. The\n passengers will feel some discomfort.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The turbulence is wave like which makes the flight unpleasant for the passengers but the manoeuvring will\n not be affected essentially.\n",
        "choicethree": "The turbulence can be resembled with the roughness of a washing-board ( small scale ) and will not have\n influence on the aircraft and its solidity , but will make flight a little more difficult. The passengers will\n seldom notice anything of this turbulence.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The type of icing that occurs in dense clouds with large supercooled drops that have a temperature of \u20135\u00b0C is most likely to\nbe ;\n",
        "answer": "clear ice.\n",
        "choiceone": "rime ice.\n",
        "choicetwo": "hoar frost.\n",
        "choicethree": "cloudy ice.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The typical weather conditions affecting the Darwin area during July are ;\n",
        "answer": "dry season - mainly SE winds - visibility reduced by dust and haze.\n",
        "choiceone": "NW monsoon - very wet - proximity of the intertropical convergence zone causes widespread thunderstorm\n activity.\n",
        "choicetwo": "NE monsoon - continuous heavy rain but little thunderstorm activity.\n",
        "choicethree": "mainly clear skies - advection fog drifting inland with the typical NE wind.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The upper wind and temperature chart of 250 hPa corresponds , in a standard atmosphere , to about ;\n",
        "answer": "34.000 ft\n",
        "choiceone": "32.000 ft\n",
        "choicetwo": "30.000 ft 850 hPa \u2192 FL50 ISA +5\u00b0C , 700 hPa \u2192 FL100 ISA \u20135\u00b0C ,\n",
        "choicethree": "39.000 ft 500 hPa \u2192 FL180 ISA \u201321\u00b0C , 300 hPa \u2192 FL300 ISA \u201345\u00b0C ,\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The validity of a routine TAF is ;\n",
        "answer": "stated in the TAF.\n",
        "choiceone": "2 hours.\n",
        "choicetwo": "9 hours from the time of issue.\n",
        "choicethree": "between 6 and 9 hours.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The value of the saturated adiabatic lapse rate is closest to that of the dry adiabatic lapse rate in ;\n",
        "answer": "cirrus.\n",
        "choiceone": "cumulus.\n",
        "choicetwo": "stratus.\n",
        "choicethree": "freezing fog.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The vertical extent of the friction layer depends primarily on ;\n",
        "answer": "stability , wind speed , roughness of surface.\n",
        "choiceone": "wind speed , roughness of surface , temperature.\n",
        "choicetwo": "temperature , local time , environmental lapse rate.\n",
        "choicethree": "roughness of surface , temperature , local time.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The visibility transmitted in a METAR is ;\n",
        "answer": "the lowest observed in a 360\u00b0 scan from the meteorological station.\n",
        "choiceone": "given by transmissometer when the visibility is below 1500 metres.\n",
        "choicetwo": "measured by an observer counting the number of lights visible on the runway.\n",
        "choicethree": "the maximum determined by a meteorologist in a 360\u00b0 scan at the horizon.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4332A rev 20.01.2003 )\n Annex 050-4332A\n The warm sector is indicated by ;\n",
        "answer": "number 3.\n",
        "choiceone": "number 2.\n",
        "choicetwo": "number 4.\n",
        "choicethree": "number 1.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The weather activity within a cold air pool is usually greatest ;\n",
        "answer": "in the afternoon.\n",
        "choiceone": "in the late evening.\n",
        "choicetwo": "early in the morning.\n",
        "choicethree": "at noon.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10765A )\n Annex 050-10765A\n The weather most likely to be experienced at position A is ;\n",
        "answer": "mainly overcast with stratus or stratocumulus and drizzle , medium to strong winds.\n",
        "choiceone": "radiation fog , low stratus , drizzle , no medium or upper cloud , light wind.\n",
        "choicetwo": "cumulus , cumulonimbus clouds , heavy rain or snow showers , medium to strong winds.\n",
        "choicethree": "clear skies , good visibility in light winds.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10773A )\n Annex 050-10773A\n The weather most likely to be experienced at position \u201cB\u201d is ;\n",
        "answer": "frequent showers of rain or snow.\n",
        "choiceone": "advection fog and drizzle.\n",
        "choicetwo": "early morning fog lifting to low stratus later.\n",
        "choicethree": "poor visibility in anticyclonic circulation.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10774A )\n Annex 050-10774A\n The weather most likely to be experienced at position \u201cB\u201d is ;\n",
        "answer": "frequent showers of rain or snow , good visibility outside showers.\n",
        "choiceone": "scattered stratocumulus with good visibility.\n",
        "choicetwo": "mainly overcast with stratus or stratocumulus , drizzle.\n",
        "choicethree": "clear skies , moderate wind , good visibility.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10803A )\n Annex 050-10803A\n The weather most likely to be experienced at position \u201cR\u201d is ;\n",
        "answer": "fine and warm at first - AC castellanus and CB in late afternoon with thunderstorms.\n",
        "choiceone": "early morning fog lifting to low stratus.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increasing amounts of AS and NS - heavy rain.\n",
        "choicethree": "overcast with drizzle and hill fog.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10766A )\n Annex 050-10766A\n The weather most likely to be experienced at position \u201cS\u201d is ;\n",
        "answer": "frequent heavy showers of rain or snow.\n",
        "choiceone": "morning fog lifting to low stratus.\n",
        "choicetwo": "OVC SC.\n",
        "choicethree": "little or no cloud - hazy.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 2 )\n Image 2\n The weather most likely to be experienced at position \u201cS\u201d is ;\n",
        "answer": "overcast with drizzle and orographie fog.\n",
        "choiceone": "scattered thunderstorms and good visibility .\n",
        "choicetwo": "increasing AS and NS with moderate to heavy rain.\n",
        "choicethree": "small amounts of CU with generally good visibility.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10772A )\n Annex 050-10772A\n The weather most likely to be experienced near to position \u201cA\u201d is ;\n",
        "answer": "frequent showers of rain and snow , good visibility outside precipitation.\n",
        "choiceone": "overcast layer cloud - rain later.\n",
        "choicetwo": "clear skies - radiation fog at night.\n",
        "choicethree": "advection fog and drizzle.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10775A )\n Annex 050-10775A\n The weather most likely to be experienced on the coast near position \u201cQ\u201d is ;\n",
        "answer": "showery with generally good visibility.\n",
        "choiceone": "mainly clear skies with fog developing overnight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "mainly overcast with poor visibility.\n",
        "choicethree": "thundery showers particularly at night.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The widest precipitation zone occurs usually ;\n",
        "answer": "ahead of a warm front.\n",
        "choiceone": "in rear of a cold front.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ahead of a cold front.\n",
        "choicethree": "in rear of a warm front.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The wind at 500 ft above ground is 290/15 kt and at the same position at 600 ft above ground 300/22 kt. How is this wind\nsituation called ?\n",
        "answer": "Moderate vertical wind shear.\n",
        "choiceone": "Severe low level turbulence.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Severe horizontal wind shear.\n",
        "choicethree": "Gradual horizontal wind shear.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The wind direction in a METAR is measured relative to ;\n",
        "answer": "true north.\n",
        "choiceone": "magnetic north.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the 0-meridian.\n",
        "choicethree": "grid north.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The wind indicator for a weather observation receives the measured value from an anemometer. Where is this instrument\nplaced ?\n",
        "answer": "On a mast 6-10 m above the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Close to the station about 2 m above the ground.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 m above the runway.\n",
        "choicethree": "On the roof of the weather station.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The wind speed in a system with curved isobars compared to a system with straight isobars is ; ( other conditions being the\nsame )\n",
        "answer": "higher if curvature is anticyclonic.\n",
        "choiceone": "always lower.\n",
        "choicetwo": "higher if curvature is cyclonic.\n",
        "choicethree": "always higher.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The wind tends to follow the contour lines ( isohypses ) above the friction layer because ;\n",
        "answer": "the coriolis force tends to balance with the horizontal pressure gradient force.\n",
        "choiceone": "the coriolis force acts perpendicular on a line that connects high and low pressure system.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the friction of the air with the earth\u2019s surface gives the airflow a diversion perpendicular to the gradient force.\n",
        "choicethree": "contour lines are lines that connect points with the same wind speed in the upper air.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4389A )\n Annex 050-4389A\n This chart shows the weather situation at 0600 UTC on May 23. Which of the following reports reflects weather\ndevelopment at Geneva Airport ?\n",
        "answer": "TAF LSGG 230600Z 230716 23016KT 8000 -RA BKN030 OVC070 BECMG 0810 5000 RA BKN020\n OVC050 TEMPO 1012 3000 +RA BKN010 OVC030 BECMG 1215 25014KT 8000 SCT030 BKN090 =\n",
        "choiceone": "TAF LSGG 230600Z 230716 26012KT 9999 SCT030 BKN080 TEMPO 1013 25020G35KT 3000 TSRA\n BKN030CB BECMG 1316 VRB02KT 3000 BCFG SCT100 =\n",
        "choicetwo": "TAF LSGG 230600Z 230716 05014KT 5000 BR OVC015 BECMG 0810 8000 BKN018 BECMG 1013\n 05015G30KT 9999 SCT025 =\n",
        "choicethree": "TAF LSGG 230600Z 230716 VRB03KT 6000 SCT020 BECMG 0811 23005KT 9999 SCT025TCU PROB\n 40 TEMPO 1216 34012G30KT 3000 TSRA BKN020CB =\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Thunderstorms are often preceded by ;\n",
        "answer": "Altocumulus Castellanus.\n",
        "choiceone": "Altocumulus Lenticularis.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Nimbostratus.\n",
        "choicethree": "Altostratus.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Thunderstorms can occur on a warm front if the ;\n",
        "answer": "warm air is moist and the environmental lapse rate exceeds the saturated adiabatic lapse rate.\n",
        "choiceone": "cold air is moist and the environmental lapse rate exceeds the saturated adiabatic lapse rate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "cold air is moist and the environmental lapse rate is less than the dry adiabatic lapse rate.\n",
        "choicethree": "warm air is moist and the environmental lapse rate is less than the saturated adiabatic lapse rate.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Thunderstorms in exceptional circumstances can occur in a warm front if ;\n",
        "answer": "the warm air is unstable.\n",
        "choiceone": "the cold air is unstable.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the warm air is stable.\n",
        "choicethree": "the cold air is stable.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Thunderstorms reach their greatest intensity during the ;\n",
        "answer": "mature stage.\n",
        "choiceone": "period in which precipitation is not falling.\n",
        "choicetwo": "cumulus stage.\n",
        "choicethree": "dissipating stage.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-2556A )\n Annex 050-2556A\n To what extent is Munich covered by clouds ?\n",
        "answer": "5 to 8 oktas.\n",
        "choiceone": "5 to 7 oktas.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 to 4 oktas.\n",
        "choicethree": "3 to 5 oktas.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-3030A )\n Annex 050-3030A\n To which aerodrome is the following TAF most applicable ?\n TAF 230900Z 231019 24014KT 6000 SCT030 BKN100 TEMPO 1113 25020G38KT 2500 +TSRA SCT008 BKN025CB\n BECMG 1315 28012KT 9999 SCT025 TEMPO 1517 5000 SHRA BKN020 BECMG 1719 27008KT 9999 SCT030 =\n",
        "answer": "LOWW\n",
        "choiceone": "LEMD\n",
        "choicetwo": "EKCH\n",
        "choicethree": "LFPG\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "To which type of message does the following text belong ?\n ... MBST APCH RWY26 REP AT 1510 B747 30KT ASPEEDL 2NM FNA =\n",
        "answer": "Wind shear warning\n",
        "choiceone": "AIRMET\n",
        "choicetwo": "Aerodrome warning\n",
        "choicethree": "SIGMET\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "To which type of message does the following text belong ?\n ... VALID 211600/212000 HVY SN 25CM FCST =\n",
        "answer": "Aerodrome warning\n",
        "choiceone": "SIGMET\n",
        "choicetwo": "SNOWTAM\n",
        "choicethree": "Supplementary information of a METAR\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Tropical revolving storms are NOT formed in ;\n",
        "answer": "South Atlantic Ocean.\n",
        "choiceone": "South Indian Ocean.\n",
        "choicetwo": "waters around the Philippines.\n",
        "choicethree": "Gulf of Bengal.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Tropical revolving storms do not occur in the southeast Pacific and the South Atlantic because ;\n",
        "answer": "of the low water temperature.\n",
        "choiceone": "of the strong southeast wind.\n",
        "choicetwo": "there is no coriolis force present.\n",
        "choicethree": "the southeast trade winds cross over into the northern hemisphere.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Troughs are extensions of ;\n",
        "answer": "low pressure areas and generally have large amounts of cloud.\n",
        "choiceone": "high pressure areas and generally have large amounts of cloud.\n",
        "choicetwo": "high pressure areas and generally have small amounts of cloud.\n",
        "choicethree": "low pressure areas and generally have small amounts of cloud.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Two aircraft are flying simultaneously in level flight at different flight levels on opposite tracks overhead a given position ;\nAircraft A flying at FL 070 experiences a 30 kt headwind. Aircraft B flying at FL 060 experiences a 20 kt headwind. None of the\naircraft experiences cross wind. This wind condition will be referred to as ;\n",
        "answer": "vertical wind shear only.\n",
        "choiceone": "horizontal wind shear only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "no wind shear since the absolute value of the difference in wind velocity per height unit is too small to fit the\n definition of wind shear at all.\n",
        "choicethree": "vertical and horizontal wind shear.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Two aircraft , one with a sharp wing profile ( S ) , and the other with a thick profile ( T ) , are flying through the same cloud\nwith same true airspeed. The cloud consists of small supercooled droplets. Which of the following statements is most correct\nconcerning ice accretion ?\n",
        "answer": "Aircraft S experiences more icing than T.\n",
        "choiceone": "Neither of the aircraft accumulate ice due to the small size of droplets.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Aircraft S and T experience the same amount of icing\n",
        "choicethree": "Aircraft T experiences more icing than S.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under anticyclone conditions in the northern hemisphere , with curved isobars the speed of the gradient wind is ;\n",
        "answer": "greater than the geostrophic wind.\n",
        "choiceone": "less than the geostrophic wind.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the same as the thermal component.\n",
        "choicethree": "proportional only to the Coriolis force.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4305A )\n Annex 050-4305A\n Under the weather conditions depicted , which of the following statements is likely to apply ?\n",
        "answer": "Thunderstorms may occur in the summer months over Central Europe.\n",
        "choiceone": "Severe gradient wind likely over Central Europe.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Moderate to strong Foehn in the Alps.\n",
        "choicethree": "Radiation fog is unlikely in Central Europe in the winter.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under what condition does pressure altitude have the same value as density altitude ?\n",
        "answer": "At standard temperature.\n",
        "choiceone": "When the altimeter has no position error.\n",
        "choicetwo": "At sea level when the temperature is 0\u00b0C.\n",
        "choicethree": "When the altimeter setting is 1013.2 hPa.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under which conditions would you expect the heaviest clear ice accretion to occur in a CB ?\n",
        "answer": "Between -2\u00b0C and -15\u00b0C.\n",
        "choiceone": "Close to the freezing level.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Between -30\u00b0C and -40\u00b0C.\n",
        "choicethree": "Between -20\u00b0C and -30\u00b0C.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under which of the following conditions is the most severe CAT likely to be experienced ?\n",
        "answer": "A curved jet stream near a deep trough.\n",
        "choiceone": "A jet stream , with great spacing between the isotherms.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A westerly jet stream at low latitudes in the summer.\n",
        "choicethree": "A straight jet stream near a low pressure area.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under which of these conditions is radiation fog most likely to form ?\n",
        "answer": "Little or no cloud.\n",
        "choiceone": "Very low temperatures.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Very dry air.\n",
        "choicethree": "Strong surface winds.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Updraughts in a thunderstorm are prevailing during the ;\n",
        "answer": "initial stage.\n",
        "choiceone": "period in which precipitation is falling.\n",
        "choicetwo": "dissipating stage.\n",
        "choicethree": "mature stage.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Vertical wind shear is ;\n",
        "answer": "a change of horizontal wind direction and/or speed with height.\n",
        "choiceone": "a change of vertical wind speed with horizontal distance.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a horizontal shear of vertical wind.\n",
        "choicethree": "a change of horizontal wind direction and/or speed with horizontal distance.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Visibility is reduced by haze when ;\n",
        "answer": "dust particles are trapped below an inversion.\n",
        "choiceone": "a light drizzle falls.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a cold front just passed.\n",
        "choicethree": "small water droplets are present.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10800A )\n Annex 050-10800A\n Weather conditions at Mumbai during early July are mainly influenced by the ;\n",
        "answer": "SW monsoon.\n",
        "choiceone": "NE monsoon and the proximity of the ITCZ.\n",
        "choicetwo": "passage of frontal system generated in the south Indian ocean.\n",
        "choicethree": "high incidence of tropical revolving storms originating in the Persian gulf.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10801A )\n Annex 050-10801A\n Weather conditions at Mumbai during January are mainly influenced by the ;\n",
        "answer": "NE monsoon.\n",
        "choiceone": "SW monsoon.\n",
        "choicetwo": "SE monsoon.\n",
        "choicethree": "NW monsoon.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What , approximately , is the average height of the tropopause over the equator ?\n",
        "answer": "16 km\n",
        "choiceone": "11 km\n",
        "choicetwo": "8 km\n",
        "choicethree": "40 km\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are squall lines ?\n",
        "answer": "Bands of intensive thunderstorms.\n",
        "choiceone": "The surface weather associated with upper air troughs.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Unusual intensive cold fronts.\n",
        "choicethree": "The paths of tropical revolving storms.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the characteristics of cumuliform clouds ?\n",
        "answer": "Large water droplets , instability , turbulence , showers and mainly clear ice.\n",
        "choiceone": "Small water droplets , instability , turbulence , extensive areas of rain and rime ice.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Large water droplets , stability , no turbulence , showers and mainly rime ice.\n",
        "choicethree": "Small water droplets , stability , no turbulence and extensive areas of rain.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the characteristics of rime ice , and what conditions are most favourable for its formation ?\n",
        "answer": "Milky granular appearance , forming on leading edges and accumulating forward into the air stream.\n Stratiform clouds at temperatures of -10\u00baC to -20\u00baC are most conductive to its formation.\n",
        "choiceone": "Opaque rough appearance , tending to spread back over an aircraft surface. Most frquently encountered in\n cumuliform clouds at temperatures slightly below freezing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Smooth appearance and builds forward from leading surfaces into a sharp edge. Most common in cumuliform\n clouds at temperatures of -20\u00baC to -25\u00baC.\n",
        "choicethree": "Transparent appearance and tendency to take the shape of the surface on which it freezes. Stratiform clouds\n and temperatures only slightly below freezing promote its formation.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the characteristics of the Bora ? ( Ref : Inter Cockpit , Pg. 158 )\n",
        "answer": "It is a cold and very strong wind that blows mainly in winter from a tableland downwards to the Adriatic.\n",
        "choiceone": "It is a warm and moist , south-westerly wind experienced in the eastern Mediterranean , that usually carries\n precipitation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It is a very cold wind that blows mainly in winter from a north-westerly direction in the Mediterranean.\n",
        "choicethree": "It is a dry and hot southerly wind experienced in the Sahara desert , that often carries dust.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the colours with which a stationary front is shown on a surface chart ?\n",
        "answer": "Red and blue.\n",
        "choiceone": "Red and green.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Violet and red.\n",
        "choicethree": "Blue and violet.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the conditions required for the formation of hoar frost ?\n",
        "answer": "The temperature of the surface is lower than the dew point of the air and the dew point is lower than 0\u00baC.\n",
        "choiceone": "Falling droplets on a surface while the air temperature is below freezing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The temperature of the surface is higher than the dew point of the air and the dew point is lower than 0\u00baC.\n",
        "choicethree": "Falling droplets on a surface with a temperature below freezing.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the differences between radiation fog and advection fog ?\n",
        "answer": "Radiation fog forms due to surface cooling at night in a light wind. Advection for forms when warm humid\n air flows over a cold surface.\n",
        "choiceone": "Radiation fog is formed by surface cooling in a calm wind. Advection fog is formed by evaporation over the\n sea.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Radiation fog forms only on the ground , advection fog only on the sea.\n",
        "choicethree": "Radiation for forms due to night cooling and advection fog due to daytime cooling.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the images of satellites provided daily by the Weather Service used for ?\n",
        "answer": "To locate fronts in areas with few observation stations.\n",
        "choiceone": "To locate precipitation zones.\n",
        "choicetwo": "To measure wind currents on the ground.\n",
        "choicethree": "To help provide 14-day forecasts.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the meanings of the meteorological abbreviations SQ , BR , MIFG and SG respectively ?\n",
        "answer": "Sudden increase in wind speed lasting for at least one minute / mist / shallow fog / snowgrains.\n",
        "choiceone": "Short wind gust / fog / shallow fog / snowgrains.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Sudden strong increase in wind speed lasting for at least one minute / haze / patches of fog / snowgrains.\n",
        "choicethree": "Short wind gust / mist / shallow fog / polar snow.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the normal and official sources of meteorological information for an aircraft in flight ?\n",
        "answer": "VOLMET broadcast , ATIS , all ATS-units.\n",
        "choiceone": "VOLMET broadcast , ATIS , and from the ATS-units the FIC only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "VOLMET broadcast , ATIS , and from the ATS-units the TWR , APP and FIC only.\n",
        "choicethree": "VOLMET broadcast , ATIS , and from the ATS-units the TWR only.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the requirements for the formation of a thunderstorm ?\n",
        "answer": "An adaquate supply of moisture , conditional instability and a lifting action.\n",
        "choiceone": "A cumulus cloud with sufficient moisture associated with an inversion.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Water vapour and high pressure.\n",
        "choicethree": "A stratocumulus cloud with sufficient moisture.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the typical differences with regard to the temperature and humidity between an air mass with its origin in the\nAzores and an air mass with its origin over northern Russia ?\n",
        "answer": "The air of the Azores is warmer and more humid than the North-Russian air.\n",
        "choiceone": "The North-Russian air is warmer and dryer than the air of the Azores.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The air of the Azores is warmer and dryer than the North-Russian air.\n",
        "choicethree": "The North-Russian air is colder and more humid than the air of the Azores.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the typical weather conditions in a cold air pool in summer ?\n",
        "answer": "Precipitation is predominant.\n",
        "choiceone": "Generally fine weather , thunderstorms in the afternoon or evening.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Ground fog formation is common.\n",
        "choicethree": "Fine weather with thunderstorms in the morning or forenoon.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the typical weather conditions in a warm anticyclone over land ?\n",
        "answer": "Fine weather dominates in summer.\n",
        "choiceone": "In the winter ground fog formation is not common.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only short term weather improvements.\n",
        "choicethree": "Strong westerly winds.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the typical weather conditions in a westerly situation ?\n",
        "answer": "Very changeable.\n",
        "choiceone": "Steady rainfall.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Fine weather with strong westerly winds.\n",
        "choicethree": "Frequent thunderstorms during winter.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the typical weather conditions in an area with a flat pressure pattern in summer ?\n",
        "answer": "Generally fine weather , possibly thunderstorms in the afternoon or evening.\n",
        "choiceone": "Only short term weather improvements.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Steady rainfall.\n",
        "choicethree": "Fine weather with strong westerly winds.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What average geographical latitude is assumed for the zone of the subtropical high ?\n",
        "answer": "30\u00baN\n",
        "choiceone": "50\u00baN\n",
        "choicetwo": "0\u00ba ( equator )\n",
        "choicethree": "10\u00baN\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What causes surface winds to flow across the isobars at an angle rather than parallel to the isobars ?\n",
        "answer": "Surface friction.\n",
        "choiceone": "Greater density of the air at the surface.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Greater atmospheric pressure at the surface.\n",
        "choicethree": "Coriolis force.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-2388A rev. 20.01.2003 )\n Annex 050-2388A\n What change in pressure , will occur at point A , during the next hour ?\n",
        "answer": "A rise in pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "A drop in pressure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Approximately constant pressure.\n",
        "choicethree": "Irregular fluctuations.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-2388A rev. 20.01.2003 )\n Annex 050-2388A\n What change in pressure , will occur at point B , during the next hour ?\n",
        "answer": "Approximately constant pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "A drop in pressure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A rise in pressure.\n",
        "choicethree": "Irregular fluctations.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-2388A rev. 20.01.2003 )\n Annex 050-2388A\n What change in pressure , will occur at point F , during the next hour ?\n",
        "answer": "A drop in pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "A rise in pressure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Constant pressure.\n",
        "choicethree": "Irregular fluctations.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-2388A rev. 20.01.2003 )\n Annex 050-2388A\n What change in temperature will occur at point A during the next hour ?\n",
        "answer": "A drop in temperature.\n",
        "choiceone": "A rise in temperature.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Irregular fluctations.\n",
        "choicethree": "Approximately constant temperature.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-2388A rev. 20.01.2003 )\n Annex 050-2388A\n What change in temperature will occur at point B during the next hour ?\n",
        "answer": "Approximately constant temperature.\n",
        "choiceone": "A rise in temperature.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Irregular fluctuations.\n",
        "choicethree": "A drop in temperature.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What characteristic is associated with a temperature inversion ?\n",
        "answer": "Stability.\n",
        "choiceone": "Area of active storms.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Instability.\n",
        "choicethree": "Clear ice.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What characteristics will the surface winds have in an area where the isobars on the weather map are very close together ?\n",
        "answer": "Strong and flowing somewhat across the isobars.\n",
        "choiceone": "Very weak but gusty and flowing across the isobars.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Moderate and flowing parallel to the isobars.\n",
        "choicethree": "Strong and flowing parallel to the isobars.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What characterizes a stationary front ?\n",
        "answer": "The surface wind usually has its direction parallel to the front.\n",
        "choiceone": "The surface wind usually has its direction perpendicular to the front.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The warm air moves at approximately half the speed of the cold air.\n",
        "choicethree": "The weather conditions that it originates is a combination between those of an intense cold front and those of\n a warm and very active front.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What cloud cover is typical for a wide warm sector of a polar front depression over Central Europe in the summer ?\n",
        "answer": "Fair weather CU.\n",
        "choiceone": "Sky clear.\n",
        "choicetwo": "BKN CU and CB.\n",
        "choicethree": "ST with drizzle.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What cloud formation is most likely to occur at low levels when a warm air mass overrides a cold air mass ?\n",
        "answer": "Nimbostratus.\n",
        "choiceone": "Altostratus.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cumulonimbus.\n",
        "choicethree": "Cumulus.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What cloud type can produce freezing rain ?\n",
        "answer": "Nimbostratus.\n",
        "choiceone": "Stratus.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cumulonimbus.\n",
        "choicethree": "Stratocumulus.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What conditions are most likely to lead to the formation of hill fog ?\n",
        "answer": "Humid stable air mass , wind blowing towards the hills.\n",
        "choiceone": "Precipitation which is lifted by the action of moderate winds striking the range.\n",
        "choicetwo": "High relative humidity and an unstable air mass.\n",
        "choicethree": "Clear skies , calm or light winds , with relatively low humidity.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10847A )\n Annex 050-10847A\n What conditions are most likely to prevail at an aerodrome located in square 3B ?\n",
        "answer": "6 - 8 oktas SC and ST , visibility moderate to poor in drizzle.\n",
        "choiceone": "Intermittent thunderstorms otherwise generally clear skies with good visibility.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Broken CU base 2000 FT , visibility more than 5 km , occasional showers of rain or snow.\n",
        "choicethree": "Mainly overcast at 8000 FT , visibility less than 5 km in continuous moderate rain.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What conditions are necessary for vertical visibility to be reported ?\n",
        "answer": "Whenever the sky is obscured by fog or heavy precipitation and the height of the cloud base cannot be\n measured.\n",
        "choiceone": "Whenever the lowest ceiling is below 1500 ft above ground.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It is always reported.\n",
        "choicethree": "Whenever the lowest cloud base is below 1500 ft above ground.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What degree of aircraft icing is determined by the following ICAO description ?\n \u201cConditions in which change of heading and/or altitude may be considered desirable.\u201d\n",
        "answer": "Moderate\n",
        "choiceone": "Violent\n",
        "choicetwo": "Light\n",
        "choicethree": "Severe\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What degree of aircraft icing is determined by the following ICAO description ?\n \u201cConditions in which immediate change of heading and/or altitude is considered essential\u201d.\n",
        "answer": "Severe\n",
        "choiceone": "Moderate\n",
        "choicetwo": "Light\n",
        "choicethree": "Violent\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What degree of turbulence , if any , is likely to be encountered while flying through a cold front in the summer over Central\nEurope at FL 100 ?\n",
        "answer": "Severe turbulence in CB cloud.\n",
        "choiceone": "Light turbulence in ST cloud.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Light turbulence in CB cloud.\n",
        "choicethree": "Moderate turbulence in NS cloud.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does dewpoint mean ?\n",
        "answer": "The temperature to which a mass of air must be cooled in order to reach saturation.\n",
        "choiceone": "The freezing level ( danger of icing ).\n",
        "choicetwo": "The temperature at which the relative humidity and saturation vapour pressure are the same.\n",
        "choicethree": "The temperature at which ice melts.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the abbreviation \u201cBKN\u201d mean ?\n",
        "answer": "5-7 Eights of the sky is cloud covered.\n",
        "choiceone": "3-5 Eights of the sky is cloud covered.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3-4 Eights of the sky is cloud covered.\n",
        "choicethree": "Nil significant cloud cover.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the abbreviation \u201cnosig\u201d mean ?\n",
        "answer": "No significant changes.\n",
        "choiceone": "No report received.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Not signed by the meteorologist.\n",
        "choicethree": "No weather related problems.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the code R24R/P1500 mean ?\n",
        "answer": "RVR RWY 24 right above 1500 metres.\n",
        "choiceone": "RVR RWY 24 right below 1500 metres.\n",
        "choicetwo": "RVR RWY 24 right 1500 metres.\n",
        "choicethree": "Snow clearance in progress on RWY 24 right , useable runway length 1500 metres.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the code TAF AMD mean ?\n",
        "answer": "Revised TAF.\n",
        "choiceone": "Weather conditions expected to affect the safety of normal operations.\n",
        "choicetwo": "No change compared with the previous TAF.\n",
        "choicethree": "Delayed issue of a TAF.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-2058A )\n Annex 050-2388A\n What does the symbol indicate on a Significant Weather Chart ?\n",
        "answer": "The centre of a tropopause \u201chigh\u201d , where the tropopause is at FL 400.\n",
        "choiceone": "The centre of a high pressure area at 400 hPa.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The lower limit of the tropopause.\n",
        "choicethree": "The upper limit of significant weather at FL 400.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the term METAR signify ?\n",
        "answer": "A METAR signifies the actual weather report at an aerodrome and is generally issued in half-hourly\n intervals.\n",
        "choiceone": "A METAR is a landing forecast added to the actual weather report as a brief prognostic report.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A METAR is a flight forecast, issued by the meteorological station several times daily.\n",
        "choicethree": "A METAR is a warning of dangerous meteorological conditions within a FIR.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the term SIGMET signify ?\n",
        "answer": "A SIGMET is a warning of dangerous meteorological conditions.\n",
        "choiceone": "A SIGMET is an actual weather report at an aerodrome and is generally issued at halfhourly intervals.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A SIGMET is a brief landing forecast added to the actual weather report.\n",
        "choicethree": "A SIGMET is a flight forecast , issued by the meteorological station several times daily.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the term TREND signify ?\n",
        "answer": "It is a landing forecast added to the actual weather report.\n",
        "choiceone": "It is a warning of dangerous meteorological conditions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It is the actual weather report at an aerodrome and is generally issued at half-hourly intervals.\n",
        "choicethree": "It is a flight forecast , issued by the meteorological station several times daily.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What feature is normally associated with the initial stage of a thunderstorm ?\n",
        "answer": "Continuous updraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Frequent lightning.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Rain or hail at the surface.\n",
        "choicethree": "Roll cloud.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10769A )\n Annex 050-10769A\n What flight conditions are most likely to be experienced in square 2B by an aircraft at FL 120 ?\n",
        "answer": "VMC above layers of ST and SC , generally stable conditions.\n",
        "choiceone": "VMC below an overcast of AS and CS , generally smooth air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "IMC in NS with risk of light icing.\n",
        "choicethree": "IMC in layers of AS and isolated CB risk of severe turbulence and icing.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What flying conditions are normally encountered when flying in cirrus clouds ?\n",
        "answer": "Average horizontal visibility more than 1000 m , nil icing.\n",
        "choiceone": "Average horizontal visibility less than 500 m , nil icing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Average horizontal visibility more than 1000 m , light to moderate rime ice.\n",
        "choicethree": "Average horizontal visibility less than 500 m , light to moderate icing.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What information is given on a Significant Weather Chart ?\n",
        "answer": "The significant weather forecast for the time given on the chart.\n",
        "choiceone": "The significant weather that is observed at the time given on the chart.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The significant weather forecast for a period 6 hours after the time given on the chart.\n",
        "choicethree": "The significant weather in a period 3 hours before and 3 hours after the time given on the chart.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What information is required to calculate a lowest usable flight level from a given minimum safe altitude ?\n",
        "answer": "Lowest value of QNH and the highest negative temperature deviation from ISA.\n",
        "choiceone": "Highest value of QNH and the highest positive temperature deviation from ISA.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Highest value of QNH and the highest negative temperature deviation from ISA.\n",
        "choicethree": "Lowest value of QNH and the lowest negative temperature deviation from ISA.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What information is required to convert a minimum safe altitude into a lowest usable flight level ?\n",
        "answer": "Lowest value of QNH and the highest negative temperature deviation from ISA.\n",
        "choiceone": "Highest value of QNH and the highest positive temperature deviation from ISA.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Lowest value of QNH and the lowest negative temperature deviation from ISA.\n",
        "choicethree": "Highest value of QNH and the highest negative temperature deviation from ISA.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What intensity and type of aircraft icing is likely to occur at FL 100 in a thunderstorm , with the freezing level at 7000 ft ?\n",
        "answer": "Moderate to severe icing due to clear ice.\n",
        "choiceone": "Light icing due to clear ice.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Moderate to severe icing due to rime ice.\n",
        "choicethree": "Light icing due to rime ice.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What intensity and type of airframe icing is most likely to occur when aircraft descend rapidly from FL 320 ( temp. \u201345\u00b0C )\nto FL 60 in warm , moist clear air ?\n",
        "answer": "Light or moderate hoar frost.\n",
        "choiceone": "Light opaque rime and light clear ice.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Nil ice.\n",
        "choicethree": "Moderate opaque rime.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What intensity and type of airframe icing is most likely to occur when flying at FL 170 in AS with the outside air\ntemperature at \u201320\u00b0C ?\n",
        "answer": "Light - rime\n",
        "choiceone": "Severe - clear\n",
        "choicetwo": "Moderate - clear\n",
        "choicethree": "Moderate - hoar frost\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a characteristic of stable air ?\n",
        "answer": "Stratiform clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "Fair weather cumulus clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Unlimited visibility.\n",
        "choicethree": "Temperature decreases rapidly.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a characteristic phenomenon for a stable atmosphere ?\n",
        "answer": "Stratified clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "No precipitation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Weak wind\n",
        "choicethree": "Many vertical currents.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a downburst ? ( Ref : Inter Cockpit , Pg. 178 )\n",
        "answer": "A concentrated downdraft with high speeds and a lower temperature than the surrounding air.\n",
        "choiceone": "An extremely strong wind gust in a tropical revolving storm.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A concentrated downdraft with high speeds and a higher temperature than the surrounding air.\n",
        "choicethree": "A small low pressure system where the wind circulates with very high speeds.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a favourable synoptic situation for the development of a Scirocco ?\n",
        "answer": "Low pressure area in the western part of the Mediterranean sea\n",
        "choiceone": "Extension of the Azores high pressure area over the Alps\n",
        "choicetwo": "High pressure area over Italy\n",
        "choicethree": "High pressure area in the western part of the Mediterranean sea\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a Foehn wind ?\n",
        "answer": "It is an adiabatically heated wind blowing down a mountain side. The temperature on the lee side is normally\n higher than on the windward side of the mountain at the same level.\n",
        "choiceone": "It is a warm and moist anabatic wind that usually carries precipitation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It is a flow of warm air up a slope of a hill caused by surface heating.\n",
        "choicethree": "It is an adiabatically heated wind blowing down a mountain side. The temperature on the lee side is normally\n lower than on the windward side of the mountain at the same level.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a radiosonde ?\n",
        "answer": "Instrument intended to be carried by a balloon up through the atmosphere , equipped with devices to measure\n meteorological variables and provided with a radio transmitter for sending this information to the observing\n station.\n",
        "choiceone": "A meteorological station on ground or water at which measurements of meteorological variables are made\n automatically and a radio transmitter sends automatically this information to a meteorological centre. These\n data from such a station are indcated.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Equipment used for determining upper winds ( velocity and direction ) by transmitting different radio waves\n and measuring the amount of the reflected waves by the moving air. These values correlate to the speed and\n direction of the wind.\n",
        "choicethree": "Equipment used for determining upper winds only ( velocity and direction ) by tracking a free balloon by\n electronic means at the observing station.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a SPECI ?\n",
        "answer": "A special aerodrome weather report , issued when a significant change of the weather conditions have been\n observed.\n",
        "choiceone": "A warning of meteorological dangers at an aerodrome , issued only when required.\n",
        "choicetwo": "An aerodrome forecast issued every 9 hours.\n",
        "choicethree": "A routine aerodrome weather report issued every 3 hours.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a stormscope ?\n",
        "answer": "An instrument on board an aircraft to detect electrical discharges.\n",
        "choiceone": "The technical term ( jargon ) for a radar scope showing thuderstorms.\n",
        "choicetwo": "An instrument to detect wind shear by means of the Doppler-effect during flight.\n",
        "choicethree": "An instrument to measure wind velocity.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a trend forecast ?\n",
        "answer": "A landing forecast appended to METAR/SPECI , valid for 2 hours.\n",
        "choiceone": "An aerodrome forecast valid for 9 hours.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A routine report.\n",
        "choicethree": "A route forecast valid for 24 hours.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a VOLMET broadcast ?\n",
        "answer": "Provision , as appropriate , of current METAR , SPECI , TAF and SIGMET by means of continuous and\n repetitive voice broadcast.\n",
        "choiceone": "That part of an ATIS which is concerned to meteorological information.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Weather information transmitted continuously via radio ( special broadcast ) , containing weather information\n for one airport.\n",
        "choicethree": "Information issued by a meteorological watch office concerning the occurrence or expected occurrence of\n specified enroute weather phenomena which may affect the safety of aircraft operations.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is an aerodrome warning ?\n",
        "answer": "A message issued by a meteorological office concerning the meteorological conditions which could adversely\n affect aircraft on ground , including parked aircraft , and the aerodrome facilities and services.\n",
        "choiceone": "A message issued by a meteorological watch office concerning the occurrence and/or expeced occurrence of\n specified enroute weather phenomena , whichmay affect the safety of aircraft operations.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A message prepared by a meteorological office concerning wind shear which could adversely affect aircraft\n on the approach path or take-off path or during circling approach between runway level and a specified upper\n level , and aircraft on the runway.\n",
        "choicethree": "The part of a METAR message that is called supplementary information.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is , approximately , the temperature at 20.000 ft in the ICAO Standard Atmosphere ?\n",
        "answer": "\u201325\u00baC\n ISA\u2019ya g\u00f6re ; MSL\u2019da s\u0131cakl\u0131k +15\u00baC ve y\u00fckseldik\u00e7e bu s\u0131cakl\u0131k her 1000 feet\u2019de\n",
        "choiceone": "\u201330\u00baC\n",
        "choicetwo": "\u201320\u00baC\n 2\u00baC azalaca\u011f\u0131ndan 20.000 feet\u2019de ISA\u2019ya g\u00f6re olmas\u0131 gereken s\u0131cakl\u0131k ;\n",
        "choicethree": "\u201315\u00baC\n +15\u00baC + ( 20 x \u20132\u00baC ) = +15\u00baC + (\u201340\u00baC ) = \u201325\u00baC olarak bulunur.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is characteristic of the pamperos ?\n",
        "answer": "A marked advance of cold air in South America.\n",
        "choiceone": "Katabatic winds in the Atlas Mountains.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A marked advance of cold arctic air in North America.\n",
        "choicethree": "Foehn conditions in the Spanish Pyrenees.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is determined by a transmissometer ?\n",
        "answer": "Visibility , runway visual range.\n",
        "choiceone": "Air density.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Height of cloud base.\n",
        "choicethree": "Vertical visibility.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is encountered during the summer , over land , in the centre of a cold air pool ?\n",
        "answer": "Showers and thunderstorms.\n",
        "choiceone": "Fine weather CU.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Sky clear ( SKC ).\n",
        "choicethree": "Strong westerly winds.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is meant by QFE ?\n",
        "answer": "The atmospheric pressure at the official aerodrome elevation.\n",
        "choiceone": "The pressure at MSL in standard atmospheric conditions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The present atmospheric pressure at an aerodrome converted to mean sea level in accordance with the actual\n conditions.\n",
        "choicethree": "The atmospheric pressure at the official aerodrome elevation , reduced to mean sea level in standard\n atmospheric conditions.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is meant by QFF ?\n",
        "answer": "The present atmospheric pressure at an aerodrome converted to mean sea level in accordance with the actual\n conditions.\n",
        "choiceone": "The pressure at mean sea level in standard atmospheric conditions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The present atmospheric pressure at an aerodrome converted to mean sea level in accordance with the ICAO\n standard atmosphere.\n",
        "choicethree": "The atmospheric pressure at the official aerodrome elevation.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is meant by the term \u201caltitude\u201d ?\n",
        "answer": "The vertical distance of a level or a point measured from mean sea level.\n",
        "choiceone": "The vertical distance of a level or a point measured from the aerodrome reference point.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Altimeter indication when altimeter subscale is set to present QFE.\n",
        "choicethree": "The vertical distance of a level or a point measured from the earth\u2019s surface.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is \u201cmixing ratio\u201d ?\n",
        "answer": "The number of grammes of water vapour per kilogramme of dry air.\n",
        "choiceone": "The percentage of water drops per volume unit of dry air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The volume of water vapour which is mixed with each volume unit of dry air.\n",
        "choicethree": "The ratio between actual water vapour content and saturated water vapour content.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is necessary for the development of a polar front jet stream ?\n",
        "answer": "Strong horizontal temperature gradients.\n",
        "choiceone": "Strong vertical temperature gradients.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A uniform pressure pattern.\n",
        "choicethree": "An unstable atmosphere up to great heights.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is normally the most effective measure to reduce or avoid CAT effects ?\n",
        "answer": "Change of flight level.\n",
        "choiceone": "Change of course.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Increase of speed.\n",
        "choicethree": "Decrease of speed.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is signified if an occlusion is described as \u201ccold\u201d ?\n",
        "answer": "The air ahead of the associated warm front is less cold than the air behind the associated cold front.\n",
        "choiceone": "On meeting the warm front , the cold front moves up the warm frontal surface.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It derives from a polar depression.\n",
        "choicethree": "The air ahead of the associated warm front is colder than the air behind the associated cold front.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the approximate composition of the dry air by volume in the troposphere ?\n",
        "answer": "21 % oxygen , 78 % nitrogen , and the rest other gasses.\n",
        "choiceone": "50 % oxygen , 40 % nitrogen , and the rest other gasses.\n",
        "choicetwo": "10 % oxygen , 89 % nitrogen , and the rest other gasses.\n",
        "choicethree": "88 % oxygen , 9 % nitrogen , and the rest other gasses.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-2506A )\n Annex 050-2506A\n What is the approximate height of the tropopause between Keflavik and Helsinki ?\n",
        "answer": "FL 320\n",
        "choiceone": "FL 350\n",
        "choicetwo": "FL 360\n",
        "choicethree": "FL 300\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-2506A )\n Annex 050-2506A\n What is the approximate height of the tropopause between Munich and Helsinki ?\n",
        "answer": "FL 340\n",
        "choiceone": "FL 280\n",
        "choicetwo": "FL 390\n",
        "choicethree": "FL 300\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the approximate maximum diameter of a the area affected by damaging winds at the surface caused by a\nmicroburst ?\n",
        "answer": "4 km\n",
        "choiceone": "400 m\n",
        "choicetwo": "50 km\n",
        "choicethree": "20 km\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the approximate ratio between height and width for a jet stream cross section ?\n",
        "answer": "1/100\n",
        "choiceone": "1/1000\n",
        "choicetwo": "1/1\n",
        "choicethree": "1/10\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the approximate speed of a 25-knot wind , expressed in kilometres per hour ?\n",
        "answer": "45 km/h\n",
        "choiceone": "60 km/h\n",
        "choicetwo": "35 km/h 25 kt = 25 NM/h ise ;\n",
        "choicethree": "55 km/h 25 NM/h = 25 x 1,852 = 46,3 \u2248 45 km/h\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the approximate speed of a 40-knot wind , expressed in m/sec ?\n",
        "answer": "20 m/sec 40 kt = 40 NM/h ise ;\n",
        "choiceone": "15 m/sec\n",
        "choicetwo": "30 m/sec\n",
        "choicethree": "25 m/sec 40 NM/h = 40 x 1852 = 74080 m/h , 1 saat 3600 saniye oldu\u011funa g\u00f6re ;\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the approximate speed of a 90 km/h wind , expressed in knots ?\n",
        "answer": "50 kt 90 km/h = 90 x 1,852 = 48,59 NM/h \u2248 50 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "70 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "55 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "60 kt 1 kt = 1 NM/h ve 1 NM = 1,852 km ise ;\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the approximate vertical interval which is equal to a pressure change of 1 hPa at an altitude of 5500 m ?\n",
        "answer": "15 m ( 50 ft ).\n",
        "choiceone": "8 m ( 27 ft ).\n",
        "choicetwo": "64 m ( 210 ft ).\n",
        "choicethree": "32 m ( 105 ft ).\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the approximate vertical interval which is equal to a pressure change of 1 hPa at sea level ?\n",
        "answer": "8 m ( 27 ft ).\n",
        "choiceone": "32 m ( 105 ft ).\n",
        "choicetwo": "64 m ( 210 ft ).\n",
        "choicethree": "15 m ( 50 ft ).\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the average height of the arctic jet stream core ?\n",
        "answer": "20.000 ft .\n",
        "choiceone": "40.000 ft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "50.000 ft.\n",
        "choicethree": "30.000 ft.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the average height of the jet core within a polar front jet stream ?\n",
        "answer": "30.000 ft.\n",
        "choiceone": "50.000 ft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "20.000 ft.\n",
        "choicethree": "40.000 ft.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-2547A )\n Annex 050-2547A\n What is the average temperature at FL 160 between Oslo and Paris ?\n",
        "answer": "\u201319\u00b0C\n",
        "choiceone": "\u201325\u00b0C\n",
        "choicetwo": "\u201323\u00b0C\n",
        "choicethree": "\u201315\u00b0C\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10896A )\n Annex 050-10896A\n What is the average temperature difference from ISA at FL 300 between Edinburgh and Madrid ?\n",
        "answer": "\u20132\u00b0C\n",
        "choiceone": "\u201312\u00b0C\n",
        "choicetwo": "+2\u00b0C\n",
        "choicethree": "+12\u00b0C\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10901A )\n Annex 050-10901A\n What is the average temperature difference from ISA at FL 390 between Madrid and Dhahran ?\n",
        "answer": "\u20131\u00b0C\n",
        "choiceone": "\u20135\u00b0C\n",
        "choicetwo": "+5\u00b0C\n",
        "choicethree": "+2\u00b0C\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the average vertical extent of radiation fog ?\n",
        "answer": "500 ft.\n",
        "choiceone": "5000 ft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2000 ft.\n",
        "choicethree": "10000 ft.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10896A )\n Annex 050-10896A\n What is the average wind forecast for FL 300 between Edinburgh and Madrid ?\n",
        "answer": "280/30\n",
        "choiceone": "180/20\n",
        "choicetwo": "240/25\n",
        "choicethree": "300/45\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the best approximation for the wind speed at flight level 250 ?\n",
        "answer": "By interpolation of the wind information available from the 500 and 300 hPa charts , while also considering\n the maximum wind information found on the Significant Weather Chart.\n",
        "choiceone": "By reading wind direction and speed from the 300 hPa chart.\n",
        "choicetwo": "By simple interpolation of wind information available from the 500 and 300 hPa charts.\n",
        "choicethree": "By reading wind direction and speed from the 500 hPa chart.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the best way in dealing with thunderstorms associated with a cold front ?\n",
        "answer": "Avoidance of embedded CBs by using airborne weather radar.\n",
        "choiceone": "Flying underneath the cloud base in all cases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Flying though the upper third of the clouds to prevent the aircraft from being struck by lightning.\n",
        "choicethree": "Flying through the front with maximum speed and perpendicular to the front line in order to minimize the\n time of hazard exposure.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the boundary layer between troposphere and stratosphere called ?\n",
        "answer": "Tropopause.\n",
        "choiceone": "Ionosphere.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Atmosphere.\n",
        "choicethree": "Stratosphere.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-2065A )\n Annex 050-2065A\n What is the classification of the air mass affecting position \u201cQ\u201d at 0600 UTC ?\n",
        "answer": "Tropical maritime.\n",
        "choiceone": "Polar maritime.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Tropical continental.\n",
        "choicethree": "Polar continental.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the correct term for the descending air flow in a large high pressure area ?\n",
        "answer": "Subsidence.\n",
        "choiceone": "Convection.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Convergence.\n",
        "choicethree": "Advection.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4371A rev. 10.11.2002 )\n Annex 050-4371A\n What is the deviation of the temperature at FL 140 above Copenhagen compared to ISA ?\n",
        "answer": "8\u00b0C colder than ISA.\n",
        "choiceone": "4\u00b0C warmer than ISA.\n",
        "choicetwo": "12\u00b0C colder than ISA.\n",
        "choicethree": "8\u00b0C warmer than ISA.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the difference between radiation fog and advection fog ?\n",
        "answer": "Radiation fog forms due to surface cooling at night in a light wind. Advection fog forms when warm humid\n air flows over a cold surface.\n",
        "choiceone": "Radiation fog forms only on the ground , advection fog only on the sea.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Radiation fog forms due to night cooling and advection fog due to daytime cooling.\n",
        "choicethree": "Radiation fog is formed by surface cooling in a calm wind. Advection fog is formed by evaporation over the\n sea.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the dry adiabatic lapse rate ?\n",
        "answer": "3.0\u00b0C / 1000 ft.\n",
        "choiceone": "1.5\u00b0C / 1000 ft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2.0\u00b0C / 1000 ft.\n",
        "choicethree": "3.5\u00b0C / 1000 ft.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the effect of a strong low level inversion ?\n",
        "answer": "It promotes vertical wind shear.\n",
        "choiceone": "It prevents vertical wind shear.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It results in good visual conditions near the surface.\n",
        "choicethree": "It promotes extensive vertical movement of air.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the height of the lowest cloud forecast for Bangkok at ETA 1400 UTC ?\n TAF VTBD 271800Z 280024 VRB05KT 1200 BR TEMPO 0002 4000 BECMG 0205 9999 SCT015 BKN100 TEMPO 1118\n 04010G20KT 5000 TSRA SCT009 BKN014 BKN018CB BECMG 2024 6000 =\n",
        "answer": "900 feet\n",
        "choiceone": "1200 feet\n",
        "choicetwo": "1400 feet\n",
        "choicethree": "1800 feet\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the ICAO qualifying term for the described intensity of turbulence ; \u201cConditions in which abrupt changes in aircraft\nattitude and/or altitude occur , aircraft may be out of control for short periods\u201d ?\n",
        "answer": "Severe\n",
        "choiceone": "Noticeable\n",
        "choicetwo": "Light\n",
        "choicethree": "Moderate\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the likely track for a hurricane in the Caribbean area ?\n",
        "answer": "West in the earlier stages and later turning north east.\n",
        "choiceone": "West deep into the USA.\n",
        "choicetwo": "East then south.\n",
        "choicethree": "West in the earlier stages and later turning south east.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the lowest cloud base forecast at ETA Zurich 1200 UTC ?\n LSZH 060900Z 061019 20018G30KT 9999 -RA SCT050 BKN080 TEMPO 1113 23012KT 6000 -DZ BKN015 BKN030\n BECMG 1518 23020G35KT 4000 RA OVC010 =\n",
        "answer": "1500 ft.\n",
        "choiceone": "1000 ft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5000 ft.\n",
        "choicethree": "1500 m.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the lowest cloud base forecast for arrival at Geneva ( ETA 1200 UTC ) ?\n TAF LSGG 020900Z 021019 18007KT 9999 SCT020 BKN100 BECMG 1114 8000 RA SCT010 OVC020 PROB30\n TEMPO 1018 VRB10G25KT TSRA SCT005 BKN015CB =\n",
        "answer": "500 ft\n",
        "choiceone": "1000 ft\n",
        "choicetwo": "500 m\n",
        "choicethree": "1000 m\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the lowest cloud base that can be expected from the forecast for 1500 UTC ?\n KCHS 280430Z 280606 VRB05KT 4000 BR SCT005 OVC013 PROB40 SHRA BECMG 1314 9000 SHRA OVC015\n PROB40 TEMPO 1416 VRB15G25KT 1600 TSRA OVC010CB BECMG 1618 26010KT BKN030 BECMG 2122 CAVOK\n",
        "answer": "1000 feet\n",
        "choiceone": "1300 feet\n",
        "choicetwo": "1500 feet\n",
        "choicethree": "3000 feet\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the lowest forecast visibility that can be expected during an approach into Madrid at 2300 UTC ?\n TAF LEMD 281200Z 281812 13005KT CAVOK TEMPO 1821 8000 SCT020 SCT030 BECMG 2123 21005KT 9999\n SCT015 BKN080 PROB40 TEMPO 2306 6000 SCT008 =\n",
        "answer": "10 kilometres or more\n",
        "choiceone": "8000 metres\n",
        "choicetwo": "6000 metres\n",
        "choicethree": "Greater than 10 kilometres\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the lowest possible cloud base forecast for 2300 UTC ?\n EDDF 272200Z 280624 VRB05KT 4000 BR SCT005 OVC013 BECMG 1314 9000 SHRA OVC015 PROB40 TEMPO\n 1416 VRB15G25KT 1600 TSRA OVC010CB BECMG 1618 26010KT BKN030 BECMG 2122 CAVOK =\n",
        "answer": "5000 feet\n",
        "choiceone": "1500 feet\n",
        "choicetwo": "3000 feet\n",
        "choicethree": "500 feet\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the lowest probable cloud base forecast for ETA 1700 UTC at Kingston ?\n TAF MKJP 160000Z 160606 36010KT 9999 FEW025 BECMG 1315 14020G34KT FEW015CB SCT025 PROB30 TEMPO\n 1520 6000 +SHRA SCT010 BKN015CB BECMG 2301 34010KT FEW025 =\n",
        "answer": "1000 ft\n",
        "choiceone": "1500 m\n",
        "choicetwo": "1000 m\n",
        "choicethree": "1500 ft\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the lowest visibility forecast at ETA Zurich 1430 UTC ?\n LSZH 260900Z 261019 20018G30KT 9999 -RA SCT050 BKN080 TEMPO 1215 23012KT 6000 -DZ BKN015 BKN030\n BECMG 1518 23020G35KT 4000 RA OVC010 =\n",
        "answer": "6 km.\n",
        "choiceone": "6 NM.\n",
        "choicetwo": "10 km.\n",
        "choicethree": "4 km.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the lowest visibility forecast for approach into Geneva ( ETA 1200 UTC ) ?\n TAF LSGG 020900Z 021019 18007KT 9999 SCT020 BKN100 BECMG 1114 8000 RA SCT010 OVC020 PROB30\n TEMPO 1018 VRB10G25KT TSRA SCT005 BKN015CB =\n",
        "answer": "8 km.\n",
        "choiceone": "6 NM.\n",
        "choicetwo": "10 km.\n",
        "choicethree": "8 NM.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the lowest visibility forecast for Bangkok at ETA 1400 UTC ?\n TAF VTBD 271800Z 280024 VRB05KT 1200 BR TEMPO 0002 4000 BECMG 0205 9999 SCT015 BKN100 TEMPO 1118\n 04010G20KT 5000 TSRA SCT009 BKN014 BKN018CB BECMG 2024 6000 =\n",
        "answer": "5 km.\n",
        "choiceone": "1200 metres.\n",
        "choicetwo": "10 km or more.\n",
        "choicethree": "6 km.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the lowest visibility that may be expected during an approach into Dhahran at ETA 0600 UTC ?\n TAF OEDR 280000Z 280110 VRB08KT CAVOK BECMG 0103 7000 TEMPO 0410 28014G24KT 4000 SA =\n",
        "answer": "4 km.\n",
        "choiceone": "4000 yards.\n",
        "choicetwo": "10 km or more.\n",
        "choicethree": "7 km.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the main cause for the formation of a polar front jet stream ?\n",
        "answer": "The north-south horizontal temperature gradient at the polar front.\n",
        "choiceone": "Strong winds in the upper atmosphere.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The varied elevations of the tropopause in the polar front region.\n",
        "choicethree": "The pressure difference , close to the ground , between a high over the Azores and a low over Iceland.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the main composition of clouds classified as \u201chigh level clouds\u201d ?\n",
        "answer": "Ice crystals.\n",
        "choiceone": "Water droplets.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Supercooled water droplets.\n",
        "choicethree": "Water vapour.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the main energy source of a tropical revolving storm ?\n",
        "answer": "Latent heat released from condensing water vapour.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cold air advancing from temperate latitudes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Temperature difference between equatorial low pressure trough and subtropical high pressure belt.\n",
        "choicethree": "The equatorial jet stream.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4370A rev. 10.11.2002 )\n What is the mean temperature deviation from ISA for the route Frankfurt - Rome at FL 180 ?\n",
        "answer": "4\u00b0C colder than ISA.\n",
        "choiceone": "4\u00b0C warmer than ISA.\n",
        "choicetwo": "10\u00b0C warmer than ISA.\n",
        "choicethree": "10\u00b0C colder than ISA.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the meaning of \u201cRERA\u201d in a METAR ?\n",
        "answer": "There has been moderate or heavy rain since the last issue of METAR.\n",
        "choiceone": "The intensity of rain is decreasing ( Retrograding Rain ).\n",
        "choicetwo": "There is showery precipitation in the vicinity.\n",
        "choicethree": "It is presently not raining , but there has been rain 2 hours ago.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the meaning of the abbreviation \u201cSCT\u201d ?\n",
        "answer": "3 - 4 oktas.\n",
        "choiceone": "5 - 7 oktas.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 - 2 oktas.\n",
        "choicethree": "1 - 4 oktas.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the meaning of the different coloured areas on a plan position indicator of an airborne weather radar ?\n",
        "answer": "Different ranges of intensities of precipitation.\n",
        "choiceone": "Different intensities of turbulence ( light , moderate , severe ) within clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Different ranges of cloud thickness ( vertical extent ).\n",
        "choicethree": "Different horizontal dimensions of cloud.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the meaning of the expression \u201cFEW\u201d ?\n",
        "answer": "1 - 2 oktas.\n",
        "choiceone": "5 - 7 oktas.\n",
        "choicetwo": "8 oktas.\n",
        "choicethree": "3 - 4 oktas.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the meaning of the following weather message ?\n CNL WS WRNG 1 211130/211330 =\n",
        "answer": "The first wind shear warning on the 21st of that month , issued at 1130 UTC has been cancelled at the same\n day at 1330 UTC.\n",
        "choiceone": "The weather warning with the number 121 concerning a cyclone at low levels has a validity time from 1130\n until 1330 UTC.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The first wind shear warning on the 21st of that month with an occasional intensity has a forecast validity\n from 1130 until 1330 UTC.\n",
        "choicethree": "This message cancels all weather warnings issued on the 21st of January between 1130 and 1330 UTC.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the minimum speed for a wind to be classified as a jet stream ?\n",
        "answer": "60 kt.\n",
        "choiceone": "70 kt.\n",
        "choicetwo": "100 kt.\n",
        "choicethree": "50 kt.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the most likely cause of a lack of clouds at higher levels in a stationary high ?\n",
        "answer": "Sinking air.\n",
        "choiceone": "Instability.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Rising air.\n",
        "choicethree": "Divergence at higher levels.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the most likely forecast lowest cloud base that can be expected during an approach to Madrid into 2300 UTC ?\n TAF LEMD 281200Z 281812 13005KT CAVOK TEMPO 1821 8000 SCT020 SCT030 BECMG 2123 21005KT 9999\n SCT015 BKN080 PROB40 TEMPO 2306 6000 SCT008 =\n",
        "answer": "1500 feet\n",
        "choiceone": "2000 feet\n",
        "choicetwo": "800 feet\n",
        "choicethree": "3000 feet\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the most likely temperature at the tropical tropopause ?\n",
        "answer": "\u201375\u00b0C.\n",
        "choiceone": "\u201335\u00b0C.\n",
        "choicetwo": "\u201355\u00b0C.\n",
        "choicethree": "\u201325\u00b0C.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the most probable temperature at the tropical tropopause ?\n",
        "answer": "\u201375\u00b0C.\n",
        "choiceone": "\u201325\u00b0C.\n",
        "choicetwo": "\u201355\u00b0C.\n",
        "choicethree": "\u201335\u00b0C.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the most significant difference between an equatorial jet stream and all the other jet streams ?\n",
        "answer": "Wind direction.\n",
        "choiceone": "Wind speed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Vertical dimension.\n",
        "choicethree": "Horizontal dimension.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the northerly , cold and strong wind , that sometimes blows over a certain part of Europe ?\n",
        "answer": "Mistral.\n",
        "choiceone": "Typhoon.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Bora.\n",
        "choicethree": "Foehn.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the wind or air mass which gives to the main part of India its greatest proportion of precipitation ?\n",
        "answer": "South-west monsoon.\n",
        "choiceone": "South-east trade wind.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Indian , maritime tropical air mass.\n",
        "choicethree": "Winter monsoon.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-2504A )\n Annex 050-2504A\n What is the optimum flight level between Rome and Paris according to the significant weather chart ?\n",
        "answer": "FL 220\n",
        "choiceone": "FL 360\n",
        "choicetwo": "FL 340\n",
        "choicethree": "FL 160\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the relationship between visibility and RVR in homogeneous fog ?\n",
        "answer": "The visibility generally is less than the RVR.\n",
        "choiceone": "The visibility generally is greater than the RVR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The visibility generally is the same as the RVR.\n",
        "choicethree": "There is no specific relationship between the two.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the relationship , if any , between QFE and QNH at an airport situated 50 ft below sea level ?\n",
        "answer": "QFE is greater than QNH.\n",
        "choiceone": "No clear relationship exists.\n",
        "choicetwo": "QFE is smaller than QNH.\n",
        "choicethree": "QFE equals QNH.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the relative movement of the two air masses along a cold front ?\n",
        "answer": "Cold air pushes under a warm air mass.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cold air slides over a warm air mass.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Warm air pushes under a cold air mass.\n",
        "choicethree": "Warm air pushes over a cold air mass.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the significance to aviation of breaks or steps in the tropopause ?\n",
        "answer": "they indicate the position of strong upper winds.\n",
        "choiceone": "they indicate light winds at the surface ( the horse latitudes )\n",
        "choicetwo": "they indicate the position and movement of anticyclones.\n",
        "choicethree": "they indicate the position and movement of tropical revolving storms.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-2549A )\n Annex 050-2549A\n What is the speed of the front located over France ?\n",
        "answer": "15 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "25 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "30 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "10 kt\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the strong relatively cold katabatic wind , blowing down the northern Adriatic coast , mainly during the winter and\nspring called ?\n",
        "answer": "Bora.\n",
        "choiceone": "Scirocco.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Mistral.\n",
        "choicethree": "Ghibli.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the surface visibility most likely to be , in a warm sector of tropical maritime air , during a summer afternoon in\nwestern Europe ?\n",
        "answer": "Moderate ( several km ).\n",
        "choiceone": "Good ( greater than 10 km ).\n",
        "choicetwo": "Very good ( greater than 50 km ).\n",
        "choicethree": "Very poor ( less than 1 km ).\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 10 )\n Image 10\n What is the symbol for hail on a significant weather chart ?\n",
        "answer": "Symbol 2\n",
        "choiceone": "Symbol 3\n",
        "choicetwo": "Symbol 1\n",
        "choicethree": "Symbol 4\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the technical term for an increase in temperature with altitude ?\n",
        "answer": "Inversion\n",
        "choiceone": "Advection\n",
        "choicetwo": "Adiabatic\n",
        "choicethree": "Subsidence\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the temperature at 20.000 ft in the ICAO Standard Atmosphere ?\n",
        "answer": "\u201325\u00b0C\n 1000 feet\u2019de 2\u00b0C d\u00fc\u015fer. Buna g\u00f6re ;\n",
        "choiceone": "\u201330\u00b0C\n",
        "choicetwo": "\u201320\u00b0C\n ISA\u2019ya g\u00f6re MSL\u2019da s\u0131cakl\u0131k +15\u00b0C\u2019dir ve y\u00fckseklikle beraber her\n",
        "choicethree": "\u201315\u00b0C\n ( +15\u00b0C ) \u2013 [ 20 x ( \u20132\u00b0C ) ] = ( +15\u00b0C ) \u2013 ( \u201340\u00b0C ) = \u201325\u00b0C\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-2548A )\n Annex 050-2548A\n What is the temperature deviation in degrees Celsius , from the ICAO Standard Atmosphere overhead Frankfurt ?\n",
        "answer": "ISA \u2013 13\u00b0C 2\u00b0C d\u00fc\u015fer. Buna g\u00f6re FL180\u2019da ISA\u2019ya g\u00f6re s\u0131cakl\u0131k ;\n",
        "choiceone": "ISA \u2013 2\u00b0C\n",
        "choicetwo": "ISA + 2\u00b0C Haritaya g\u00f6re Frankfurt \u00fczerinde FL180\u2019daki hava s\u0131cakl\u0131\u011f\u0131 \u201334\u00b0C\u2019dir.\n",
        "choicethree": "ISA + 13\u00b0C ISA\u2019ya g\u00f6re MSL\u2019da s\u0131cakl\u0131k +15\u00b0C\u2019dir ve y\u00fckseklikle beraber her 1000 feet\u2019de\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the type , intensity and seasonal variation of precipitation in the equatorial region ?\n",
        "answer": "Rainshowers , hail showers and thunderstorms occur the whole year , but frequency is highest during two\n periods: April-May and October-November.\n",
        "choiceone": "Precipitation is generally in the form of showers but continuous rain occurs also. The greatest intensity is in\n July.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Warm fronts are common with continuous rain. The frequency is the same throughout the year.\n",
        "choicethree": "Showers of rain or hail occur throughout the year , the frequency is highest in January.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the wind speed given in a METAR report based on ?\n",
        "answer": "The average speed of the previous 10 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "The actual speed at the time of recording.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The strongest gust in the previous hour.\n",
        "choicethree": "The average speed of the previous 30 minutes.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is true for the water vapour distribution in the layer between the surface and the 500 hPa pressure surface in the\ntradewind belt ?\n",
        "answer": "The lower part is relatively moist and the upper part is relatively dry.\n",
        "choiceone": "The whole layer is relatively dry.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The whole layer is relatively moist.\n",
        "choicethree": "The lower part is relatively dry and the upper part is relatively moist.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What jet streams are likely to be crossed during a flight from Stockholm to Rio de Janeiro ( 23\u00b0S ) at FL 350 in July ?\n",
        "answer": "A polar front jet stream followed by one or two subtropical jet streams.\n",
        "choiceone": "A polar front jet stream followed by a subtropical jet stream and later , a second polar front jet stream.\n",
        "choicetwo": "One subtropical jet stream.\n",
        "choicethree": "A subtropical jet stream followed by a polar front jet stream.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What kind of fog is often observed in the coastal region of Newfoundland in spring time ?\n",
        "answer": "Advection fog.\n",
        "choiceone": "Frontal fog.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Steaming fog.\n",
        "choicethree": "Radiation fog.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What kind of turbulence is caused by the friction of air flowing over the earth\u2019s surface ?\n",
        "answer": "Mechanical turbulence.\n",
        "choiceone": "Clear air turbulence.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Convective turbulence.\n",
        "choicethree": "Turbulence in downdrafts.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What kind of turbulence is dependent on the sun\u2019s radiation and therefore follows a pronounced diurnal pattern ?\n",
        "answer": "Convective turbulence.\n",
        "choiceone": "Turbulence induced by wind speed\n",
        "choicetwo": "Orographic turbulence.\n",
        "choicethree": "Mechanical turbulence.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What lowest cloud base is most likely to be experienced during an approach into Madrid at 2300 UTC ?\n TAF LEMD 281200Z 281812 13005KT CAVOK TEMPO 1821 8000 SCT020 SCT030 BECMG 2123 21005KT 9999\n SCT015 BKN080 PROB40 TEMPO 2306 6000 SCT008 =\n",
        "answer": "1500 feet\n",
        "choiceone": "3000 feet\n",
        "choicetwo": "2000 feet\n",
        "choicethree": "800 feet\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-2541A )\n Annex 050-2541A\n What name is given to the jet stream lying across India (A) ?\n",
        "answer": "Tropical jet stream.\n",
        "choiceone": "Polar front jet stream.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Sub-tropical jet stream.\n",
        "choicethree": "Arctic jet stream.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-2541A )\n Annex 050-2541A\n What name is given to the jet stream lying over North Africa ( B ) ?\n",
        "answer": "Sub-tropical jet stream\n",
        "choiceone": "Arctic jet stream\n",
        "choicetwo": "Polar front jet stream\n",
        "choicethree": "Equatorial jet stream\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-2541A )\n Annex 050-2541A\n What name is given to the jet stream lying over Scandinavia ( C ) ?\n",
        "answer": "Polar front jet stream\n",
        "choiceone": "Tropical jet stream.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Low level jet stream.\n",
        "choicethree": "Sub-tropical jet stream.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What name is given to the low level wind system between the subtropical high pressure belt and the equatorial trough of low\npressure ( ITCZ ) ?\n",
        "answer": "Trade winds.\n",
        "choiceone": "Monsoon.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Westerly winds.\n",
        "choicethree": "Doldrums.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-2558A )\n Annex 050-2558A\n What OAT would you expect at FL 200 over Geneva ?\n",
        "answer": "\u201324\u00b0C\n Y\u00fckseklikle beraber s\u0131cakl\u0131k her 1000 feet\u2019de 2\u00b0C d\u00fc\u015fece\u011fine g\u00f6re FL200\u2019daki s\u0131cakl\u0131k ;\n",
        "choiceone": "\u201316\u00b0C\n",
        "choicetwo": "\u201328\u00b0C\n Haritaya g\u00f6re Geneva \u00fczerinde FL180\u2019daki ortalama hava s\u0131cakl\u0131\u011f\u0131 \u201320\u00b0C\u2019dir.\n",
        "choicethree": "\u201320\u00b0C\n ( \u201320\u00b0C ) + ( 2 x \u20132\u00b0C ) = \u201324\u00b0C\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What of the following is the most important constituent in the atmosphere from a weather stand-point ?\n",
        "answer": "Water vapour\n",
        "choiceone": "Nitrogen\n",
        "choicetwo": "Hydrogen\n",
        "choicethree": "Oxygen\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What positions are connected by contour lines on a weather chart ?\n",
        "answer": "Positions with the same height in a chart of constant pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "Positions with the same air density.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Positions with the same wind velocity.\n",
        "choicethree": "Positions with the same thickness between two constant pressure levels.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What positions are connected by isobars on the surface weather chart ?\n",
        "answer": "Positions with the same air pressure at a given level.\n",
        "choiceone": "Positions with the same wind velocity at a given level.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Positions with the same temperature at a given level.\n",
        "choicethree": "Positions with the same relative pressure heights.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What pressure is defined as QFE ?\n",
        "answer": "The pressure at field elevation.\n",
        "choiceone": "The pressure of the altimeter.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The pressure reduced to sea level using actual temperatures.\n",
        "choicethree": "The pressure reduced to sea level using ISA temperatures.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What prevents air from flowing directly from high-pressure areas to low-pressure areas ?\n",
        "answer": "Coriolis force.\n",
        "choiceone": "The pressure gradient force.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Katabatic force.\n",
        "choicethree": "Surface friction.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What process in an air mass leads to the creation of wide spread NS and AS cloud coverage ?\n",
        "answer": "Lifting\n",
        "choiceone": "Sinking\n",
        "choicetwo": "Convection process\n",
        "choicethree": "Radiation\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What relationship exists between the wind at 3000 feet and the surface wind ?\n",
        "answer": "The wind at 3000 feet is parallel to the isohypses and the surface wind direction is across the isobars toward\n the low pressure and the surface wind is weaker.\n",
        "choiceone": "They are practically the same , except when eddies exist , caused by obstacles\n",
        "choicetwo": "The surface wind is veered compared to the wind at 3000 feet and is usually weaker.\n",
        "choicethree": "They have the same direction , but the surface wind is weaker , caused by friction\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What surface weather is associated with a stationary high pressure region over land in the winter ?\n",
        "answer": "A tendency for fog and low ST.\n",
        "choiceone": "The possibility of snow showers.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Thunderstorms.\n",
        "choicethree": "NS with continuous rain.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What surface wind is forecast for 2200 UTC ?\n EDDF 272200Z 280624 VRB05KT 4000 BR SCT005 OVC013 BECMG 1314 9000 SHRA OVC015 PROB40 TEMPO\n 1416 VRB15G25KT 1600 TSRA OVC010CB BECMG 1618 26010KT BKN030 BECMG 2122 CAVOK =\n",
        "answer": "260\u00b0 / 10 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "Variable / 15 to 25 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "Variable / 05 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "Calm\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What surface wind is forecast for ETA 1700 UTC at Kingston ?\n MKJP 160430Z 160606 36010KT 9999 FEW025CB BECMG1315 14020G34KT FEW015CB SCT025 PROB30 TEMPO\n 1720 6000 +SHRA SCT010 BKN015CB BECMG 2301 34010KT FEW025 =\n",
        "answer": "140\u00b0 / 20 kt gusts 34 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "360\u00b0 / 10 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "340\u00b0 / 10 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "140\u00b0 / 27 kt\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of air movement is associated with the centre line of a trough ?\n",
        "answer": "Convergence with lifting.\n",
        "choiceone": "Convergence with descending air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Divergence with descending air.\n",
        "choicethree": "Divergence with lifting.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of cloud can produce hail showers ?\n",
        "answer": "CB\n",
        "choiceone": "NS\n",
        "choicetwo": "CS\n",
        "choicethree": "AC\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of cloud is being described ?\n A generally grey cloud layer with fairly uniform base and uniform appearance , which may give drizzle or snow grains.When\nthe sun is visible through the cloud , the outline is clearly discernible. Sometimes it appears in the form of ragged patches.\n",
        "answer": "Stratus\n",
        "choiceone": "Altostratus\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cirrostratus\n",
        "choicethree": "Nimbostratus\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of clouds are associated with rain showers ?\n",
        "answer": "Towering cumulus and cumulonimbus.\n",
        "choiceone": "Altostratus and stratus.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Towering cumulus and altostratus.\n",
        "choicethree": "Nimbostratus.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of clouds are associated with snow showers ?\n",
        "answer": "Cumulus and cumulonimbus.\n",
        "choiceone": "Nimbostratus.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cumulus and altostratus.\n",
        "choicethree": "Altostratus and stratus.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of fog is most likely to form over flat land during a clear night , with calm or light wind conditions ?\n",
        "answer": "Radiation.\n",
        "choiceone": "Steam.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Advection.\n",
        "choicethree": "Orographic.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of front / occlusion usually moves the fastest ?\n",
        "answer": "Cold front.\n",
        "choiceone": "Warm front.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cold occlusion.\n",
        "choicethree": "Warm occlusion.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of fronts are most likely to be present during the winter in Central Europe when temperatures close to the ground\nare below 0\u00b0C , and freezing rain starts to fall ?\n",
        "answer": "Warm fronts , warm occlusions.\n",
        "choiceone": "High level cold fronts.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cold fronts.\n",
        "choicethree": "Cold occlusions.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of low pressure area is associated with a surface front ?\n",
        "answer": "Polar front low.\n",
        "choiceone": "A low on lee side of a mountain.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Heat low.\n",
        "choicethree": "A cold air pool.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of meteorological hazard to safe flight is most likely to be experienced during the final approach to Geneva ( ETA\n1200 UTC ) ?\n TAF LSGG 020900Z 021019 18007KT 9999 SCT020 BKN100 BECMG 1114 8000 RA SCT010 OVC020 PROB30\n TEMPO 1018 VRB10G25KT TSRA SCT005 BKN015CB =\n",
        "answer": "Low level wind shear.\n",
        "choiceone": "Radiation fog.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Roll cloud associated with standing waves.\n",
        "choicethree": "Anabatic winds.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of precipitation might occur at 1700 UTC ?\n MKJP 160430Z 160606 36010KT 9999 FEW025 BECMG 1315 14020G34KT FEW015CB SCT025 PROB30 TEMPO 1720\n 6000 +SHRA SCT010 BKN015CB BECMG 2224 34010KT FEW025 =\n",
        "answer": "Heavy rain showers.\n",
        "choiceone": "Continuous moderate rain.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Intermittent light rain.\n",
        "choicethree": "Light drizzle.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of precipitation might occur at 1730 UTC ?\n MKJP 160430Z 160606 36010KT 9999 FEW025 BECMG 1315 14020G34KT FEW015CB SCT025 PROB30 TEMPO 1720\n 2500 +SHRA SCT010 BKN015CB BECMG 2224 34010KT FEW025 =\n",
        "answer": "Heavy rain showers.\n",
        "choiceone": "Light drizzle.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Intermittent light rain.\n",
        "choicethree": "Continuous moderate rain.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of precipitation would you expect at an active unstable cold front ?\n",
        "answer": "Showers associated with thunderstorms.\n",
        "choiceone": "Drizzle.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Light to moderate continuous rain.\n",
        "choicethree": "Freezing rain.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of weather can usually be expected in a polar maritime air mass over central Europe in the daytime during\nsummer ?\n",
        "answer": "Showers and good visibility.\n",
        "choiceone": "Drizzle and low stratus.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Continuous rain and poor visibility.\n",
        "choicethree": "Sky clear.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What types of cloud will you meet flying towards a warm front ?\n",
        "answer": "At some 800 km CS , later AS , and at some 300 km NS until the front.\n",
        "choiceone": "Extensive areas of fog. At some 100 km from the front NS begin.\n",
        "choicetwo": "At some 500 km from the front , groups of CB , later at some 250 km thickening AS.\n",
        "choicethree": "At some 500 km AS , later CS and at some 80 km before the front CB.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What types of cloud will you see flying at FL 50 towards a warm front ?\n",
        "answer": "At some 800 km CS , later AS , and at some 300 km NS until the front.\n",
        "choiceone": "Mainly clear skies. At some 100 km from the front NS begins.\n",
        "choicetwo": "At some 500 km from the front , groups of CB , later at some 250 km thickening AS.\n",
        "choicethree": "At some 500 km AS , later CS and at some 80 km before the front CB.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What units are used to report vertical wind shear ?\n",
        "answer": "kt/100 ft.\n",
        "choiceone": "kt.\n",
        "choicetwo": "m/100 ft.\n",
        "choicethree": "m/sec.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What values are used for the forecasted wind at higher levels ?\n",
        "answer": "Direction relative to true north and speed in knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "Direction relative to magnetic north and speed in knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Direction relative to grid north and speed in km/h.\n",
        "choicethree": "Direction relative to magnetic north and speed in km/h.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What visibility is most likely to be experienced at 1400 UTC ?\n EDDF 272200Z 280624 VRB05KT 4000 BR SCT005 OVC013 BECMG 1314 9000 SHRA OVC015 PROB40 TEMPO\n 1416 VRB15G25KT 1600 TSRA OVC010CB BECMG 1618 26010KT BKN030 BECMG 2122 CAVOK =\n",
        "answer": "9000 metres\n",
        "choiceone": "4000 metres\n",
        "choicetwo": "1000 metres\n",
        "choicethree": "1600 metres\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What visibility is most likely to be experienced during an approach into Madrid at 2300 UTC ?\n TAF LEMD 281200Z 281812 13005KT CAVOK TEMPO 1821 8000 SCT020 SCT030 BECMG 2123 21005KT 9999\n SCT015 BKN080 PROB40 TEMPO 2306 6000 SCT008 =\n",
        "answer": "10 kilometres or more.\n",
        "choiceone": "6000 metres.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Greater than 10 kilometres.\n",
        "choicethree": "8000 metres.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-2433A )\n Annex 050-2433A\n What weather conditions are expected at Paris airport ( LFPO ) around 0550 UTC ?\n",
        "answer": "23014KT 3000 +RA SCT008 OVC025 15/13 Q1004 NOSIG =\n",
        "choiceone": "26012KT 9999 SCT025 SCT040 14/09 Q1018 TEMPO 5000 SHRA =\n",
        "choicetwo": "22020G36KT 1500 TSGR SCT004 BKN007 BKN025CB 18/13 Q1009 BECMG NSW =\n",
        "choicethree": "20004KT 8000 SCT110 SCT250 22/08 Q1016 NOSIG =\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What weather conditions are indications of the summer monsoon in India ?\n",
        "answer": "Thunderstorms , showers of heavy rain.\n",
        "choiceone": "Fog.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Sandstorms.\n",
        "choicethree": "Stratus clouds and drizzle.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10799A )\n Annex 050-10799A\n What weather conditions are most likely to affect an approach to Dakar during July ?\n",
        "answer": "Wet and thundery due to the proximity of the intertropical convergence zone ( ITCZ ).\n",
        "choiceone": "Generally clear skies - NW trade winds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Dry and clear due to the influence of the Azores high pressure system.\n",
        "choicethree": "Reduced visibility due to the rising sand of the Harmattan.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What weather conditions are prevalent during the summer , over the North Sea , approximately 300 km behind a quickly\nmoving cold front ?\n",
        "answer": "Cloud cover mostly scattered , isolated showers.\n",
        "choiceone": "8 octas CS , AS without precipitation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Advection fog.\n",
        "choicethree": "Rain covering a large area , 8 octas NS.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What weather conditions in the region of the Alps would you expect with Foehn from south ?\n",
        "answer": "Clouds , on the southern sides of passes in the Alps.\n",
        "choiceone": "Strong north winds on the southern side of the Alps.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Heavy clear air turbulence on the southern side of the Alps.\n",
        "choicethree": "Heavy airframe icing conditions on the northern side of the Alps.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What weather conditions would you expect at a squall line ?\n",
        "answer": "Thunderstorms.\n",
        "choiceone": "Strong whirlwinds reaching up to higher levels.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Continuous heavy rain.\n",
        "choicethree": "Fog.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What weather is prevalent in easterly waves ?\n",
        "answer": "Thunderstorms and rain.\n",
        "choiceone": "Frontal weather.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Clear skies.\n",
        "choicethree": "Continuous rain.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will be the effect on the reading of an altimeter of an aircraft parked on the ground as an active cold front is passing ?\n",
        "answer": "It will first increase then decrease.\n",
        "choiceone": "It will fluctuate up and down by about +/- 50 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It will first decrease then increase.\n",
        "choicethree": "It will remain unchanged.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will be the effect on the reading of an altimeter of an aircraft parked on the ground during the period following the\npassage of an active cold front ?\n",
        "answer": "It will have decreased.\n",
        "choiceone": "It will show a small increase or decrease.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It will have increased.\n",
        "choicethree": "It will remain unchanged.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will be the effect on the reading of an altimeter of an aircraft parked on the ground shortly before an active cold front\npasses ?\n",
        "answer": "It will be increasing.\n",
        "choiceone": "It will remain unchanged.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It will be decreasing.\n",
        "choicethree": "It will fluctuate up and down by about +/- 50 feet.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-2388A rev. 20.01.2003 )\n Annex 050-2388A\n What wind direction will occur at point B ?\n",
        "answer": "Southwest\n",
        "choiceone": "Northwest\n",
        "choicetwo": "Southeast\n",
        "choicethree": "East\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-2388A rev. 20.01.2003 )\n Annex 050-2388A\n What wind direction will occur over the land at point E ?\n",
        "answer": "West\n",
        "choiceone": "Northeast\n",
        "choicetwo": "Southwest\n",
        "choicethree": "Southeast\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-2388A rev. 20.01.2003 )\n Annex 050-2388A\n What wind direction will occur over the sea at point F ?\n",
        "answer": "South\n",
        "choiceone": "Northwest\n",
        "choicetwo": "Southeast\n",
        "choicethree": "Northeast\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-2545A )\n Annex 050-2545A\n What wind is forecast at FL 390 over Paris ?\n",
        "answer": "210 / 40\n",
        "choiceone": "240 / 20\n",
        "choicetwo": "190 / 40\n",
        "choicethree": "030 / 40\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What winds and air mass characteristics are mainly associated with the winter monsoon in the monsoon regions of the Indian\nsub-continent ?\n",
        "answer": "North-easterly winds bringing dry and hazy air.\n",
        "choiceone": "North-westerly winds bringing dry and hazy air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "South-westerly winds carrying warm and humid air.\n",
        "choicethree": "South-easterly winds carrying warm and humid air.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a front crosses a mountain range , its activity ;\n",
        "answer": "strengthens \u201cupwind\u201d of the mountains.\n",
        "choiceone": "is not disturbed by the mountains.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ceases immediately.\n",
        "choicethree": "decreases when it reaches the mountains.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a front has to cross a chain of mountains , its activity ;\n",
        "answer": "strengthens \u201cupwind\u201d of the mountains.\n",
        "choiceone": "decreases when it reaches the mountains.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is not disturbed by the mountains.\n",
        "choicethree": "ceases immediately.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a given mass of air descends , what effect will it have on relative humidity ?\n",
        "answer": "It decreases.\n",
        "choiceone": "It increases up to 100% , then remains stable.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It remains constant.\n",
        "choicethree": "It increases.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a mass of unsaturated air descends , what effect will it have on relative humidity ?\n",
        "answer": "It decreases.\n",
        "choiceone": "It remains constant.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It increases.\n",
        "choicethree": "It increases up to 100% , then remains stable.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When and where is an easterly jet stream likely to be encountered ?\n",
        "answer": "In summer from south-east Asia extending over southern India to central Africa.\n",
        "choiceone": "In summer from the Middle East extending over the southern part of the Mediterranean to southern Spain.\n",
        "choicetwo": "In winter along the Russian coast facing the Arctic ocean.\n",
        "choicethree": "Throughout the year to the south of the Azorian high.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When are the rainy seasons in equatorial Africa ?\n",
        "answer": "March to May and October to November.\n",
        "choiceone": "March to May and August to October.\n",
        "choicetwo": "April to July and December to February.\n",
        "choicethree": "December to February and July to October.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When compared to the geostrophic wind in the northern hemisphere , surface friction will cause the surface wind to ;\n",
        "answer": "back and decrease.\n",
        "choiceone": "veer and decrease.\n",
        "choicetwo": "back and increase.\n",
        "choicethree": "veer and increase.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When do cold occlusions occur most frequently in Europe ?\n",
        "answer": "Summer.\n",
        "choiceone": "Winter.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Winter and spring.\n",
        "choicethree": "Autumn and winter.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When flying at 5000 feet in the northern hemisphere over plains ( flat country ) with an anticyclone on the left and a\ndepression on the right , the wind will be ;\n",
        "answer": "a head wind.\n",
        "choiceone": "from the left.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a tail wind.\n",
        "choicethree": "from the right.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When flying in mountainous terrain and assuming ISA temperatures and strong winds , which of the following is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "In case of venturi effect , the actual altitude of the aircraft is lower than the indicated altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "In case of adiabatic compression of the air , the temperature is lower than indicated.\n",
        "choicetwo": "In case of venturi effect , the indicated altitude of the aircraft is lower than the actual altitude.\n",
        "choicethree": "In case of combined effect of surface friction and adiabatic compression of the air , the dynamic pressure is\n lower than indicated by the altimeter.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When fog is reported , the visibility is below ;\n",
        "answer": "1 km\n",
        "choiceone": "1.5 km\n",
        "choicetwo": "0.8 km\n",
        "choicethree": "3 km\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-10849A )\n Annex 050-10849A\n When front \u201cG\u201d passes position \u201cT\u201d the surface wind should ;\n",
        "answer": "veer and increase.\n",
        "choiceone": "veer and decrease.\n",
        "choicetwo": "back and decrease.\n",
        "choicethree": "back and increase.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When , if at all , is a tropical revolving storm most likely to affect Darwin , on the central north coast of Australia ?\n",
        "answer": "December to April\n",
        "choiceone": "Not experienced at Darwin\n",
        "choicetwo": "May to July\n",
        "choicethree": "August to October\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When in summer calm and clear conditions exist , a station on the shore of a large body of water will experience wind ;\n",
        "answer": "from the water in daytime and from the land at night.\n",
        "choiceone": "continually from land to water.\n",
        "choicetwo": "from the land in daytime and from the water at night.\n",
        "choicethree": "continually from water to land.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When in the northern hemisphere at the same latitude the distance between isobars is equal then ;\n",
        "answer": "the gradient wind in a low pressure area is weaker than in a high pressure area.\n",
        "choiceone": "the wind around a low pressure area is stronger than around a high pressure area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the coriolis force in a high pressure area is smaller than the gradient force in a high pressure area.\n",
        "choicethree": "the geostrophic wind speed is less than the gradient wind speed in a low pressure area.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When in the upper part of a layer warm air is advected the ;\n",
        "answer": "stability increases in the layer.\n",
        "choiceone": "wind speed will always decrease with increasing height in the northern hemisphere.\n",
        "choicetwo": "wind will back with increasing height in the northern hemisphere.\n",
        "choicethree": "stability decreases in the layer.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is the RVR reported at most airports ?\n",
        "answer": "When the visibility decreases below 1500 m.\n",
        "choiceone": "When the RVR decreases below 2500 m.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When the RVR decreases below 2000 m.\n",
        "choicethree": "When the visibility decreases below 2000 m.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When isobars , for an area in the mid-latitudes on a weather map , are close together , the wind is most likely to be ;\n",
        "answer": "strong.\n",
        "choiceone": "light.\n",
        "choicetwo": "changing direction rapidly.\n",
        "choicethree": "blowing perpendicular to the isobars.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When otherwise calm and clear conditions exist a station on the shore of a large body of water will experience wind ;\n",
        "answer": "from the water in daytime and from the land at night.\n",
        "choiceone": "continually from land to water.\n",
        "choicetwo": "continually from water to the land.\n",
        "choicethree": "from the land in daytime and from the water at night.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When planning a flight at FL 60 , which upper wind and temperature chart would be nearest your flight level ?\n",
        "answer": "850 hPa 250 hPa \u2192 FL340 ISA \u201352\u00b0C , 200 hPa \u2192 FL390 ISA \u201356\u00b0C.\n",
        "choiceone": "500 hPa\n",
        "choicetwo": "700 hPa 850 hPa \u2192 FL50 ISA +5\u00b0C , 700 hPa \u2192 FL100 ISA \u20135\u00b0C ,\n",
        "choicethree": "300 hPa 500 hPa \u2192 FL180 ISA \u201321\u00b0C , 300 hPa \u2192 FL300 ISA \u201345\u00b0C ,\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When planning a flight at FL 110 , which upper wind and temperature chart would be nearest your flight level ?\n",
        "answer": "700 hPa 500 hPa \u2192 FL180 ISA \u201321\u00b0C , 300 hPa \u2192 FL300 ISA \u201345\u00b0C ,\n",
        "choiceone": "500 hPa\n",
        "choicetwo": "850 hPa 850 hPa \u2192 FL50 ISA +5\u00b0C , 700 hPa \u2192 FL100 ISA \u20135\u00b0C ,\n",
        "choicethree": "300 hPa\n 250 hPa \u2192 FL340 ISA \u201352\u00b0C , 200 hPa \u2192 FL390 ISA \u201356\u00b0C.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When severe mountain waves are present , where would the area of most severe turbulence be located ?\n",
        "answer": "In the rotor zone.\n",
        "choiceone": "Just above the cap cloud.\n",
        "choicetwo": "On the windward side of the mountain range.\n",
        "choicethree": "Just below the tropopause.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the subscale is set to the QNH of an airfield the pressure altimeter indicates ;\n",
        "answer": "elevation while landing.\n",
        "choiceone": "zero while landing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "elevation while landing only if conditions are as in the ICAO Standard Atmosphere.\n",
        "choicethree": "zero while landing only if conditions are as in the ICAO Standard Atmosphere.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the subscale of a pressure altimeter is set to the QFE of the destination airfield it will indicate ;\n",
        "answer": "zero at landing roll out.\n",
        "choiceone": "airfield elevation at landing roll out.\n",
        "choicetwo": "more than the airfield elevation.\n",
        "choicethree": "the aircraft\u2019s altitude above MSL.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the temperature and dew point are less than one degree apart the weather conditions are most likely to be ;\n",
        "answer": "fog or low cloud.\n",
        "choiceone": "unlimited visibility.\n",
        "choicetwo": "high scattered clouds.\n",
        "choicethree": "clear and cool.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When visibility is reduced by water droplets to less than 1000 metres it is classified as ;\n",
        "answer": "fog.\n",
        "choiceone": "mist.\n",
        "choicetwo": "dust fog.\n",
        "choicethree": "haze.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When water evaporates into unsaturated air ;\n",
        "answer": "heat is absorbed.\n",
        "choiceone": "relative humidity is decreased.\n",
        "choicetwo": "relative humidity is not changed.\n",
        "choicethree": "heat is released.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When water vapour condenses or water freezes ;\n",
        "answer": "heat is released in both cases.\n",
        "choiceone": "heat is released and heat is required respectively.\n",
        "choicetwo": "heat is required and heat is released respectively.\n",
        "choicethree": "heat is required in both cases.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When will the surface wind in a METAR record a gust factor ?\n",
        "answer": "When gusts are at least 10 knots above the mean wind speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "When gusts are at least 15 knots above the mean wind speed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "With gusts of at least 25 knots.\n",
        "choicethree": "With gusts of at least 35 knots.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where are easterly waves found ?\n",
        "answer": "Between subtropical high pressure cells and ITCZ.\n",
        "choiceone": "In the temperate latitudes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "In the region of the subtropical jet stream.\n",
        "choicethree": "On the poleward side of the subtropical high pressure belt.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where are the westerlies to be expected ?\n",
        "answer": "In the mid-latitudes.\n",
        "choiceone": "Between 10\u00ba and 30\u00ba north or south.\n",
        "choicetwo": "In the subtropical high pressure belt.\n",
        "choicethree": "Between 65\u00ba and 80\u00ba north or south.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where are you likely to find the strongest winds close to the ground ?\n",
        "answer": "In the transition zone between two air masses.\n",
        "choiceone": "At the centre of a low-pressure system.\n",
        "choicetwo": "At the centre of a high-pressure system.\n",
        "choicethree": "Where there is little variation in pressure over a large area during the winter months.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where , as a general rule , is the core of the polar front jet stream to be found ?\n",
        "answer": "In the tropical air mass.\n",
        "choiceone": "In the polar air mass.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Just below the cold-air tropopause.\n",
        "choicethree": "Just above the warm-air tropopause.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where do the trade winds blow ?\n",
        "answer": "Between the \u201chorse latitudes\u201d and the doldrums.\n",
        "choiceone": "Between the \u201chorse latitudes\u201d and the mid latitudes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Between the \u201chorse latitudes\u201d and the equatorial highs.\n",
        "choicethree": "At the equator.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where does one normally find the highest cloud tops ?\n",
        "answer": "In a tropical cyclone.\n",
        "choiceone": "In a polar low.\n",
        "choicetwo": "In a cold front.\n",
        "choicethree": "Near an occlusion point.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where does polar continental air originate ?\n",
        "answer": "Siberian landmass.\n",
        "choiceone": "The region of Azores.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Polar ice cap.\n",
        "choicethree": "The region of the British Isles.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where does wind shear occur ?\n",
        "answer": "At any level in the atmosphere if associated with either a change of wind direcion and/or wind speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "Wind shear occurs primarily at lower altitudes in the vicinity of mountain waves.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Wind shear occurs only when there is a strong temperature inversion , or when the jetstream is associated\n with a strong depression.\n",
        "choicethree": "Wind shear of any significance occurs only in connection with jetstreams.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where , during a flight from Marseille to Dakar , in July , may the ITCZ be encountered ?\n",
        "answer": "In the vicinity of Dakar.\n",
        "choiceone": "At the latitudes of Gibraltar.\n",
        "choicetwo": "At the latitudes of Algeria.\n",
        "choicethree": "Near the Canary Islands.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where , in central Europe , are the highest wind speeds to be found ?\n",
        "answer": "Just below the tropopause.\n",
        "choiceone": "Close to the ground.\n",
        "choicetwo": "In the stratosphere.\n",
        "choicethree": "At about 5500 metres altitude.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is a squall line most likely to be expected ?\n",
        "answer": "In front of an active cold front.\n",
        "choiceone": "At the surface position of a warm front.\n",
        "choicetwo": "In front of a cold front occlusion at higher levels.\n",
        "choicethree": "Behind a cold front.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the coldest air to be found , in an occlusion with cold front characteristics ?\n",
        "answer": "Behind the front.\n",
        "choiceone": "Ahead of the front.\n",
        "choicetwo": "At the surface position of the front.\n",
        "choicethree": "At the junction of the occlusion.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the most dangerous zone in a tropical revolving storm ?\n",
        "answer": "In the wall of clouds around the eye.\n",
        "choiceone": "Anywhere in the eye.\n",
        "choicetwo": "About 600 km away from the eye.\n",
        "choicethree": "In the centre of the eye.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the projection of the polar front jet on the surface stream most likely to be found in relation to the cold and warm\nfronts of a depression ?\n",
        "answer": "50 to 200 NM behind the cold front and 300 to 450 NM ahead of the warm front.\n",
        "choiceone": "Up to 200 NM either side of the cold front and up to 200 NM either side of the warm front.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Up to 100 NM either side of the cold front and up to 200 NM either side of the warm front.\n",
        "choicethree": "300 to 450 NM behind the cold front and 50 to 200 NM ahead of the warm front.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the source of tropical continental air that affects Europe in summer ?\n",
        "answer": "The southern Balkan region and the Near East.\n",
        "choiceone": "Southern France.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Southern Italy.\n",
        "choicethree": "The Azores region.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the wind speed of a polar front jet stream normally at its strongest ?\n",
        "answer": "In the area between a trough and a ridge.\n",
        "choiceone": "In the area where the jet stream is curving around and anticyclone.\n",
        "choicetwo": "In the area where the je stream is curving around a depression.\n",
        "choicethree": "In the area of a trough.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-2496A )\n Annex 050-2496A\n Which airport , at 1200 UTC , has the lowest probability of precipitation ?\n",
        "answer": "LSZH\n",
        "choiceone": "ENFB\n",
        "choicetwo": "ESSA\n",
        "choicethree": "EFHK\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4364A )\n Annex 050-4364A\n Which airport is most likely to have radiation fog in the coming night ?\n",
        "answer": "LSZH\n",
        "choiceone": "ESSA\n",
        "choicetwo": "EKCH\n",
        "choicethree": "ENGM\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which area of a polar front jet stream in the northern hemisphere has the highest probability of turbulence ?\n",
        "answer": "Looking downstream , the area to the left of the core.\n",
        "choiceone": "In the core of the jet stream.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Above the core in the boundary between warm and cold air.\n",
        "choicethree": "Looking downstream , the area to the right of the core.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which climatic type is to be expected between 10\u00b0N and 10\u00b0S ?\n",
        "answer": "Tropical rain climate.\n",
        "choiceone": "Warm temperate rain climate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Dry climate.\n",
        "choicethree": "Tropical transitional climate.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which cloud species is described by the following definition ?\n \u201cClouds which present , in at least some portion of their upper part , cumuliform protuberances in the form of turrets which\ngenerally give the clouds a crenellated appearance. The turrets , some of which are taller than they are wide , are connected by a\ncommon base and seem to be arranged in lines. The typical character is especially evident when the clouds are seen from the side\u201d.\n",
        "answer": "Castellanus\n",
        "choiceone": "Fractus\n",
        "choicetwo": "Calvus\n",
        "choicethree": "Congestus\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which cloud species is described by the following definition ?\n \u201cCumulonimbus characterised by the presence , mostly in its upper portion , of distinct cirriform parts of clearly fibrous or\nstriated structure , frequently having the form of an anvil , a plume or a vast , more or less disorderly mass of hair. This specie is\nusually accompanied by a shower , or by a thunderstorm , often with squalls and sometimes with hail , it frequently produces very\nwell defined virga.\u201d\n",
        "answer": "Capillatus\n",
        "choiceone": "Fractus\n",
        "choicetwo": "Calvus\n",
        "choicethree": "Congestus\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which cloud type ( genus ) is described by the following definition ?\n \u201cCumulus clouds which are markedly sprouting and are often of great vertical extent , their bulging upper part frequently\nresembles a cauliflower.\u201d\n",
        "answer": "Towering cumulus\n",
        "choiceone": "Cumulonimbus capillatus\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cumulus fractus\n",
        "choicethree": "Cumulus humilis\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which cloud type ( genus ) is described by the following definition ?\n \u201cDetached clouds in the form of white , delicate filaments or white or mostly white patches or narrow bands. These clouds\nhave fibrous ( hair-like ) appearance , or a silky sheen , or both.\u201d\n",
        "answer": "Cirrus\n",
        "choiceone": "Stratus\n",
        "choicetwo": "Altostratus\n",
        "choicethree": "Cirrostratus\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which cloud type ( genus ) is described by the following definition ?\n \u201cGrey cloud layer , often dark , the appearance of which is rendered diffuse by more or less continuously falling rain or snow\n, which in most cases reaches the ground. It is thick enough throughout to blot out the sun. Low , ragged clouds frequently occur\nbelow the layer , with which they may or may not merge\u201d.\n",
        "answer": "Nimbostratus\n",
        "choiceone": "Stratus\n",
        "choicetwo": "Stratocumulus\n",
        "choicethree": "Altostratus\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which cloud type ( genus ) is described by the following definition ?\n \u201cGreyish or bluish cloud sheet or layer of striated , fibrous or uniform appearance , totally or partly covering the sky , and\nhaving parts thin enough to reveal the sun at least vaguely , as through ground glass. This genus does not show halo phenomena.\u201d\n",
        "answer": "Altostratus\n",
        "choiceone": "Cirrostratus\n",
        "choicetwo": "Stratocumulus\n",
        "choicethree": "Stratus\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which cloud type may indicate the presence of severe turbulence ?\n",
        "answer": "Altocumulus lenticularis\n",
        "choiceone": "Cirrocumulus\n",
        "choicetwo": "Stratocumulus\n",
        "choicethree": "Nimbostratus\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constant pressure altitude chart is standard for FL50 ?\n",
        "answer": "850 hPa.\n",
        "choiceone": "300 hPa.\n 850 hPa \u2192 FL50 ISA +5\u00b0C , 700 hPa \u2192 FL100 ISA \u20135\u00b0C ,\n",
        "choicetwo": "500 hPa.\n 500 hPa \u2192 FL180 ISA \u201321\u00b0C , 300 hPa \u2192 FL300 ISA \u201345\u00b0C ,\n",
        "choicethree": "700 hPa.\n 250 hPa \u2192 FL340 ISA \u201352\u00b0C , 200 hPa \u2192 FL390 ISA \u201356\u00b0C.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constant pressure altitude chart is standard for FL 100 ?\n",
        "answer": "700 hPa 500 hPa \u2192 FL180 ISA \u201321\u00b0C , 300 hPa \u2192 FL300 ISA \u201345\u00b0C ,\n",
        "choiceone": "850 hPa\n",
        "choicetwo": "500 hPa 850 hPa \u2192 FL50 ISA +5\u00b0C , 700 hPa \u2192 FL100 ISA \u20135\u00b0C ,\n",
        "choicethree": "300 hPa 250 hPa \u2192 FL340 ISA \u201352\u00b0C , 200 hPa \u2192 FL390 ISA \u201356\u00b0C.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constant pressure altitude chart is standard for FL 180 ?\n",
        "answer": "500 hPa\n",
        "choiceone": "700 hPa 850 hPa \u2192 FL50 ISA +5\u00b0C , 700 hPa \u2192 FL100 ISA \u20135\u00b0C ,\n",
        "choicetwo": "200 hPa 500 hPa \u2192 FL180 ISA \u201321\u00b0C , 300 hPa \u2192 FL300 ISA \u201345\u00b0C ,\n",
        "choicethree": "300 hPa 250 hPa \u2192 FL340 ISA \u201352\u00b0C , 200 hPa \u2192 FL390 ISA \u201356\u00b0C.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constant pressure altitude chart is standard for FL 300 ?\n",
        "answer": "300 hPa 250 hPa \u2192 FL340 ISA \u201352\u00b0C , 200 hPa \u2192 FL390 ISA \u201356\u00b0C.\n",
        "choiceone": "500 hPa\n",
        "choicetwo": "200 hPa 850 hPa \u2192 FL50 ISA +5\u00b0C , 700 hPa \u2192 FL100 ISA \u20135\u00b0C ,\n",
        "choicethree": "700 hPa 500 hPa \u2192 FL180 ISA \u201321\u00b0C , 300 hPa \u2192 FL300 ISA \u201345\u00b0C ,\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constant pressure altitude chart is standard for FL 390 ?\n",
        "answer": "200 hPa\n 250 hPa \u2192 FL340 ISA \u201352\u00b0C , 200 hPa \u2192 FL390 ISA \u201356\u00b0C.\n",
        "choiceone": "300 hPa\n",
        "choicetwo": "500 hPa\n 850 hPa \u2192 FL50 ISA +5\u00b0C , 700 hPa \u2192 FL100 ISA \u20135\u00b0C ,\n",
        "choicethree": "700 hPa\n 500 hPa \u2192 FL180 ISA \u201321\u00b0C , 300 hPa \u2192 FL300 ISA \u201345\u00b0C ,\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constant pressure chart is standard for FL 140 ?\n",
        "answer": "600 hPa\n",
        "choiceone": "700 hPa\n",
        "choicetwo": "850 hPa\n",
        "choicethree": "500 hPa\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constant pressure chart is standard for FL 240 ?\n",
        "answer": "400 hPa\n",
        "choiceone": "500 hPa\n",
        "choicetwo": "600 hPa\n",
        "choicethree": "300 hPa\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constant pressure chart is standard for FL 340 ?\n",
        "answer": "250 hPa\n",
        "choiceone": "300 hPa 850 hPa \u2192 FL50 ISA +5\u00b0C , 700 hPa \u2192 FL100 ISA \u20135\u00b0C ,\n",
        "choicetwo": "400 hPa 500 hPa \u2192 FL180 ISA \u201321\u00b0C , 300 hPa \u2192 FL300 ISA \u201345\u00b0C ,\n",
        "choicethree": "200 hPa 250 hPa \u2192 FL340 ISA \u201352\u00b0C , 200 hPa \u2192 FL390 ISA \u201356\u00b0C.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constant pressure chart is standard for FL 450 ?\n",
        "answer": "150 hPa\n",
        "choiceone": "250 hPa\n",
        "choicetwo": "200 hPa\n",
        "choicethree": "300 hPa\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-2061A )\n Annex 050-2061A\n Which cross-section of air mass and cloud presentation is applicable to the straight line A-B ?\n",
        "answer": "3\n",
        "choiceone": "1\n",
        "choicetwo": "4\n",
        "choicethree": "2\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which degree of aircraft turbulence is determined by the following ICAO description ?\n \u201cConditions in which abrupt changes in aircraft attitude and/or altitude occur , aircraft may be out of control for short\nperiods. Usually , large variations in air speed\u201d.\n",
        "answer": "Severe\n",
        "choiceone": "Light\n",
        "choicetwo": "Violent\n",
        "choicethree": "Moderate\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which degree of aircraft turbulence is determined by the following ICAO description ?\n \u201cThere may be moderate changes in aircraft attitude and/or altitude but the aircraft remains in positive control at all times.\nUsually , small variations in air speed. Changes in accelerometer readings of 0.5 to 1.0 g at the aircraft\u2019s centre of gravity. Occupants\nfeel strain against seat belts. Loose objects move about. Food service and walking are difficult\u201d.\n",
        "answer": "Moderate.\n",
        "choiceone": "Severe.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Light.\n",
        "choicethree": "Violent.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which FL corresponds with the 150 hPa pressure level ?\n",
        "answer": "FL 450\n",
        "choiceone": "FL 390\n",
        "choicetwo": "FL 300\n",
        "choicethree": "FL 340\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which FL corresponds with the 200 hPa pressure level ?\n",
        "answer": "FL 390.\n 850 hPa \u2192 FL50 ISA +5\u00b0C , 700 hPa \u2192 FL100 ISA \u20135\u00b0C ,\n",
        "choiceone": "FL 50.\n",
        "choicetwo": "FL 300.\n 500 hPa \u2192 FL180 ISA \u201321\u00b0C , 300 hPa \u2192 FL300 ISA \u201345\u00b0C ,\n",
        "choicethree": "FL 100.\n 250 hPa \u2192 FL340 ISA \u201352\u00b0C , 200 hPa \u2192 FL390 ISA \u201356\u00b0C.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which FL corresponds with the 250 hPa pressure level ?\n",
        "answer": "FL 340 250 hPa \u2192 FL340 ISA \u201352\u00b0C , 200 hPa \u2192 FL390 ISA \u201356\u00b0C.\n",
        "choiceone": "FL 300\n",
        "choicetwo": "FL 450 850 hPa \u2192 FL50 ISA +5\u00b0C , 700 hPa \u2192 FL100 ISA \u20135\u00b0C ,\n",
        "choicethree": "FL 390 500 hPa \u2192 FL180 ISA \u201321\u00b0C , 300 hPa \u2192 FL300 ISA \u201345\u00b0C ,\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which FL corresponds with the 300 hPa pressure level ?\n",
        "answer": "FL 300 500 hPa \u2192 FL180 ISA \u201321\u00b0C , 300 hPa \u2192 FL300 ISA \u201345\u00b0C ,\n",
        "choiceone": "FL 50\n",
        "choicetwo": "FL 100 850 hPa \u2192 FL50 ISA +5\u00b0C , 700 hPa \u2192 FL100 ISA \u20135\u00b0C ,\n",
        "choicethree": "FL 390 250 hPa \u2192 FL340 ISA \u201352\u00b0C , 200 hPa \u2192 FL390 ISA \u201356\u00b0C.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which FL corresponds with the 400 hPa pressure level ?\n",
        "answer": "FL 240\n",
        "choiceone": "FL 140\n",
        "choicetwo": "FL 300\n",
        "choicethree": "FL 340\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which FL corresponds with the 500 hPa pressure level ?\n",
        "answer": "FL 180\n",
        "choiceone": "FL 390\n",
        "choicetwo": "FL 160 850 hPa \u2192 FL50 ISA +5\u00b0C , 700 hPa \u2192 FL100 ISA \u20135\u00b0C ,\n",
        "choicethree": "FL 100 500 hPa \u2192 FL180 ISA \u201321\u00b0C , 300 hPa \u2192 FL300 ISA \u201345\u00b0C ,\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which FL corresponds with the 600 hPa pressure level ?\n",
        "answer": "FL 140\n",
        "choiceone": "FL 100\n",
        "choicetwo": "FL 240\n",
        "choicethree": "FL 180\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which FL corresponds with the 700 hPa pressure level ?\n",
        "answer": "FL 100 500 hPa \u2192 FL180 ISA \u201321\u00b0C , 300 hPa \u2192 FL300 ISA \u201345\u00b0C ,\n",
        "choiceone": "FL 390\n",
        "choicetwo": "FL 300 850 hPa \u2192 FL50 ISA +5\u00b0C , 700 hPa \u2192 FL100 ISA \u20135\u00b0C ,\n",
        "choicethree": "FL 180 250 hPa \u2192 FL340 ISA \u201352\u00b0C , 200 hPa \u2192 FL390 ISA \u201356\u00b0C.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which FL corresponds with the 850 hPa pressure level ?\n",
        "answer": "FL 50\n",
        "choiceone": "FL 390\n 850 hPa \u2192 FL50 ISA +5\u00b0C , 700 hPa \u2192 FL100 ISA \u20135\u00b0C ,\n",
        "choicetwo": "FL 300\n 500 hPa \u2192 FL180 ISA \u201321\u00b0C , 300 hPa \u2192 FL300 ISA \u201345\u00b0C ,\n",
        "choicethree": "FL100\n 250 hPa \u2192 FL340 ISA \u201352\u00b0C , 200 hPa \u2192 FL390 ISA \u201356\u00b0C.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which force causes the surface wind , in the northern hemisphere , to deflect to the left compared to the geostrophic wind ?\n",
        "answer": "Frictional force.\n",
        "choiceone": "Centripetal force.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Coriolis force.\n",
        "choicethree": "Pressure gradient force.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which forces are balanced with geostrophic winds ?\n",
        "answer": "Pressure gradient force , Coriolis force.\n",
        "choiceone": "Pressure gradient force , centrifugal force , friction force.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Friction force , pressure gradient force , Coriolis force.\n",
        "choicethree": "Pressure gradient force , Coriolis force , centrifugal force.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which form of precipitation from clouds containing only water is most likely to fall in mid-latitudes ?\n",
        "answer": "Drizzle.\n",
        "choiceone": "Hail.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Heavy rain with large drops.\n",
        "choicethree": "Moderate rain with large drops.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which interpretation of the following message is correct ?\n LFLD AD WRNG 1 VALID 050430/050900 FROST FCST =\n",
        "answer": "It is forecast that some parts of the surface , vehicles , and aircraft parked outside will be contaminated by\n hoar frost between 0430 and 0900 on the 5th of that month.\n",
        "choiceone": "The aerodrome warning for runway 05 due to frost issued at 0430 UTC has been cancelled at 0900 UTC.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It is forecast for the period between 0430 and 0900 on the 5th of that month that a departing or arriving\n aircraft will pass a layer of ground fog in which the aircraft will be contaminated by hoar frost.\n",
        "choicethree": "It is forecast for the period between 0430 and 0900 on the 5th of that month that especially an aircraft in the\n final approach phase will be covered by hoar frost.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true of a secondary depression in the northern hemisphere ?\n",
        "answer": "It tends to move round the primary in a cyclonic sense.\n",
        "choiceone": "It rapidly closes on , and merges with the primary.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It tends to maintain its position relative to the primary.\n",
        "choicethree": "It tends to move round the primary in an anticyclonic sense.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true of a typical non frontal thermal depression ?\n",
        "answer": "It forms over land in summer.\n",
        "choiceone": "It forms over the ocean in summer.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It forms over land in winter.\n",
        "choicethree": "It forms over the ocean in winter.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true of a typical thermal depression ?\n",
        "answer": "It forms over land in summer.\n",
        "choiceone": "It forms over land in winter.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It forms over the ocean in summer.\n",
        "choicethree": "It forms over the ocean in winter.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true of advection fog ?\n",
        "answer": "It can appear suddenly by day or by night.\n",
        "choiceone": "It usually forms by night and clears by day.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It develops slowly and clears fast.\n",
        "choicethree": "It forms when unstable air is adiabatically cooled.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true of Nairobi ( Kenya ) ?\n",
        "answer": "There are two wet seasons.\n",
        "choiceone": "Apart from the wet season(s) it is cloud and rain free.\n",
        "choicetwo": "In July it is frequently affected by clear skies and northerly winds from North Africa.\n",
        "choicethree": "There is one wet season.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true of the temperature at the tropopause ?\n",
        "answer": "It is higher in polar regions than in equatorial regions.\n",
        "choiceone": "It is higher in equatorial regions than in polar regions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It is highest in mid-latitudes.\n",
        "choicethree": "There is no significant difference with change of latitude.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which jet stream blows all year round , over the northern hemisphere ?\n",
        "answer": "The subtropical jet stream.\n",
        "choiceone": "The polar night jet stream.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The arctic jet stream.\n",
        "choicethree": "The equatorial jet stream.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which jet stream is connected with a surface front system ?\n",
        "answer": "The polar front jet stream.\n",
        "choiceone": "The equatorial jet stream.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The subtropical jet stream.\n",
        "choicethree": "The easterly jet stream.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which kind of meteorological messages are normally transmitted in a VHF-VOLMET broadcast within Europe ?\n",
        "answer": "METAR / SPECI\n",
        "choiceone": "AIREP / SPECIAL\n",
        "choicetwo": "TAF / SPECIAL\n",
        "choicethree": "GAMET / AIRMET\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which kind of meteorological messages are normally transmitted in an ATIS ?\n",
        "answer": "MET REPORT / SPECIAL\n",
        "choiceone": "AIRMET / GAMET\n",
        "choicetwo": "TAF / SPECI\n",
        "choicethree": "METAR / SPECI\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which layer of the atmosphere contains more than 90 per cent of all water vapour ?\n",
        "answer": "Troposphere\n",
        "choiceone": "Upper stratosphere\n",
        "choicetwo": "Ozone layer\n",
        "choicethree": "Lower stratosphere\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following are favourable conditions for the formation of freezing rain ?\n",
        "answer": "Warm air aloft from which rain is falling into air with a temperature below 0\u00b0C.\n",
        "choiceone": "Water droplets falling from cold air aloft with a temperature below 0\u00b0C into air with a temperature above\n 0\u00b0C.\n",
        "choicetwo": "An isothermal layer aloft with a temperature just above 0\u00b0C through which rain is falling.\n",
        "choicethree": "Cold air aloft from which hail is falling into air that is warm.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following are medium level clouds ?\n",
        "answer": "Altostratus and altocumulus.\n",
        "choiceone": "All convective clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cumulonimbus.\n",
        "choicethree": "Cirrocumulus and cirrostratus.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following best describes the intertropical convergence zone ?\n",
        "answer": "The zone where the trade winds of the northern hemisphere meet those of the southern hemisphere.\n",
        "choiceone": "The zone where the Harmattan meets the north-easterly trade winds over Africa.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The zone where cold fronts form in the tropics.\n",
        "choicethree": "The zone where the west winds meet the subtropical high pressure belt.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4333A )\n Annex 050-4333A\n Which of the following best describes Zone A ?\n",
        "answer": "Trough of low pressure\n",
        "choiceone": "Ridge of high pressure\n",
        "choicetwo": "Col\n",
        "choicethree": "Depression\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4333A )\n Annex 050-4333A\n Which of the following best describes Zone B ?\n",
        "answer": "Col\n",
        "choiceone": "Ridge of high pressure\n",
        "choicetwo": "Trough of low pressure\n",
        "choicethree": "Depression\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4333A )\n Annex 050-4333A\n Which of the following best describes Zone C ?\n",
        "answer": "Ridge of high pressure\n",
        "choiceone": "Col\n",
        "choicetwo": "Trough of low pressure\n",
        "choicethree": "Depression\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4333A )\n Annex 050-4333A\n Which of the following best describes Zone D ?\n",
        "answer": "Depression\n",
        "choiceone": "Trough of low pressure\n",
        "choicetwo": "Anticyclone\n",
        "choicethree": "Ridge of high pressure\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following causes echoes on meteorological radar screens ?\n",
        "answer": "Hail\n",
        "choiceone": "Any cloud\n",
        "choicetwo": "Fog\n",
        "choicethree": "Water vapour\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following changes of state is known as condensation ?\n",
        "answer": "Gas to liquid\n",
        "choiceone": "Gas to solid\n",
        "choicetwo": "Liquid to gas\n",
        "choicethree": "Liquid to solid\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following changes of state is known as evaporation ?\n",
        "answer": "Liquid to gas\n",
        "choiceone": "Gas to solid\n",
        "choicetwo": "Liquid to solid\n",
        "choicethree": "Solid to liquid\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following changes of state is known as freezing ?\n",
        "answer": "Liquid to solid\n",
        "choiceone": "Solid to liquid\n",
        "choicetwo": "Liquid to gas\n",
        "choicethree": "Gas to solid\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following changes of state is known as melting ?\n",
        "answer": "Solid to liquid\n",
        "choiceone": "Liquid to solid\n",
        "choicetwo": "Solid to gas\n",
        "choicethree": "Liquid to gas\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following changes of state is known as sublimation ( in meteorology ) ?\n",
        "answer": "Solid direct to vapour\n",
        "choiceone": "Liquid direct to vapour\n",
        "choicetwo": "Liquid direct to solid\n",
        "choicethree": "Solid direct to liquid\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following circumstances most favour the development of radiation fog ?\n",
        "answer": "Moist air over land during clear night with little wind.\n",
        "choiceone": "Maritime tropical air flowing over cold sea.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Advection of very cold air over much warmer sea.\n",
        "choicethree": "Warm moist air at the windward side of a mountain.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following circumstances most favours the development of frontal fog ?\n",
        "answer": "Increase of the relative humidity by evaporation of rain drops.\n",
        "choiceone": "Absolutely unstable air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Nocurnal radiation.\n",
        "choicethree": "Advection of very cold air over much warmer sea.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following circumstances most favours the development of orographic fog ?\n",
        "answer": "High relative humidity.\n",
        "choiceone": "Katabatic winds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Absolutely unstable air.\n",
        "choicethree": "Clear nights.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following cloud is classified as low level cloud ?\n",
        "answer": "ST\n",
        "choiceone": "AS\n",
        "choicetwo": "CS\n",
        "choicethree": "CC\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following cloud may extend over the low , middle and high stages ?\n",
        "answer": "CB\n",
        "choiceone": "ST\n",
        "choicetwo": "CI\n",
        "choicethree": "AC\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following cloud types are most likely to produce light to moderate icing when they are not subject to\norographic lifting and consist of supercooled cloud droplets ?\n",
        "answer": "Altocumulus and altostratus.\n",
        "choiceone": "Stratus and cumulonimbus\n",
        "choicetwo": "Altostratus and cirrocumulus\n",
        "choicethree": "Stratocumulus and cirrostratus\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following cloud types can project up into the stratosphere ?\n",
        "answer": "Cumulonimbus\n",
        "choiceone": "Altostratus\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cirrostratus\n",
        "choicethree": "Altocumulus\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following cloud types is a medium level cloud ?\n",
        "answer": "AS\n",
        "choiceone": "ST\n",
        "choicetwo": "SC\n",
        "choicethree": "CS\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following cloud types is classified as low level cloud ?\n",
        "answer": "SC\n",
        "choiceone": "AC\n",
        "choicetwo": "CS\n",
        "choicethree": "AS\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following cloud types is found at high level ?\n",
        "answer": "CS\n",
        "choiceone": "AC\n",
        "choicetwo": "CS\n",
        "choicethree": "ST\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following cloud types is found at high levels ?\n",
        "answer": "CI\n",
        "choiceone": "CU\n",
        "choicetwo": "SC\n",
        "choicethree": "AS\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following cloud types is found at high levels ?\n",
        "answer": "CC\n",
        "choiceone": "AC\n",
        "choicetwo": "SC\n",
        "choicethree": "ST\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following cloud types is least likely to produce precipitation ?\n",
        "answer": "CI\n",
        "choiceone": "CB\n",
        "choicetwo": "NS\n",
        "choicethree": "AS\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following cloud types will most probably form when cold moist air moves over a warm surface ?\n",
        "answer": "Cumulus.\n",
        "choiceone": "Nimbostratus.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Stratus.\n",
        "choicethree": "Stratocumulus.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following clouds are classified as medium level clouds in temperate regions ?\n",
        "answer": "AS , AC.\n",
        "choiceone": "SC , NS\n",
        "choicetwo": "CI , CC.\n",
        "choicethree": "CS , ST.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following clouds may extend into more than one layer ?\n",
        "answer": "Cumulus congestus\n",
        "choiceone": "Stratus\n",
        "choicetwo": "Altocumulus\n",
        "choicethree": "Cirrocumulus\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following clouds may extend into more than one layer ?\n",
        "answer": "Nimbostratus.\n",
        "choiceone": "Stratus.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Altocumulus.\n",
        "choicethree": "Cirrus.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following combinations is most characteristic of unstable air behind a cold front ?\n",
        "answer": "Good visibility between showers , showery precipitation , cumuliform clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "Poor visibility , intermittent precipitation , cumuliform clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Good visibility between showers , persistent precipitation , stratiform clouds.\n",
        "choicethree": "Poor visibility , continuous precipitation , stratiform clouds.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following combinations of pressure and temperature is correct in the ICAO standard atmosphere ?\n",
        "answer": "500 hPa \u201321.1\u00baC 850 hPa \u2192 FL50 ISA +5\u00b0C , 700 hPa \u2192 FL100 ISA \u20135\u00b0C ,\n",
        "choiceone": "300 hPa \u201350.5\u00baC\n",
        "choicetwo": "700 hPa \u20138.4\u00baC 500 hPa \u2192 FL180 ISA \u201321\u00b0C , 300 hPa \u2192 FL300 ISA \u201345\u00b0C ,\n",
        "choicethree": "200 hPa \u201362.3\u00baC 250 hPa \u2192 FL340 ISA \u201352\u00b0C , 200 hPa \u2192 FL390 ISA \u201356\u00b0C.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following conditions are most favourable to the formation of mountain waves ?\n",
        "answer": "Stable air at mountain top altitude and a wind at least 20 knots blowing across the mountain ridge.\n",
        "choiceone": "Either stable or unstable air at mountain top and a wind of at least 30 knots blowing parallel to the mountain\n ridge.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Moist unstable air at mountain top and wind of less than 5 knots blowing across the mountain ridge.\n",
        "choicethree": "Unstable air at mountain top altitude and a wind at least 20 knots blowing across the mountain ridge.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following conditions are you most likely to encounter when approaching an active warm front at medium to\nlow level ?\n",
        "answer": "Low cloud base and poor visibility.\n",
        "choiceone": "Severe thunderstorms at low altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "High cloud base , good surface visibility , and isolated thunderstorms.\n",
        "choicethree": "Extreme turbulence and severe lightning striking the ground.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following conditions gives the highest value of the QNH ?\n",
        "answer": "QFE = 995 hPa , elevation = 1600 ft ( 488m )\n",
        "choiceone": "QFE = 1003 hPa , elevation = 1200 ft ( 366m )\n",
        "choicetwo": "QFE = 1000 hPa , elevation = 1200 ft ( 366m )\n",
        "choicethree": "QFE = 995 hPa , elevation = 1200 ft ( 366m )\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following conditions is most likely to cause airframe icing ?\n",
        "answer": "+FZRA\n",
        "choiceone": "PE\n",
        "choicetwo": "GR\n",
        "choicethree": "SHSN\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following conditions is most likely to lead to the formation of steam fog ( arctic smoke ) ?\n",
        "answer": "Cold air moving over warm water.\n",
        "choiceone": "The sea is warmed by strong radiation from the sun.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Warm air moving over cold water.\n",
        "choicethree": "The coastal region of the sea cools at night.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following conditions would cause the altimeter to indicate a lower altitude than that actually flown ?\n",
        "answer": "Air temperature higher than standard.\n",
        "choiceone": "Air temperature lower than standard.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Atmospheric pressure lower than standard.\n",
        "choicethree": "Pressure altitude the same as indicated altitude.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following constant pressure charts would be most relevant for planning a flight at FL 260 ?\n",
        "answer": "400 hPa 500 hPa \u2192 FL180 ISA \u201321\u00b0C , 300 hPa \u2192 FL300 ISA \u201345\u00b0C ,\n",
        "choiceone": "500 hPa\n",
        "choicetwo": "300 hPa 850 hPa \u2192 FL50 ISA +5\u00b0C , 700 hPa \u2192 FL100 ISA \u20135\u00b0C ,\n",
        "choicethree": "600 hPa 250 hPa \u2192 FL340 ISA \u201352\u00b0C , 200 hPa \u2192 FL390 ISA \u201356\u00b0C.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following constant pressure charts would be most relevant for planning a flight at FL 330 ?\n",
        "answer": "250 hPa 250 hPa \u2192 FL340 ISA \u201352\u00b0C , 200 hPa \u2192 FL390 ISA \u201356\u00b0C.\n",
        "choiceone": "400 hPa\n",
        "choicetwo": "200 hPa 850 hPa \u2192 FL50 ISA +5\u00b0C , 700 hPa \u2192 FL100 ISA \u20135\u00b0C ,\n",
        "choicethree": "300 hPa 500 hPa \u2192 FL180 ISA \u201321\u00b0C , 300 hPa \u2192 FL300 ISA \u201345\u00b0C ,\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following constant pressure charts would be most relevant for planning a flight at FL 430 ?\n",
        "answer": "150 hPa\n",
        "choiceone": "200 hPa\n",
        "choicetwo": "300 hPa\n",
        "choicethree": "250 hPa\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following describes a warm occlusion ?\n",
        "answer": "The coldest air mass is ahead of the original warm front.\n",
        "choiceone": "The air mass behind the front is more unstable than the air mass ahead of the front.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The warmer air mass is ahead of the original warm front.\n",
        "choicethree": "The air mass ahead of the front is drier than the air mass behind the front.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following extracts of weather reports could be , in accordance with the regulations , abbreviated to \u201cCAVOK\u201d ?\n( MSA above ground : LSZB 10000 ft , LSZH 8000 ft , LSGG 12000 ft , LFSB 6000 ft )\n",
        "answer": "LSGG 22003KT 9999 SCT120 BKN280 09/08 Q1026 BECMG 5000 BR =\n",
        "choiceone": "LFSB 00000KT 9000 SCT080 22/15 Q1022 NOSIG =\n",
        "choicetwo": "LSZB 30004KT 9999 SCT090 10/09 Q1006 NOSIG =\n",
        "choicethree": "LSZH 26024G52KT 9999 BKN060 17/14 Q1012 RETS TEMPO 5000 TSRA =\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following factors have the greatest effect on the formation of the various types of ice on an aircraft ?\n",
        "answer": "Cloud temperature and droplet size.\n",
        "choiceone": "Relative humidity inside the cloud.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Aircraft speed and size of cloud droplets.\n",
        "choicethree": "Aircraft speed and curvature of the airfoil.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following front types is most known for gusty winds ?\n",
        "answer": "Cold front.\n",
        "choiceone": "Stationary front.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Warm front.\n",
        "choicethree": "Occluded front.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following groups of conditions requires a crew to transmit a special air-report ( subsonic air transport ) ?\n",
        "answer": "Severe turbulence , widespread thunderstorms , severe mountain waves.\n",
        "choiceone": "Volcanic ash cloud , isolated thunderstorms , moderate or severe sandstorms.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Heavy wind shears , moderate or severe aircraft icing , moderate or severe turbulence.\n",
        "choicethree": "Moderate aircraft icing , severe turbulence , embedded thunderstorms.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is a cause of stratus forming over flat land ?\n",
        "answer": "Radiation during the night from the earth surface in moderate wind.\n",
        "choiceone": "Unstable air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The release of latent heat.\n",
        "choicethree": "Convection during the day.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is a common cause of ground or surface temperature inversion ?\n",
        "answer": "Terrestrial radiation on a clear night with no or very light winds.\n",
        "choiceone": "Warm air being lifted rapidly aloft , in the vicinity of mountainous terrain.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Heating of the air by subsidence.\n",
        "choicethree": "The movement of colder air under warm air , or the movement of warm air over cold air.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is a possible consequence of subsidence ?\n",
        "answer": "An inversion over a large area with haze , mist.\n",
        "choiceone": "CB-clouds and thunderstorms over a large area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Clear air turbulence at higher altitudes .\n",
        "choicethree": "Wide spread NS and AS clouds and intense precipitation.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is correct regarding a cold high pressure area ?\n",
        "answer": "It will decrease in intensity with increasing altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "Both temperature and pressure will remain costant with increasing altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Apart from a surface inversion , the temperature will increase with increasing altitude.\n",
        "choicethree": "It will increase in intensity with increasing altitude.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is correct regarding a warm anticyclone ?\n",
        "answer": "It increases in intensity with increasing altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "It weakens with altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Apart from a surface inversion , the temperature increases with increasing altitude.\n",
        "choicethree": "It remains the smae strength up to the tropopause.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is correct regarding geostrophic wind ?\n",
        "answer": "It blows parallel to straight equidistant isobars.\n",
        "choiceone": "It blows across the isobars from high to low pressure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It is the wind resulting from the vector sum of gradient wind and surface wind , such that the geostrophic\n wind normally blows at an angle of 20-45 degrees relative to the isobars.\n",
        "choicethree": "It blows parallel to curved isobars.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is correct regarding the wind speed in a jet stream in the northern hemisphere ?\n",
        "answer": "With colder air to the left when looking downwind , the wind speed increases with height , while with the\n colder air to the right the wind speed decreases with height.\n",
        "choiceone": "With colder air ahead when looking downwind , the wind speed increases with height , while with the colder\n air behind the wind speed decreases with height.\n",
        "choicetwo": "With colder air to the left when looking upwind , the wind speed increases with height , while with the colder\n air to the right the wind speed decreases with height.\n",
        "choicethree": "With colder air behind when looking downwind , the wind speed increases with height , while with the colder\n air ahead the wind speed decreases with height.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is most likely to lead to the dissipation of radiation fog ?\n",
        "answer": "A marked increase in wind velocity near the ground.\n",
        "choiceone": "A build up of a high pressure area resulting in adiabatic warming associated with a sinking air mass.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A marked decrease in wind velocity close to the ground.\n",
        "choicethree": "Ground cooling caused by radiation during the night.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is most likely to lead to the formation of radiation fog ?\n",
        "answer": "Heat loss from the ground on clear nights.\n",
        "choiceone": "The passage of fronts.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Dry , warm air passing over warm ground.\n",
        "choicethree": "Cold air passing over warm ground.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is the definition of relative humidity ?\n",
        "answer": "Ratio between the actual mixing ratio and the saturation mixing ratio x 100.\n",
        "choiceone": "Ratio between water vapour ( g ) and air ( kg ) x 100.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Ratio between air temperature and dewpoint temperature x 100.\n",
        "choicethree": "Ratio between water vapour pressure and atmospheric pressure x 100.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is true concerning an aircraft that is flying at FL180 in the northern hemisphere , where wind is\ngeostrophic and the true altitude remains constant ?\n",
        "answer": "There is no cross wind.\n",
        "choiceone": "There is a cross wind from the left.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Without knowing temperature at FL 180 this question can not be answered.\n",
        "choicethree": "There is a cross wind from the right.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is true of a land breeze ?\n",
        "answer": "It blows from land to water.\n",
        "choiceone": "It blows from water to land.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It blows by day.\n",
        "choicethree": "It blows only at noon.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is typical for the passage of a cold front in the summer ?\n",
        "answer": "Mainly towering clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "Rapid increase in temperature once the front has passed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Mainly layered clouds.\n",
        "choicethree": "Rapid drop in pressure once the front has passed.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is typical for the snow ( tundra ) climate ?\n",
        "answer": "High pressure weather dominates in winter , with the sub-soil being frozen.\n",
        "choiceone": "Temperatures generally between +5 and +18\u00baC throughout the whole year.\n",
        "choicetwo": "High pressure weather dominates in summer.\n",
        "choicethree": "Travelling depressions during winter time.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following layers of fog above land is coded as MIFG ?\n",
        "answer": "A layer of 5 feet deep.\n",
        "choiceone": "A layer of 20 feet deep.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A layer of 10 feet deep.\n",
        "choicethree": "A layer of 15 feet deep.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following messages should be cancelled when the conditions are no longer occurring or no longer expected to\noccur ?\n",
        "answer": "Aerodrome warning\n",
        "choiceone": "Trend forecast\n",
        "choicetwo": "TAF\n",
        "choicethree": "GAMET\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following meteorological phenomena can rapidly change the braking action of a runway ?\n",
        "answer": "+FZRA\n",
        "choiceone": "FG\n",
        "choicetwo": "HZ\n",
        "choicethree": "MIFG\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following meteorological phenomenon indicates upper level instability which may lead to thunderstorm\ndevelopment ?\n",
        "answer": "AC castellanus.\n",
        "choiceone": "Halo.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Red cirrus.\n",
        "choicethree": "AC lenticularis.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following phenomena are formed when a moist , stable layer of air is forced to rise against a mountain range ?\n",
        "answer": "Stratified clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "Areas of severe turbulence.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Showers and thunderstorms.\n",
        "choicethree": "Inversions.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following phenomena can produce a risk of aquaplaning ?\n",
        "answer": "+RA\n",
        "choiceone": "BCFG\n",
        "choicetwo": "SA\n",
        "choicethree": "FG\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following phenomena can provide the initial lifting leading to air mass thunderstorms ?\n",
        "answer": "Advection of cold air over a warm sea.\n",
        "choiceone": "Mountain waves.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Low level wind shear.\n",
        "choicethree": "Advection of warm air over a cold sea.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following phenomena has to be mentioned in a SIGMET ?\n",
        "answer": "Heavy duststorm.\n",
        "choiceone": "Snow and ice on the runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Thick fog.\n",
        "choicethree": "Strong inversion.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following phenomena has to be mentioned in a SIGMET ?\n",
        "answer": "Volcanic ash.\n",
        "choiceone": "Thick fog.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Strong inversion.\n",
        "choicethree": "Snow and ice on the runway.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following phenomena is least likely to lead to the formation of a Cumulonimbus with thunderstorm ?\n",
        "answer": "Ground radiation\n",
        "choiceone": "Orographic lift\n",
        "choicetwo": "Convection\n",
        "choicethree": "Convergence\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following phenomena should be described as precipitation at the time they are observed ?\n",
        "answer": "DZ\n",
        "choiceone": "TS\n",
        "choicetwo": "SQ\n",
        "choicethree": "SA\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following phenomena should be described as precipitation at the time they are observed ?\n",
        "answer": "+SHSN\n",
        "choiceone": "BR\n",
        "choicetwo": "MIFG\n",
        "choicethree": "VA\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following phenomena should be described as precipitation at the time they are observed ?\n",
        "answer": "SN\n",
        "choiceone": "FZFG\n",
        "choicetwo": "HZ\n",
        "choicethree": "BCFG\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following processes contributes to the formation of frontal fog ?\n",
        "answer": "Rain falls from the warm air into the cold air.\n",
        "choiceone": "Moist air flows over land during a clear night.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Very cold air flows over much warmer sea.\n",
        "choicethree": "Maritime polar air flows over a warm ground.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following processes is the most important one concerning the heating of the air in the troposphere ? The\nradiation of the sun heats ;\n",
        "answer": "the surface of the earth , which heats the air in the troposphere.\n",
        "choiceone": "the air in the troposphere only directly if no clouds are present.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the water vapour in the air of the troposphere.\n",
        "choicethree": "the air in the troposphere mainly by absorbtion.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following processes will increase the stability of an air mass ?\n",
        "answer": "Cooling by the underlying surface.\n",
        "choiceone": "Advection of colder air aloft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Warning of the air mass from below.\n",
        "choicethree": "Addition of water vapour in the lower layer.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following processes within a layer of air may lead to the building of CU and CB clouds ?\n",
        "answer": "Convection.\n",
        "choiceone": "Subsidence.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Radiation.\n",
        "choicethree": "Frontal lifting within stable layers.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following quantities remains unchanged if unsaturated air is lifted until it reaches the lifting condensation\nlevel ?\n",
        "answer": "Mixing ratio.\n",
        "choiceone": "Maximum vapour pressure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Maximum mixing ratio.\n",
        "choicethree": "Difference between temperature and dewpoint temperature.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following sets of conditions are most favourable to the development of thunderstorms ?\n",
        "answer": "Environmental lapse rate greater than saturated adiabatic lapse rate through a great vertical extent , high\n relative humidity and an initial lifting process.\n",
        "choiceone": "Environmental lapse rate less than dry adiabatic lapse rate with freezing level below the cloud base , high\n relative humidity and strong surface winds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Extensive isothermal layer , ice particles and water droplets must exist just below the freezing level and\n orographic lifting.\n",
        "choicethree": "Environmental lapse rate less than saturated adiabatic lapse rate with dew point below 0\u00b0C and considerable\n surface heating.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following sets of conditions are most likely to lead to the formation of advection fog ?\n",
        "answer": "A mild moist airstream flowing over colder surfaces with the wind speed less than 15 kt.\n",
        "choiceone": "A mild moist airstream flowing over colder surfaces with a wind in excess of 30 kt.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cold maritime air flowing over a warmer land surface at a speed greater than 15 kt.\n",
        "choicethree": "Clear skies at night over an inland marshy area.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following situations favours the formation of heavy thunderstorms ?\n",
        "answer": "A cold front approaching a mountain range in the evening.\n",
        "choiceone": "A cold front on the leeward side of a mountain range.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A warm sector moving over a snow-covered ground.\n",
        "choicethree": "The passage of a warm front in the morning.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following situations will be typical for the intertropical convergence zone ?\n",
        "answer": "Low pressure and instability.\n",
        "choiceone": "High pressure the whole year , accompanied by calm winds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "High pressure the whole year , accompanied by strong prevailing winds.\n",
        "choicethree": "Hot , mainly dry climate.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following situations will most likely lead to a stable air mass ?\n",
        "answer": "Subsidence and/or cooling from below.\n",
        "choiceone": "Decreasing wind and developing showers.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Widespread convection.\n",
        "choicethree": "Cold air at higher levels and advection of warm air at lower levels.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about lightnings and lightning strikes is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "The aircraft is temporarily part of the lightning trajectory.\n",
        "choiceone": "Compasses and electronics are always affected.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Spherical lightnings often penetrate into aircraft.\n",
        "choicethree": "Lightning strikes always cause heavy damage.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements concerning a cold air pool is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "Direction and speed of movements of cold air pools are difficult to forecast.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cold air pools normally disappear at night.\n",
        "choicetwo": "During summer cold air pools are more active over the sea than over land areas.\n",
        "choicethree": "Cold air pools can only be active for several hours.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements concerning airborne weather radar is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "It shows on a plan position indicator the areas of precipitation of rain , snow and/or hail.\n",
        "choiceone": "The indication on the plan position indicator represents the amount ( mm/h ) of water vapour within clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It shows the areas which are dangerous for aircraft icing. The intensity levels for aircraft icing as defined by\n ICAO are indicated by contour lines.\n",
        "choicethree": "It can also be used for proximity warning and anti-collision protection.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements concerning an isothermal layer in the atmosphere is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "An isothermal layer is absolutely stable.\n",
        "choiceone": "An isothermal layer is formed when the air in the layer is well mixed by turbulence.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Air parcel that are forced to rise through an isothermal layer keep the same temperature.\n",
        "choicethree": "The vertical temperature gradient lies between the dry and saturated adiabatic lapse rates.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements concerning jet streams is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "In the northern hemisphere both westerly and easterly jet streams occur.\n",
        "choiceone": "In the southern hemisphere only easterly jet streams occur.\n",
        "choicetwo": "In the southern hemisphere no jet streams occur.\n",
        "choicethree": "In the northern hemisphere only westerly jet streams occur.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements concerning the airflow during the summer monsoon is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "Southwesterly airflow over India.\n",
        "choiceone": "Westerly airflow over Japan.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Easterly airflow over Japan.\n",
        "choicethree": "Northeasterly airflow over India.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements concerning the core of a polar front jet stream is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "It lies at a height where there is no horizontal temperature gradient , the slope of the pressure surfaces at the\n height of the core is at its maximum.\n",
        "choiceone": "It and its surface projection lie in the warm air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It lies in the warm air , its pressure surfaces are horizontal at the height of the core.\n",
        "choicethree": "It lies in the cold air , the wind reverses direction at the height of the core.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements concerning the intertropical convergence zone is true ?\n",
        "answer": "There are frequent occurrences of CB.\n",
        "choiceone": "It is an area of low pressure and low relative humidity.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It lies totally in the northern hemisphere in July and totally in the southern hemisphere in January.\n",
        "choicethree": "It does not change its position over the oceans during the year.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements concerning the lifting of a parcel of air is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "Unsaturated parcels cool more rapidly than saturated parcels.\n",
        "choiceone": "Unsaturated parcels cool less rapidly than saturated parcels.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Unsaturated parcels cool at a rate of 0.65\u00b0C per 100m.\n",
        "choicethree": "Saturated parcels always cool at a rate of 0.65\u00b0C per 100m.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements concerning the tropopause is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "The temperature lapse rate changes abruptly at the tropopause.\n",
        "choiceone": "The temperature remains constant above and below the tropopause.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The temperature of the tropopause at the equator and at the poles is equal.\n",
        "choicethree": "The temperature of the tropopause at the equator is higher than at the poles.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements concerning the use of airborne weather radar in the vicinity of thunderstorms is true ?\n",
        "answer": "Accurate assessment of the weather ahead of the aircraft might be hampered due to the attenuation of the\n radar echoes by heavy rain.\n",
        "choiceone": "The radar reflectivity echoes are much more determined by the number of reflecting particles than by the\n particle size.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The most significant echoes will be received due to lightning discharges near the freezing level.\n",
        "choicethree": "The antenna tilt shall be adjusted in order to receive the most significant echoes ( generally received from an\n altitude of approxiately 30.000 ft ).\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements concerning the variation in wind speed between summer and winter on the North Atlantic\nbetween FL 300 and FL 400 is most correct ?\n",
        "answer": "The average westerly component is greater in the winter than in the summer. The latitude of the axis of\n greatest seasonal wind speed is further south in winter than in summer.\n",
        "choiceone": "The average westerly component remains the same but the altitude of greatest wind speed reduces in winter.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The average westerly component remains the same but the axis of greatest speeds moves south in winter.\n",
        "choicethree": "The average westerly component is greater in the summer than in the winter. The latitude of the axis of\n greatest wind speed is also further north in summer than in winter.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements concerning trade winds is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "They occur only in the lower part of the troposphere and more pronounced over the oceans.\n",
        "choiceone": "They occur only in the lower part of the troposphere and are more pronounced over the continents.\n",
        "choicetwo": "They reach up to the tropopause and are more pronounced over the oceans.\n",
        "choicethree": "They reach up to the tropopause and are more pronounced over the continents.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is an interpretation of the METAR ?\n 00000KT 0200 R14/0800U R16/P1500U FZFG VV001 m03/m03 Q1022 BECMG 0800 =\n",
        "answer": "RVR for runway 14 800 metres , vertical visibility 100 feet , calm , visibility improving to 800 metres in the\n next 2 hours.\n",
        "choiceone": "Visibility for runway 14 800 metres , fog with hoar frost , RVR for runway 16 more than 1500 metres.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Visibility 200 feet , RVR for runway 16 more than 1500 metres , vertical visibility 100 feet , fog with hoar\n frost.\n",
        "choicethree": "Visibility 200 metres , RVR for runway 16 1500 metres , temperature -3\u00b0C , vertical visibility 100 metres.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is an interpretation of the METAR ?\n 25020G38KT 1200 +TSGR BKN006 BKN015CB 23/18 Q1016 BECMG NSW =\n",
        "answer": "Gusts of 38 knots , thunderstorm with heavy hail , dew point 18\u00b0C.\n",
        "choiceone": "Mean wind speed 20-38 knots , visibility 1200 metres , temperature 23\u00b0C.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Wind 250\u00b0 , thunderstorm with moderate hail , QNH 1016 hPa.\n",
        "choicethree": "Broken , cloud base 600 feet and 1500 feet , temperature 18\u00b0C.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is an interpretation of the SIGMET ?\n LGGG SIGMET 3 VALID 121420/121820 LGATATHINAI FIR EMBD TS OBS AND FCST IN W PART MOV E NC\n",
        "answer": "Thunderstorms must be expected in the western part of the Athens FIR. The thunderstorm zone is moving\n east. Intensity is constant.\n",
        "choiceone": "Thunderstorms have formed in the eastern part of the Athens FIR and are slowly moving west.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Athens Airport is closed due to thunderstorms. The thunderstorm zone should be east of Athens by 1820\n UTC.\n",
        "choicethree": "The thunderstorms in the Athens FIR are increasing in intensity , but are stationary above the western part of\n the Athens FIR.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is an interpretation of the SIGMET ?\n LSAS SIGMET 2 VALID 030700/031100 LSZH SWITZERLAND FIR/UIR MOD TO SEV CAT FCST N OF ALPS BTN\n FL 260/380 STNR INTSF\n",
        "answer": "Moderate to severe clear air turbulence to be expected north of the Alps. Intensity increasing. Danger zone\n between FL 260 and FL 380.\n",
        "choiceone": "Severe turbulence observed below FL 260 north of the Alps. Pilots advised to cross this area above FL 380.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Moderate to severe clear air turbulence of constant intensity to be expected north of the Alps.\n",
        "choicethree": "Zone of moderate to severe turbulence moving towards the area north of the Alps. Intensity increasing. Pilots\n advised to cross this area above FL 260.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "Airframe icing can occur in clear air.\n",
        "choiceone": "Above the tropopause no turbulence occurs.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Haze is a reduction of visibility due to the presence of water vapour.\n",
        "choicethree": "Mountain waves are always accompanied by rotor clouds.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "At the equator horizontal motions do not induce any horizontal Coriolis force.\n",
        "choiceone": "The Coriolis force is inversely proportional to the sine of latitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The Coriolis force is directed in the same sense at all latitudes.\n",
        "choicethree": "In gradient wind the Coriolis force is in balance with the horizontal pressure gradient force and the frictional\n force.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "FG is reported only when visibility is reduced by water droplets or ice crystals to less than 1000 m.\n",
        "choiceone": "When BR is reported then the visibility is more than 1000 m but less than 8000 m.\n",
        "choicetwo": "VC denotes not at the aerodrome but not within 8 nm.\n",
        "choicethree": "HZ is reported only when visibility is reduced to 2000 m or less.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "The Bergeron-Findeisen process is mainly based on the difference of maximum vapour pressure over water\n and over ice of the same temperature.\n",
        "choiceone": "The principle of the Bergeron-Findeisen process is mainly based on the difference in size of the cloud\n elements.\n",
        "choicetwo": "In the tropics stratiform precipitation does not occur.\n",
        "choicethree": "At mid-latitudes the coalescense process is usually the initial process in the formation of precipitation.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "Normally atmospheric pressure stops falling rapidly behind a warm front , the air temperature rises.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cumulus clouds and a good visibility are normally observed in a warm sector in autumn.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cumulus clouds and a good visibility are normally observed in a warm sector in winter.\n",
        "choicethree": "At warm fronts thunderstorms are often observed.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is correct concerning rotors below the crest of a mountain wave ?\n",
        "answer": "The wind direction at the lower side of the rotors is opposite to the prevailing wind direction.\n",
        "choiceone": "The rotors are always visible by the presence of rotor clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The axis of these rotors is vertical.\n",
        "choicethree": "The wind direction at the top of the rotors is opposite to the prevailing wind direction.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is correct concerning the geostrophic wind ?\n",
        "answer": "It is present at latitudes higher than about 15 degrees north/south.\n",
        "choiceone": "It is only present in the friction layer.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A horizontal temperature difference of at least 5 degrees Celsius per 100 km is required to have geostropic\n wind conditions.\n",
        "choicethree": "It is present in a pressure system consisting of curved and non-parallel isobars.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is correct concerning the mediterranean climate ?\n",
        "answer": "The annual rainfall is significantly below 700 mm.\n",
        "choiceone": "In winter it is influenced only by the subtropical high pressure belt.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Hot summers alternate with cold winters.\n",
        "choicethree": "It is not influenced by the westerlies.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is correct concerning the savannah climate ?\n",
        "answer": "There are significant yearly variations in rainfall with a wet and a dry period.\n",
        "choiceone": "There are no significant yearly variations in rainfall but there are constant daily variations.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The annual mean temperature is above 25\u00baC.\n",
        "choicethree": "Little or no rainfall occurs.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is correct concerning the typical weather in a warm sector in mid- and high latitudes over\ncontinental areas during summer ?\n",
        "answer": "Generally moderate to good visibility , haze , sometimes few or scattered cumulus.\n",
        "choiceone": "Generally good visibility outside the frequent showers of CBs.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Overcast by medium and high clouds , stratus with drizzle , poor visibility.\n",
        "choicethree": "Moderate to poor visibility , fog or stratus , stratocumulus and drizzle.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is correct concerning the weather in a warm sector ?\n",
        "answer": "Isolated thunderstorms are sometimes possible over continental areas during the summer.\n",
        "choiceone": "Isolated air mass thunderstorms are common during all seasons over continental areas.\n",
        "choicetwo": "No thunderstorms can occur.\n",
        "choicethree": "In mid- and high latitudes thunderstorms may occur only over open sea during the summer.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is correct regarding the variation of wind with height ?\n",
        "answer": "The wind normally veers during climb out through the first 2000-3000 feet in the northern hemisphere.\n",
        "choiceone": "The wind strength normally increases by a factor of 2 per 1000 feet up to the 850 hPa level.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The wind strength normally increases by a factor of 2 per 500 feetup to the 700 hPa level.\n",
        "choicethree": "The wind normally backs during climb out through the first 2000-3000 feet in the northern hemisphere.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is true ?\n",
        "answer": "QNH can be equal to QFE.\n",
        "choiceone": "QNH is always equal to QFE.\n",
        "choicetwo": "QNH is always higher than QFE.\n",
        "choicethree": "QNH is always lower than QFE.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is true concerning frontal fog ?\n",
        "answer": "It may be formed by day as well as by night.\n",
        "choiceone": "It develops rapidly and dissipates slowly.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It usually forms by night.\n",
        "choicethree": "It usually forms by day.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is true concerning orographic fog ?\n",
        "answer": "It may be formed by day as well as by night.\n",
        "choiceone": "It develops slowly and dissipates rapidly.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It forms suddenly by day but not by night.\n",
        "choicethree": "It is formed when the air is unstable.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is true concerning orographic fog ?\n",
        "answer": "It is formed when air is forced to rise up a slope.\n",
        "choiceone": "It usually forms by night.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It develops when air is descending down a slope.\n",
        "choicethree": "It usually forms by day.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is true concerning the Bergeron-Findeisen process ?\n",
        "answer": "It only takes place in clouds with supercooled water droplets and ice crystals.\n",
        "choiceone": "It takes place in clouds which are composed only of ice crystals.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It does not occur in the tropics.\n",
        "choicethree": "It only occurs in the mid-latitudes.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is true concerning the coalescence process ?\n",
        "answer": "In the mid-latitudes this process produces only drizle or very light rain.\n",
        "choiceone": "It only occurs in the tropics.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It only takes place in convective clouds.\n",
        "choicethree": "It only occurs in the mid-latitudes.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is true of the dew point of an air mass ?\n",
        "answer": "It can only be equal to , or lower , than the temperature of the air mass.\n",
        "choiceone": "It can be used to estimate the air mass\u2019s relative humidity even if the air temperature is unknown.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It can be used together with the air pressure to estimate the air mass\u2019s relative humidity.\n",
        "choicethree": "It can be higher than the temperature of the air mass.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is true regarding moderate to severe airframe icing ?\n",
        "answer": "It is likely to occur in nimbostratus cloud.\n",
        "choiceone": "It always occurs in altostratus cloud.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It will occur in clear-sky conditions.\n",
        "choicethree": "It may occur in the uppermost levels of a cumulonimbus capillatus formation.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is true regarding moderate to severe airframe icing ?\n",
        "answer": "It will not occur in clear-sky conditions.\n",
        "choiceone": "It may occur in the uppermost levels of a cumulonimbus capillatus formation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It is unlikely to occur in nimbostratus cloud.\n",
        "choicethree": "It always occurs in altostratus cloud.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is true with regard to mountain waves ?\n",
        "answer": "Flight with headwind toward high ground is likely to be more hazardous than flight with tailwind toward\n high ground.\n",
        "choiceone": "Flight with tailwind toward high ground is likely to be more hazardous than flight with headwind toward\n high ground.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Mountain waves are not experienced beyond 100 miles downwind from initiating high ground , regardless of\n the height of the ground.\n",
        "choicethree": "The absence of cloud over high ground indicates the absence of mountain waves.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements regarding an aircraft being struck by lightning is true ?\n",
        "answer": "The flight crew might have temporary difficulties in determining the current attitude of flight.\n",
        "choiceone": "Though flying through an electric field , the aircraft itself is not a charge carrier and therefore it cannot\n initiate a lightning discharge.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The crew of an aircraft made of conductive material ( e.g. metal ) will generally suffer greater adverse effects\n due to lightning discharge than the crew of an aircraft made of non-conductive composite material.\n",
        "choicethree": "The dimension of the damage caused by the lightning stroke is reciprocally proportional to the strength of the\n electric field the aircraft intruded.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements regarding the development of valley inversions is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "Valley inversions often are a result of radiation cooling in combination with gravity , both affecting the air at\n the surface of a mountain slope.\n",
        "choiceone": "The most important prerequisite for the development of valley inversions is warm air ascending along the\n mountain slope , thus leaving cooler air behind in the bottom of the valley.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Usually a valley inversion is initiated by radiation cooling and anabatic winds which are due to orographic\n conditions.\n",
        "choicethree": "The predominant factor in the development process of valley inversions is the non-uniformity of incident\n solar radiation due to orographic conditions in combination with density variations within the air.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-2421A rev. 20.01.2003 )\n Annex 050-2421A\n Which of the following symbols represents a quasi-stationary front ?\n",
        "answer": "Symbol 3\n",
        "choiceone": "Symbol 1\n",
        "choicetwo": "Symbol 2\n",
        "choicethree": "Symbol 4\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-2421A rev. 20.01.2003 )\n Annex 050-2421A\n Which of the following symbols represents a severe squall line ?\n",
        "answer": "Symbol 1\n",
        "choiceone": "Symbol 3\n",
        "choicetwo": "Symbol 4\n",
        "choicethree": "Symbol 2\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following thunderstorms produce the most severe conditions , such as heavy hail and destructive winds ?\n",
        "answer": "Squall line thunderstorms.\n",
        "choiceone": "Warm front thunderstorms.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Daytime air mass thunderstorms.\n",
        "choicethree": "Nocturnal air mass thunderstorms.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following types of cloud can extend over the low , medium and high cloud levels ?\n",
        "answer": "CB\n",
        "choiceone": "ST\n",
        "choicetwo": "AC\n",
        "choicethree": "CI\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following types of clouds are evidence of unstable air conditions ?\n",
        "answer": "CU , CB.\n",
        "choiceone": "SC , NS.\n",
        "choicetwo": "CI , SC.\n",
        "choicethree": "ST , CS.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following types of jet streams can be observed all year round ?\n",
        "answer": "Subtropical jet stream / polar front jet stream.\n",
        "choiceone": "Equatorial jet stream / polar front jet stream.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Equatorial jet stream / arctic jet stream.\n",
        "choicethree": "Arctic jet stream / subtropical jet stream.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following weather conditions favour the formation of radiation fog ?\n",
        "answer": "Light wind , little or no cloud , moist air.\n",
        "choiceone": "Light wind , extensive cloud , moist air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Strong wind , little or no cloud , moist air.\n",
        "choicethree": "Light wind , extensive cloud , dry air.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4363A )\n Annex 050-4363A\n Which of the following weather conditions would be expected at Athens Airport ( LGAT ) at around 1450 UTC ?\n",
        "answer": "21002KT 5000 BR SCT040 29/16 Q1026 NOSIG =\n",
        "choiceone": "16002KT 0200 R33L/0600N FG VV001 12/12 Q1031 BECMG 0800 =\n",
        "choicetwo": "23018G35KT 9999 SCT035 10/04 Q0988 NOSIG =\n",
        "choicethree": "26014KT 8000 BKN090 17/12 Q1009 BECMG 4000 RA =\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following weather reports could be , in accordance with the regulations , abbreviated to \u201cCAVOK\u201d ?\n",
        "answer": "15003KT 9999 BKN100 17/11 Q1024 NOSIG =\n",
        "choiceone": "29010KT 9999 SCT045TCU 16/12 Q1015 RESHRA NOSIG =\n",
        "choicetwo": "04012G26KT 9999 BKN030 11/07 Q1024 NOSIG =\n",
        "choicethree": "24009KT 6000 RA SCT010 OVC030 12/11 Q1007 TEMPO 4000 =\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following weather reports could be , in accordance with the regulations , abbreviated to \u201cCAVOK\u201d ?\n",
        "answer": "27019G37KT 9999 BKN050 18/14 Q1016 NOSIG =\n",
        "choiceone": "00000KT 0100 FG VV001 11/11 Q1025 BECMG 0500 =\n",
        "choicetwo": "26012KT 8000 SHRA BKN025 16/12 Q1018 NOSIG =\n",
        "choicethree": "34004KT 7000 MIFG SCT260 09/08 Q1029 BECMG 1600 =\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following weather reports could be , in accordance with the regulations , abbreviated to \u201cCAVOK\u201d ? ( MSA\nabove ground : LSZB 10000 ft , LSZH 8000 ft , LSGG 12000 ft , LFSB 6000 ft )\n",
        "answer": "LSZB 28012KT 9999 OVC100 16/12 Q1012 BECMG 5000 -RA =\n",
        "choiceone": "LSZH VRB02KT 9000 BKN080 21/14 Q1022 NOSIG =\n",
        "choicetwo": "LFSB 24008KT 9999 SCT050 18/11 Q1017 RERA NOSIG =\n",
        "choicethree": "LSGG 22006KT 9999 BKN090 17/15 Q1008 RERA NOSIG =\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following weather reports is a warning of conditions that could be potentially hazardous to aircraft in flight ?\n",
        "answer": "SIGMET.\n",
        "choiceone": "ATIS.\n",
        "choicetwo": "TAF.\n",
        "choicethree": "SPECI.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following zones is most likely to encounter little or no precipitation ?\n",
        "answer": "The north side of the alps with a prevailing Foehn from the south.\n",
        "choiceone": "Occlusions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Frontal zones.\n",
        "choicethree": "The north side of the alps with a prevailing Foehn from the north.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the four answers is a correct interpretation of data from the following METAR ?\n LSZH 050820Z 16003KT 0400 R14/P1500 R16/1000 FZFG VV003 M02/M02 Q1026 BECMG 2000 BR =\n",
        "answer": "Visibility 400 m , RVR for runway 16 1000 m with no distinct tendency , dew point -2\u00b0C , freezing fog.\n",
        "choiceone": "RVR for runway 14 1500 m , visibility 400 m , QNH 1026 hPa , wind 160\u00b0 at 3 kt.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Visibility 1000 m , RVR 400 m , freezing level at 300 m , variable winds , temperature 2\u00b0C.\n",
        "choicethree": "RVR for runway 16 1000 m with no distinct tendency , visibility increasing in the next 2 hours to 2000 m ,\n vertical visibility 300 m , temperature -2\u00b0C.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the statements is true concerning squall lines ?\n",
        "answer": "For severe squall lines a SIGMET is issued.\n",
        "choiceone": "Severe squall lines always move from northwest to southeast.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Severe squall lines only occur in the tropics.\n",
        "choicethree": "For severe squall lines a TAF is issued.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these four METAR reports suggests that a thunderstorm is likely in the next few hours ?\n",
        "answer": "201350Z 21005KT 9999 SCT040CB SCT100 26/18 Q1016 TEMPO 24018G30KT TS =\n",
        "choiceone": "201350Z 04012KT 3000 BR OVC012 04/03 Q1022 BECMG 6000 =\n",
        "choicetwo": "201350Z 34003KT 0800 SN VV002 M02/M04 Q1014 NOSIG =\n",
        "choicethree": "201350Z 16004KT 8000 SCT110 OVC220 02/M02 Q1008 NOSIG =\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these four METAR reports suggests that rain is most likely in the next few hours ?\n",
        "answer": "23015KT 8000 BKN030 OVC070 17/14 Q1009 BECMG 4000 =\n",
        "choiceone": "05016G33KT 8000 OVC015 08/06 Q1028 NOSIG =\n",
        "choicetwo": "34004KT 9999 SCT040 SCT100 m05/m08 Q1014 NOSIG =\n",
        "choicethree": "16002KT 0100 FG SCT300 06/06 Q1022 BECMG 1000 =\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements best describes the weather most likely to be experienced at 1500 UTC ?\n TAF LSZH 211200Z 211322 22018G35KT 9999 SCT012 BKN030 BECMG 1315 25025G45KT TEMPO 1720 4000\n +SHRA BKN025TCU BECMG 2022 25015KT TX18/15Z TN14/21Z =\n",
        "answer": "Visibility 10 kilometres or more , ceiling 3000 feet , wind 250\u00b0 , temperature 18\u00b0C.\n",
        "choiceone": "Visibility 4000 metres , gusts up to 25 knots , temperature 18\u00b0C.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Severe rainshowers , visibility 4000 metres , temperature 15\u00b0C , gusts up to 35 knots.\n",
        "choicethree": "Visibility 10 kilometres or more , ceiling 1200 feet , gusts up to 45 knots.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements best describes the weather most likely to be experienced at 1500 UTC ?\n TAF LSZH 211322 22018G35KT 9999 SCT012 BKN030 BECMG 1315 25025G45KT TEMPO 1720 4000 +SHRA\n BKN025TCU BECMG 2022 25015KT T1815Z T1618Z =\n",
        "answer": "Visibility 10 kilometres or more , main cloud base 3000 feet , wind 250\u00b0 , temperature 18\u00b0C.\n",
        "choiceone": "Severe rainshowers , meteorological visibility 4000 metres , temperature 15\u00b0C , gusts up to 35 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Visibility 10 kilometres or more , main cloud base 1200 feet , gusts up to 45 knots.\n",
        "choicethree": "Visibility 4000 metres , gusts up to 25 knots , temperature 18\u00b0C.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4387A )\n Annex 050-4387A\n Which of these statements is true ?\n",
        "answer": "Local snow and severe aircraft icing can be expected over Germany.\n",
        "choiceone": "Freezing level above London ( EGLL ) is higher than FL 065.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Turbulence is likely to be encountered at FL 400 over Malaga ( LEMG ).\n",
        "choicethree": "The front to the east of Paris ( LFPO ) is moving south.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4387A )\n Annex 050-4387A\n Which of these statements is true ?\n",
        "answer": "Scattered thunderstorms can be expected over France.\n",
        "choiceone": "Freezing level above Madrid is higher than FL 120.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Turbulence is likely to be encountred at FL 410 over Madrid.\n",
        "choicethree": "The front to the north o London is moving south.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-1914A )\n Annex 050-1914A\n Which one of the displayed cloud forms is representative of altocumulus castellanus ?\n",
        "answer": "3.\n",
        "choiceone": "2.\n",
        "choicetwo": "4.\n",
        "choicethree": "1.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4273A )\n Annex 050-4273A\n Which one of the displayed cloud forms is representative of altocumulus lenticularis ?\n",
        "answer": "2\n",
        "choiceone": "4\n",
        "choicetwo": "1\n",
        "choicethree": "3\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4274A )\n Annex 050-4274A\n Which one of the displayed cloud forms is representative of a cumulonimbus capillatus ?\n",
        "answer": "4\n",
        "choiceone": "1\n",
        "choicetwo": "3\n",
        "choicethree": "2\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4274A )\n Annex 050-4274A\n Which one of the displayed cloud forms is representative of a cumulus ?\n",
        "answer": "1\n",
        "choiceone": "2\n",
        "choicetwo": "4\n",
        "choicethree": "3\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one of the following can provide the initial lifting leading to air mass thunderstorms ?\n",
        "answer": "Advection of cold air over a warm sea.\n",
        "choiceone": "Mountain waves.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Advection of warm air over a cold sea.\n",
        "choicethree": "Low level wind shear.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one of the following cloud types can be characterised by the optical phenomenon called halo ?\n",
        "answer": "Cirrostratus.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cirrocumulus.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Altostratus.\n",
        "choicethree": "Altocumulus.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one of the following local winds is a Foehn wind ?\n",
        "answer": "Chinook\n",
        "choiceone": "Harmattan\n",
        "choicetwo": "Bora\n",
        "choicethree": "Scirocco\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one of the following statements applies to the tropopause ?\n",
        "answer": "It separates the troposphere from the stratosphere.\n",
        "choiceone": "It is , by definition , an isothermal layer.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It is , by definition , a temperature inversion.\n",
        "choicethree": "It indicates a strong temperature lapse rate.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one of the following statements concerning the formation of aircraft icing is most correct ?\n",
        "answer": "A cloud consisting of both supercooled water droplets and ice crystals produces aircraft icing.\n",
        "choiceone": "Risk for icing increases when cloud temperature decreases well below minus 12 degrees C.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Probability of icing increases when dry snow starts to fall from a cloud.\n",
        "choicethree": "Greatest risk of icing conditions is experienced in cirrus clouds.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one of the following statements is correct concerning the movement of the ITCZ in the region of West Africa ?\n",
        "answer": "It reaches its maximum northerly position of 15\u00b0 - 20\u00b0 N in July.\n",
        "choiceone": "It oscillates during the year between the Equator and 10 degrees North.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It oscillates during the year between 10 degrees North and 10 degrees South.\n",
        "choicethree": "It reaches its maximum southerly position of 5\u00b0 S in January.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one of the following statements regarding the intertropical convergence zone ( ITCZ ) is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "Frequent and widespread thunderstorms are to be expected within the area of the ITCZ.\n",
        "choiceone": "Thunderstorms seldom occur within the area of the ITCZ.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The ITCZ does not change its position during the course of the year.\n",
        "choicethree": "The ITCZ is always associated with a strong jet stream.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one of the following types of cloud is most likely to produce heavy precipitation ?\n",
        "answer": "NS.\n",
        "choiceone": "SC.\n",
        "choicetwo": "CS.\n",
        "choicethree": "ST.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-2060A )\n Annex 050-2060A\n Which one of the tracks ( dashed lines ) is represented by the cross-section shown on the left ?\n",
        "answer": "Track D-A\n",
        "choiceone": "Track C-A\n",
        "choicetwo": "Track B-C\n",
        "choicethree": "Track B-A\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which pilots are obliged to transmit a special air-report if they encounter severe aircraft icing ?\n",
        "answer": "All categories of pilots.\n",
        "choiceone": "Only pilots with ATPL or IR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only pilots with CPL or PPL.\n",
        "choicethree": "Only pilots with ATPL or IR or CPL.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about hurricanes in the North Atlantic is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "Their eye can be well observed by weather satellites.\n",
        "choiceone": "They move with a speed of at least 60 kt.\n",
        "choicetwo": "They intensify after landfall.\n",
        "choicethree": "They move towards the equator.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement concerning the cold front and warm front of a frontal depression in the northern hemisphere is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "The risk of fog is greater ahead of and behind the warm front than ahead of and behind the cold front.\n",
        "choiceone": "The precipitation zone of the cold front is in general wider than the precipitation zone of the warm front.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The wind backs more at the warm front than at the cold front.\n",
        "choicethree": "While occluding the warm front always become a front aloft.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement concerning the Sirocco is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "It blows from southerly directions and can carry dust and sand which may reach Europe.\n",
        "choiceone": "It is formed by a strong increase of air pressure over North Africa.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It is a northeasterly wind over the western part of North Africa with much dust and sand.\n",
        "choicethree": "The carried dust and sand does not reach great heights. This is caused by the presence of a trade wind\n inversion.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement concerning the tropopause is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "The layer just above the tropopause is absolutely stable.\n",
        "choiceone": "Above the tropopause no clear air turbulence occurs.\n",
        "choicetwo": "In the ICAO standard atmosphere the tropopause lies lower over the Poles than over the equator.\n",
        "choicethree": "The temperature at the tropopause is approximately -80\u00b0C over the Poles and approximately -40\u00b0C over the\n equator.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement does correspond to the definition of severe turbulence ?\n",
        "answer": "Aircraft may be out of control for short periods , occupants are forced violently against seat belts , loose\n objects are tossed about.\n",
        "choiceone": "Difficulty in walking , occupants feel strain against seat belts , loose objects move about.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Aircraft will be damaged and an emergency landing will be absolutely necessary.\n",
        "choicethree": "Aircraft gets out of control and crashes.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "Fog can be supercooled and can also contain ice crystals.\n",
        "choiceone": "Fog and haze do not occur in the tropics.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Mist and haze only differ by different values of visibility.\n",
        "choicethree": "Mist and haze consist of water droplets.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct concerning a mountain ridge where a marked mountain wave has been reported ?\n",
        "answer": "Ragged altocumulus lenticularis is an indication for the presence of moderate/severe turbulence at the level of\n these clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "There are always rotor clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The atmosphere is unstable at the level of the mountain tops.\n",
        "choicethree": "The axis of a rotor is horizontal and perpendicular to the mountains.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct for a warm occlusion ?\n",
        "answer": "The cold front becomes a front aloft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Both fronts become fronts aloft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The warm front becomes a front aloft.\n",
        "choicethree": "The warm front overtakes the cold front.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct for an absolutely unstable atmosphere ?\n",
        "answer": "visibility is good between showers.\n",
        "choiceone": "clouds are mainly of the stratiform type.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the dry adiabatic lapse rate is more than 1\u00b0C / 100 m.\n",
        "choicethree": "the environmental lapse rate is less than 1\u00b0C / 100 m.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct for microbursts ?\n",
        "answer": "The diameter of the affected area on the surface does not exceed 4 km.\n",
        "choiceone": "They occur in the tropics only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Their downdraft is warmer than the surroundings.\n",
        "choicethree": "They only develop below convective clouds with heavy rain.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct for the southern hemisphere ?\n",
        "answer": "In the friction layer the wind backs with increasing height.\n",
        "choiceone": "If the wind veers with increasing height then warm air is advected.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The jet streams are Easterly.\n",
        "choicethree": "The wind veers at the passage of a cold front.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct regarding the ICAO Standard Atmosphere ?\n",
        "answer": "At MSL temperature is 15\u00b0C and pressure is 1013.25 hPa.\n",
        "choiceone": "At MSL temperature is 15\u00b0C and the decrease in temperature with height is 1\u00b0C per 100 m.\n",
        "choicetwo": "At MSL temperature is 10\u00b0C and the decrease in temperature with height is 1\u00b0C per 100 m.\n",
        "choicethree": "At MSL pressure is 1013.25 hPa and the decrease of temperature with height is 1\u00b0C per 100 m.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is true ?\n",
        "answer": "QNH can be lower as well as higher than 1013.25 hPa.\n",
        "choiceone": "QNH is lower than 1013.25 hPa at any time.\n",
        "choicetwo": "QNH can not be 1013.25 hPa.\n",
        "choicethree": "QNH can be 1013.25 hPa only for a station at MSL.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is true for a conditionally unstable layer ?\n",
        "answer": "The environmental lapse rate is less than 1\u00b0C/100 m.\n",
        "choiceone": "The layer is unstable for unsaturated air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The wet adiabatic lapse rate is 0.65\u00b0C/100 m.\n",
        "choicethree": "The environmental lapse rate is less than 0.65\u00b0C/100 m.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is true for advection fog ?\n",
        "answer": "It can appear suddenly by day or by night.\n",
        "choiceone": "It develops slowly and clears fast.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It forms when unstable air is adiabatically cooled.\n",
        "choicethree": "It usually forms by night and clears by day.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is true for hurricanes ?\n",
        "answer": "From the earth\u2019s surface up to the tropopause the core is warmer than its surroundings.\n",
        "choiceone": "They intensify rapidly after landfall.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Their greatest frequency of occurrence is in winter.\n",
        "choicethree": "The diameter is 50-500 m\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement regarding aircraft and lightning is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "Aircraft made by composite material may get severe damage , the crew may be blinded and temporarily lose\n the hearing.\n",
        "choiceone": "Aircraft made by composite material can\u2019t conduct a lightning and will therefore very seldom be struck.\n",
        "choicetwo": "An aircraft made by metal has a certain capacity to attract a lightning , but the lightning will follow the\n surface and therefore no damage will be caused.\n",
        "choicethree": "An aircraft has in the atmosphere the same qualities as a \u201cFaradays cage\u201d , which means that struck of\n lightning seldom occurs. But if it happens , the result will be an occasional engine failure. The crew may get\n a shock.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which thunderstorms generally produce the most severe conditions , such as heavy hail and destructive winds ?\n",
        "answer": "Squall line thunderstorms.\n",
        "choiceone": "Warm front thunderstorms.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Nocturnal air mass thunderstorms.\n",
        "choicethree": "Daytime air mass thunderstorms.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which thunderstorms move forward the fastest ?\n",
        "answer": "Frontal thunderstorms.\n",
        "choiceone": "Orographic thunderstorms.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Thermal thunderstorms.\n",
        "choicethree": "Thunderstorms formed by lifting processes.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which two air masses are most likely to govern weather in western Europe ?\n",
        "answer": "Maritime tropical warm and maritime polar cold.\n",
        "choiceone": "Continental tropical warm and continental polar cold.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Maritime tropical warm and continental polar cold.\n",
        "choicethree": "Maritime polar warm and continental tropical warm.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which type of air mass never occurs over central Europe ?\n",
        "answer": "Equatorial air\n",
        "choiceone": "Arctic air\n",
        "choicetwo": "Tropical air\n",
        "choicethree": "Polar air\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which type of fog can NOT be formed over water ?\n",
        "answer": "Radiation fog\n",
        "choiceone": "Frontal fog\n",
        "choicetwo": "Advection fog\n",
        "choicethree": "Arctic smoke\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which type of fog is likely to form when air having temperature of 15\u00b0C and dew point of 12\u00b0C blows at 10 knots over a sea\nsurface having temperatures of 5\u00b0C ?\n",
        "answer": "Advection fog\n",
        "choiceone": "Radiation fog\n",
        "choicetwo": "Steam fog\n",
        "choicethree": "Frontal fog\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which types of clouds are typical evidence of stable air conditions ?\n",
        "answer": "ST , AS\n",
        "choiceone": "CU , CB\n",
        "choicetwo": "NS , CU\n",
        "choicethree": "CB , CC\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4392A )\n Annex 050-4392A\n Which typical weather situation is shown by the design for northern Italy ?\n",
        "answer": "High pressure\n",
        "choiceone": "Warm southerly wind\n",
        "choicetwo": "Easterly wind\n",
        "choicethree": "Westerly wind\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-4391A )\n Annex 050-4391A\n Which typical weather situation is shown by the design for the area of Central Europe ?\n",
        "answer": "Westerly waves\n",
        "choiceone": "Easterly waves\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cold air pool\n",
        "choicethree": "Uniform pressure pattern\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-2059A )\n Annex 050-2059A\n Which typical weather situation is shown on the weather chart ? ( Spacing of the isobars : 5 hPa )\n",
        "answer": "Flat pressure pattern.\n",
        "choiceone": "Warm south wind condition ( Foehn ).\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cutting wind.\n",
        "choicethree": "West wind condition.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which units are used for the forecasted wind at higher levels ?\n",
        "answer": "Direction in degrees relative to true north and speed in knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "Direction in degrees relative to grid north and speed in km/h.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Direction in degrees relative to magnetic north and speed in knots.\n",
        "choicethree": "Direction in degrees relative to magnetic north and speed in km/h.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which weather chart gives information about icing ?\n",
        "answer": "Significant weather chart\n",
        "choiceone": "700 hPa chart\n",
        "choicetwo": "Surface chart\n",
        "choicethree": "500 hPa chart\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which weather condition lowers true altitude as compared to pressure altitude to a position where flight over mountains\ncould be dangerous ?\n",
        "answer": "Cold low.\n",
        "choiceone": "Warm depression.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Warm high.\n",
        "choicethree": "Cold high.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which weather phenomena are typical for the northern side of the Alps with strong winds from the south ( Foehn ) ?\n",
        "answer": "Good visibility , turbulence.\n",
        "choiceone": "Decrease in temperature , moderate to severe icing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Continuous precipitation , severe turbulence.\n",
        "choicethree": "Icing , huge mass of clouds.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which wind systems converge on the ITCZ , when it lies at the equator ?\n",
        "answer": "SE trade winds and NE trade winds.\n",
        "choiceone": "SW monsoon and NW monsoon.\n",
        "choicetwo": "SW monsoon and NW trade winds.\n",
        "choicethree": "NW monsoon and SW trade winds.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "While approaching your destination aerodrome you receive the following message ;\n RVR runway 23 : 400m\n This information indicates the ;\n",
        "answer": "length of runway which a pilot in an aircraft on the ground would see , on the threshold of runway 23.\n",
        "choiceone": "visibility on runway 23.\n",
        "choicetwo": "minimum visibility at this aerodrome , with runway 23 being the one in service.\n",
        "choicethree": "portion of runway which a pilot on the threshold of any of the runways would see , with runway 23 in\n service.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "While crossing a jet stream at right angles in Western Europe ( 3000 ft below its core ) and OAT is decreasing , what would\nbe the prevailing wind ?\n",
        "answer": "Crosswind from the left.\n",
        "choiceone": "A tailwind.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A headwind.\n",
        "choicethree": "Crosswind from the right.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "While descending through a cloud cover at high level , a small amount of a white and rough powderlike contamination is\ndetected along the leading edge of the wing. This contamination is called ;\n",
        "answer": "Rime ice.\n",
        "choiceone": "Frost.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Clear ice.\n",
        "choicethree": "Mixed ice.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "While using the airborne weather radar in order to circumnavigate thunderstorms , the radar scope is clear between heavy\nechoes. Which of the following interpretations of the scope is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "The clear area indicates an area from which no echoes are received. However , this radar scope provides no\n assurance of being in VMC while flying in this area.\n",
        "choiceone": "The clear area indicates an area from which no echoes are received because the number of cloud droplets is\n too small to generate a significant echo. Thus , the pilot will have a good visual sight of the thunderstorm\n clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The clear area indicates an area from which no echoes are received. An aircraft flying in this area will be in\n VMC due to the absence of precipitation drops.\n",
        "choicethree": "This is a typical radar scope from which the region of clear air turbulence between thunderstorm clouds can\n be detected.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Whilst flying at FL 180 on the northern hemisphere an aircraft experiences right drift. What effect , if any , will this have on\nthe aircraft\u2019s true altitude ?\n",
        "answer": "It decreases.\n",
        "choiceone": "Without knowing the pressure change this question cannot be answered.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It increases.\n",
        "choicethree": "It remains constant.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why are indications about the height of the tropopause not essential for flight documentation in the tropics ?\n",
        "answer": "The tropopause is generally well above the flight level actually flown.\n",
        "choiceone": "The tropopause is always at the same height.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The temperatures of the tropical tropopause are always very low and therefore not important.\n",
        "choicethree": "The meteorological services are unable to provide such a chart.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why can the following METAR not be abbreviated to CAVOK ?\n DLLO 121550Z 31018G30KT 9999 FEW060TCU BKN070 14/08 Q1016 TEMPO 4000 TS =\n ( Aerodrome elevation 1000 ft , MSA for sector 000-190\u00b0 5800 ft , for sector 190-360\u00b0 7300 ft. )\n",
        "answer": "Because the cloud base is below the highest minimum sector altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "Because there are gusts reported.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Because towering cumulus are observed.\n",
        "choicethree": "Because thunderstorms are forecast temporary for the next 2 hours.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why do tropical revolving storms tend to develop mostly in the western parts of the tropical oceans ?\n",
        "answer": "Because there is a maximum of humidity as a result of the trade winds long sea passage.\n",
        "choiceone": "Because the gulf formation of the coastlines triggers a strong rotary circulation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Because there is a maximal temperature difference between land mass and sea.\n",
        "choicethree": "Because they are areas in which there is a strong progressive wind shear with increase of height.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Wind is caused by ;\n",
        "answer": "horizontal pressure differences.\n",
        "choiceone": "friction between the air and the ground.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the movements of fronts.\n",
        "choicethree": "the rotation of the earth.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "With all other quantities being constant , the density of the atmosphere increases with increasing ;\n",
        "answer": "air pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "temperature.\n",
        "choicetwo": "relative humidity.\n",
        "choicethree": "stability.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "With regard to temperature , which of the following is correct for the polar climates ?\n",
        "answer": "The mean temperature of all months is below plus 10\u00baC.\n",
        "choiceone": "The mean temperature of the warmest month is 10\u00baC or above , and of the coldest month below minus 3\u00baC.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The mean temperature of all months is above 0\u00baC , but temperatures a high as plus 10\u00baC will never be\n reached.\n",
        "choicethree": "The mean temperature of all months is below minus 10\u00baC.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "With the development of a thunderstorm , at what stage will there be only updraughts of air ?\n",
        "answer": "Initial stage.\n",
        "choiceone": "Anvil stage.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Dissipating stage.\n",
        "choicethree": "Mature stage.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "With what type of cloud is \u201cDZ\u201d precipitation most commonly associated ?\n",
        "answer": "ST\n",
        "choiceone": "CC\n",
        "choicetwo": "CU\n",
        "choicethree": "CB\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "With what type of cloud is \u201cGR\u201d precipitation most commonly associated ?\n",
        "answer": "CB\n",
        "choiceone": "AS\n",
        "choicetwo": "ST\n",
        "choicethree": "CC\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "With what type of cloud is heavy precipitation unlikely during the summer months ?\n",
        "answer": "SC , AS\n",
        "choiceone": "NS , CC\n",
        "choicetwo": "AS , NS\n",
        "choicethree": "CB , ST\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "With what type of cloud is \u201c+TSRA\u201d precipitation most commonly associated ?\n",
        "answer": "CB\n",
        "choiceone": "NS\n",
        "choicetwo": "SC\n",
        "choicethree": "AS\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "With what type of clouds are showers most likely associated ?\n",
        "answer": "Cumulonimbus.\n",
        "choiceone": "Stratus.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Stratocumulus.\n",
        "choicethree": "Nimbostratus.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "With which meteorological phenomena are wind shear conditions mostly associated ?\n",
        "answer": "Gust fronts , low level temperature inversions , frontal surfaces.\n",
        "choiceone": "Strong surface winds coupled with local topography , anticyclones , light precipitation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Thunderstorms , drizzle , conditional instability.\n",
        "choicethree": "Gust fronts , sea breeze fronts , high stratiform cloud.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "With which of the following types of cloud is \u201c+RA\u201d precipitation most commonly associated ?\n",
        "answer": "NS\n",
        "choiceone": "AC\n",
        "choicetwo": "SC\n",
        "choicethree": "ST\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "With which type of cloud are tornadoes associated ?\n",
        "answer": "Cumulonimbus\n",
        "choiceone": "Stratus\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cumulus mediocris\n",
        "choicethree": "Nimbostratus\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Within a short interval , several flight crews report that they have experienced strong clear air turbulence in a certain\nairspace. What is the consequence of these reports ?\n",
        "answer": "The competent aviation weather office will issue a SIGMET.\n",
        "choiceone": "The airspace in question , will be temporarily closed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The competent aviation weather office will issue a SPECI.\n",
        "choicethree": "The competent aviation weather office will issue a storm warning.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "You are flying at 2500 ft/AGL , the wind is 180\u00b0 , and intend to land at an airport , at sea level directly below. From\napproximately which direction would you expect the surface wind ( mid-latitude , northern hemisphere ) ?\n",
        "answer": "South-southeast.\n",
        "choiceone": "South.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Southwest.\n",
        "choicethree": "South-southwest.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "You are flying at FL 130 , and your true altitude is 12.000 ft. What is the temperature deviation from that of the standard\natmosphere at FL 130 ( QNH 1013.2 hPa ) ?\n",
        "answer": "ISA \u201320\u00b0C\n 1000 = Y x ( 4 : 1000 ) x 13000 ,\n",
        "choiceone": "ISA +/-0\u00b0C\n",
        "choicetwo": "ISA +12\u00b0C\n TEC = 13000 \u2013 12000 = 1000 ft , burada ISA sapmas\u0131na Y dersek ;\n",
        "choicethree": "ISA +20\u00b0C\n Y = 1000 : 52 = 19,23\u00b0C \u2248 ISA \u201320\u00b0C\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "You are flying at FL 160. Outside air temperature is \u201327\u00b0C , and the pressure at sea level is 1003 hPa. What is the true\naltitude ?\n",
        "answer": "15100 feet ( 16 x 2 ) \u2013 15 = \u201317\u00b0C , ISA sapmas\u0131 = 27\u00b0C \u2013 17\u00b0C = \u201310\u00b0C\n",
        "choiceone": "15620 feet Bas\u0131n\u00e7 sapmas\u0131 = 1013 \u2013 1003 = 10 hPa , 10 hPa x 27 ft = 270 ft ,\n",
        "choicetwo": "16360 feet 16000 \u2013 270 = 15730 ft , ISA\u2019ya g\u00f6re FL160\u2019da olmas\u0131 gereken s\u0131cakl\u0131k ;\n",
        "choicethree": "16920 feet TEC = 10 x ( 4 : 1000 ) x 15730 = 629,2 \u2248 630 ft ,\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "You are flying at FL 200. Outside air temperature is \u201340\u00b0C , and the pressure at sea level is 1033 hPa. What is the true\naltitude ?\n",
        "answer": "19310 feet ( 20 x 2 ) \u2013 15 = \u201325\u00b0C , ISA sapmas\u0131 = 40\u00b0C \u2013 25\u00b0C = \u201315\u00b0C\n",
        "choiceone": "21770 feet Bas\u0131n\u00e7 sapmas\u0131 = 1033 \u2013 1013 = 20 hPa , 20 hPa x 27 ft = 540 ft ,\n",
        "choicetwo": "20630 feet 20000 + 540 = 20540 ft , ISA\u2019ya g\u00f6re FL200\u2019de olmas\u0131 gereken s\u0131cakl\u0131k ;\n",
        "choicethree": "18290 feet TEC = 15 x ( 4 : 1000 ) x 20540 = 1232,4 \u2248 1230 ft ,\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "You are flying at FL 300 where the outside air temperature is \u201357.5\u00b0C and the pressure at MSL is 1013.25 hPa. If you\nassume that the difference between the actual temperature and the temperature in the ISA is valid for the whole troposphere , then the\ntrue altitude is ;\n",
        "answer": "28500 ft. ISA\u2019ya g\u00f6re FL300\u2019de olmas\u0131 gereken s\u0131cakl\u0131k ;\n",
        "choiceone": "30000 ft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "31500 ft. ( 30 x 2 ) \u2013 15 = \u201345\u00b0C , ISA sapmas\u0131 = 57.5\u00b0C \u2013 45\u00b0C = \u201312.5\u00b0C\n",
        "choicethree": "27000 ft. TEC = 12.5 x ( 4 : 1000 ) x 30000 = 1500 ft ,\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "You are flying at FL 340 ( 250 hPa ) on the northern hemisphere. The wind is geostrophic and there is a cross wind from the\nright all the time. Your true altitude will ;\n",
        "answer": "increase.\n",
        "choiceone": "decrease , only if the pressure at the surface is decreasing on your route.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increase , only if the temperature at your flight level is rising on your route.\n",
        "choicethree": "decrease.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "You are flying from east to west in the northern hemisphere at the 500 hPa pressure surface. Which of the following\nstatements is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "If the wind is from the north you are gaining altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "If the wind is from the south you are gaining altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "If you have a tail wind you are losing altitude.\n",
        "choicethree": "If you have a head wind you are gaining altitude.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 050-2509A )\n Annex 050-2509A\n You are flying from Munich to Amsterdam. Which of the following flight levels would you choose in order to avoid\nturbulence and icing ?\n",
        "answer": "FL 260\n",
        "choiceone": "FL 180\n",
        "choicetwo": "FL 320\n",
        "choicethree": "FL 140\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "You are flying in the northern hemisphere at 2000 ft over a flat country area. An anticyclone is ahead of you and a\ndepression is behind you. The wind affecting you , will be ;\n",
        "answer": "from your right.\n",
        "choiceone": "from your left.\n",
        "choicetwo": "from ahead.\n",
        "choicethree": "from behind.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "You are flying in the southern hemisphere at FL 180 from east to west. If the wind at FL 180 is southerly , which of the\nfollowing statements is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "The true altitude is increasing.\n",
        "choiceone": "The true altitude remains constant.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The true altitude is decreasing.\n",
        "choicethree": "A statement on altitude changes cannot be given without information on temperature.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "You are flying over the sea at FL 250 and measure an outside temperature of \u201350\u00b0C. The pressure at sea level is 1023 hPa.\nWhat is your approximate true altitude calculated using normal vertical change in temperature with increase in height ?\n",
        "answer": "23770 ft/AMSL. ( 25 x 2 ) \u2013 15 = \u201335\u00b0C , ISA sapmas\u0131 = 50\u00b0C \u2013 35\u00b0C = \u201315\u00b0C\n",
        "choiceone": "23230 ft/AMSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "26770 ft/AMSL. Bas\u0131n\u00e7 sapmas\u0131 = 1023 \u2013 1013 = 10 hPa , 10 hPa x 27 ft = 270 ft ,\n",
        "choicethree": "26230 ft/AMSL. 25000 + 270 = 25270 ft , ISA\u2019ya g\u00f6re FL250\u2019da olmas\u0131 gereken s\u0131cakl\u0131k ;\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "You are flying with an outside air temperature of \u201312\u00b0C and a TAS of 250 kt at FL 150 through 8 oktas NS. What type and\ndegree of icing is most probable ?\n",
        "answer": "In clouds pushed up against the mountains , moderate to severe mixed ice.\n",
        "choiceone": "Over flat terrain , away from fronts , moderate to severe mixed ice.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Over flat terrain , moderate hoar frost.\n",
        "choicethree": "In clouds pushed up against the mountains , moderate to severe clear ice.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "You are planning to fly across a mountain range. The chart recommends a minimum altitude of 12000 feet above mean sea\nlevel. The air mass you will be flying through is an average 10\u00b0C warmer than ISA. Your altimeter is set to 1023 hPa ( QNH of a\nnearby airport at nearly sea level ). What altitude will the altimeter show when you have reached the recommended minimum\naltitude ?\n",
        "answer": "11520 feet ISA sapmas\u0131 = +10\u00b0C\n",
        "choiceone": "12210 feet\n",
        "choicetwo": "11790 feet Halihaz\u0131rda QNH ba\u011fl\u0131 oldu\u011fundan bas\u0131n\u00e7 sapmas\u0131 hesaplanmaz ,\n",
        "choicethree": "11250 feet TEC = 10 x ( 4 : 1000 ) x 12000 = 480 ft ,\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "You cross a jet stream in horizontal flight at approximately right angles. While crossing , in spite of a strong wind of 120 kt ,\nyou notice the temperature barely changes. Which of the following statements is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "This phenomenon is absolutely normal as you are crossing the jet core.\n",
        "choiceone": "You assume the front associated with the jet stream to be very weak with practically no temperature\n difference between the two air masses.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Since the result of such readings seems impossible , you will have the instruments tested after landing.\n",
        "choicethree": "This phenomenon does not surprise you at all , since normally no large temperature differences are possible\n at these heights.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "You have been flying for some time in dense layered cloud. The outside air temperature is \u201325\u00b0C. Which of the following\nstatements is true ?\n",
        "answer": "Severe airframe icing is unlikely under these conditions.\n",
        "choiceone": "In a dense layered cloud icing is unlikely also at an outside air temperature of \u20135\u00b0C.\n",
        "choicetwo": "If you do not have weather radar on board there is no need to worry , as CB is unlikely to form in such cloud.\n",
        "choicethree": "Severe airframe icing is quite likely under these conditions.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "You intend to carry out a VFR flight over the Alps , on a fine and hot summer day. What is the best time of day to conduct\nthis flight ?\n",
        "answer": "Morning.\n",
        "choiceone": "Mid-day.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Afternoon.\n",
        "choicethree": "Early evening.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "You intend to overfly a mountain range. The recommended minimum flight altitude is , according to the aviation chart ,\n15000 ft/AMSL. The air mass that you will fly through is on average 15\u00b0C warmer than the standard atmosphere. The altimeter is set\nto QNH ( 1023 hPa ). At what altimeter reading will you effectively be at the recommended minimum flight altitude ?\n",
        "answer": "14100 ft. Halihaz\u0131rda QNH ba\u011fl\u0131 oldu\u011fundan bas\u0131n\u00e7 sapmas\u0131 hesaplanmaz ,\n",
        "choiceone": "15900 ft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "14370 ft. ISA sapmas\u0131 = +15\u00b0C\n",
        "choicethree": "13830 ft. TEC = 15 x ( 4 : 1000 ) x 15000 = 900 ft ,\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "You must make an emergency landing at sea. The QNH of a field on a nearby island with an elevation of 4000 ft is 1025 hPa\nand the temperature is \u201320\u00b0C. What is your pressure altimeter reading when landing if 1025 hPa is set in the subscale ?\n",
        "answer": "Less than 0 ft.\n",
        "choiceone": "0 ft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "4000 ft.\n",
        "choicethree": "More than 0 ft , but less than 4000 ft.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "You plan a flight over a mountain range at a true altitude of 15000 ft/AMSL. The air is on an average 15\u00b0C colder than ISA ,\nthe pressure at sea level is 1003 hPa. What approximate indication should the altimeter ( setting 1013.2 hPa ) read ?\n",
        "answer": "16230 ft.\n",
        "choiceone": "13830 ft. Ger\u00e7ek irtifa 15.000 ft ve OAT ISA \u2013 15\u00b0C oldu\u011funa g\u00f6re ;\n",
        "choicetwo": "15690 ft. TEC = 15 x ( 4 : 1000 ) x 15.000 = 900 ft \u2192 15.000 + 900 = 15.900 ft\n",
        "choicethree": "14370 ft. 1 hPa = 30 ft olarak al\u0131rsak altimetreye 1013 hPa ba\u011fland\u0131\u011f\u0131nda ;\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "You receive the following METAR ;\n LSGG 120750Z 00000KT 0300 R05/0700N FG VV001 M02/M02 Q1014 NOSIG =\n What will be the RVR at 0900 UTC ?\n",
        "answer": "The RVR is unknown , because the \u201cNOSIG\u201d does not refer to RVR.\n",
        "choiceone": "700 m.\n",
        "choicetwo": "300 m.\n",
        "choicethree": "900 m.\n",
        "source": "meteorology-1355-soru_compress-2.txt"
    }
]